<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Adnuguk | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/adnuguk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-19T20:50:45+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jon Skeet Scotland Tour]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/jon-skeet-scotland-tour/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-07T07:13:09+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/jon-skeet-scotland-tour</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Jon Skeet - Taking a quick break from Stack Overflow</h1>

<p>It is with great pleasure that I can announce that I have been able to confirm Jon Skeet, <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/22656/jon-skeet">legendary contributor to Stack Overflow</a>, and author of <a href="http://www.manning.com/skeet3/">C# in Depth</a>, to do User Group Presentations in Glasgow, Aberdeen and Edinburgh.</p>

<p>I have to say a big thank you to Jon for taking the time out of his busy schedule to come up to Scotland to do these talks, it really is very much appreciated!  Jon will be talking to two topics, &ldquo;Semantics Matter&rdquo; and &ldquo;Abusing C#&rdquo;.  The Abusing C# talk will be repeated in both Aberdeen and Edinburgh, so if you can&rsquo;t make it to one, you have the option to attend the other.</p>

<p>You can find out more information about Jon Skeet on his site <a href="http://msmvps.com/blogs/jon_skeet/">here</a>.</p>

<h1>Glasgow Event</h1>

<p>With the help of <a href="http://www.scottishdevelopers.com/">Scottish Developers</a>, this meeting, entitled &ldquo;Semantics Matter&rdquo;, will be taking place on Wednesday 7th August 2013, in the Mercure Hotel, starting at 7 o&#8217;clock in the evening.  For full details of the event, and to register, check out the Eventbrite page <a href="http://jonskeet-glasgow.eventbrite.com/">here</a>.</p>

<h1>Aberdeen Event</h1>

<p>This meeting, entitled &ldquo;Abusing C#&rdquo;, will be taking place on Thursday 8th August 2013, at the RGU St Andrews Street building at 6 o&#8217;clock in the evening.  For full details of the event, and to register, check out the Eventbrite page <a href="http://adnuguk-aug2013.eventbrite.com/">here</a>.</p>

<h1>Edinburgh Event</h1>

<p>Once again, with the help of <a href="http://www.scottishdevelopers.com/">Scottish Developers</a>, this meeting, entitled &ldquo;Abusing C#&rdquo;, will be taking place on Friday 9th August, For full details of the event, and to register, check out the Eventbrite page <a href="http://jonskeet-edinburgh-2013.eventbrite.co.uk/">here</a>.</p>

<h1>Questions</h1>

<p>If you have any questions about either of these events, please don&rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bill Wagner Scotland Tour]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/bill-wager-scotland-tour/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-06T19:18:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/bill-wager-scotland-tour</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Bill Wagner - Taking a break from Golf</h1>

<p>It is with great pleasure that I can announce that I have been able to confirm Bill Wagner, author of <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Effective-Covers-4-0-Development-ebook/dp/B003BXRNZI/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1370544140&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=effective+c%23">Effective C#</a> and <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/More-Effective-Specific-Development-ebook/dp/B001FA0MAC/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1370544140&amp;sr=8-2&amp;keywords=effective+c%23">More Effective C#</a>, to do User Group Presentations in both Glasgow and Aberdeen.</p>

<p>I have to send out a huge thank you to Mark Rendle (<a href="https://twitter.com/markrendle">@markrendle</a>) for the initial introductions, and obviously a special thank to Bill for agreeing to visit these User Groups.  Bill is taking time out of a busy golfing holiday (which I am very jealous of) to present topics on Async and Await Practices in C# 5.</p>

<p>You can find out more information about Bill Wagner at his site <a href="http://billwagner.azurewebsites.net/">here</a>.</p>

<h1>Aberdeen Event</h1>

<p>This meeting, entitled &ldquo;Async/Await Practices in C# 5&rdquo;, will be taking place on Thursday 4th July 2013, at the RGU St Andrews Street building at 6 o&#8217;clock in the evening.  For full details of the event, and to register, check out the Eventbrite page <a href="http://adnuguk-jul2013.eventbrite.com/">here</a>.</p>

<h1>Glasgow Event</h1>

<p>With the help of <a href="http://www.scottishdevelopers.com/">Scottish Developers</a>, this meeting, entitled &ldquo;Async/Await Practices in C# 5&rdquo;, will be taking place on Saturday 13th July 2013, in the Mercure Hotel, starting at 10 o&#8217;clock in the morning.  For full details of the event, and to register, check out the Eventbrite page <a href="http://billwagner-glasgow.eventbrite.com/#">here</a>.</p>

<h1>Questions</h1>

<p>If you have any questions about either of these events, please don&rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA["Mmmm, Chocolatey Goodness!" at Aberdeen Developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/mmmm-chocolatey-goodness-at-aberdeen-developers/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-24T11:00:45+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/mmmm-chocolatey-goodness-at-aberdeen-developers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>My Chocolatey Talk at Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group</h1>

<p>On Thursday 28th March 2013, I presented a talk at the Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group entitled &ldquo;Mmmm, Chocolatey Goodness!&rdquo;.  If you attended the session, and are interested in seeing the demonstrations that were used in the presentation, or the slide desk, you can find this information below.  If you did attend, let me say thank you very much, and I very much hope you enjoyed it!</p>

<h1>The Code</h1>

<p>As explained on the night, there was very little &ldquo;code&rdquo; used within this presentation, but rather it was a demonstration of how Chocolatey can used to install, update, and uninstall packages on your computer.  If you are interested in the demonstrations that were shown on the night, you can check them out <a href="https://github.com/gep13/ChocolateyDemos/wiki">here</a>.</p>

<h1>The Slides</h1>

<p>A full copy of the slides that were used on the day can be found attached to this post, and you can see a preview of them below:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/28937731 " width="595" height="446" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC;border-width:1px 1px 0;margin-bottom:5px" allowfullscreen></iframe> </p>

<h1>Feedback</h1>

<p>I would be very interested to hear any feedback for the presentation that was given.  If you are willing to complete a short survey on the topic, you can find it <a href="http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/MZWQP5T">here</a>.</p>

<p>[wpdm_file id=1]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scott Hanselman Doing User Group Tour of Scotland]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/scott-hanselman-doing-user-group-tour-of-scotland/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-15T06:21:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/scott-hanselman-doing-user-group-tour-of-scotland</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>No, really, scott hanselman is coming to Scotland</h1>

<p>I am <strong>very</strong> happy to announce that <a href="http://www.hanselman.com">Scott Hanselman</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/shanselman">@shanselman</a>) is doing a User Group tour of Scotland in July.  He is going to be over here for 1 week, and while he is here he is going to be doing 4 User Group sessions.  The details for these sessions are as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li></li>
</ul>


<h5><strong><a href="http://scott-hanselman-edi-2012.eventbrite.co.uk/?ref=gep13blog">9 July - Edinburgh</a></strong>: Developing for the Mobile Web</h5>

<p>Mobile traffic on the web is exploding. Are you ready? ASP.NET MVC 4 includes new mobile-friendly templates, a focus on responsive design as well as dedicated mobile templates that leverage jQuery and jQuery mobile. Scott Hanselman will show you what you can do today and tomorrow to make your site friendly on a mobile device. When should your mobile site become a mobile application? Should you use CSS3 media queries, or go &ldquo;all in&rdquo; and use jQuery mobile or another mobile framework?</p>

<ul>
<li></li>
</ul>


<h5><strong><a href="http://scott-hanselman-dee-2012.eventbrite.co.uk/?ref=gep13blog">10 July - Dundee</a></strong>: Personal Productivity - Scaling yourself in the face of Information Overload</h5>

<p>As information workers, we are asked to absorb even more information than ever before. More blogs, more documentation, more patterns, more layers of abstraction. Now Twitter and Facebook compete with Email and Texts for our attention, keeping us up-to-date on our friends dietary details and movie attendance second-by-second. Does all this information take a toll on your psyche or sharpen the saw? Is it a matter of finding the right tools and filters to capture what you need, or do you just need to unplug. Is ZEB (zero email bounce) a myth or are there substantive techniques for prioritizing your life one the web? Join Scott Hanselman as we explore how you can be truly productive.</p>

<ul>
<li></li>
</ul>


<h5><strong><a href="http://scott-hanselman-abz-2012.eventbrite.co.uk/?ref=gep13blog">12 July - Aberdeen</a></strong>: One ASP.NET - Open Source, .NET and the Cloud</h5>

<p>It&rsquo;s an exciting time for ASP.NET and Open Source. What does the next version of Visual Studio and ASP.NET bring to the world of web development? How will you use HTML5, CSS3 and new advances in JavaScript with ASP.NET? There’s new advances in ASP.NET with the addition of real-time (Signalr), new features in WebForms as well as support for mobile. How will it all snap together in a way that makes sense? Join Scott Hanselman as he shares some internal documents and exciting surprises about the future of ASP.NET. What about Azure? We&rsquo;ll talk about the world’s most misunderstood cloud and it means for developers of all flavours and persuasions.</p>

<ul>
<li></li>
</ul>


<h5><strong><a href="http://scott-hanselman-gla-2012.eventbrite.co.uk/?ref=gep13blog">13 July - Glasgow</a></strong>: One ASP.NET - Open Source, .NET and the Cloud</h5>

<p>It&rsquo;s an exciting time for ASP.NET and Open Source. What does the next version of Visual Studio and ASP.NET bring to the world of web development? How will you use HTML5, CSS3 and new advances in JavaScript with ASP.NET? There’s new advances in ASP.NET with the addition of real-time (Signalr), new features in WebForms as well as support for mobile. How will it all snap together in a way that makes sense? Join Scott Hanselman as he shares some internal documents and exciting surprises about the future of ASP.NET. What about Azure? We&rsquo;ll talk about the world’s most misunderstood cloud and it means for developers of all flavours and persuasions.</p>

<h1></h1>

<h1>more information</h1>

<p>In case you still don’t believe me (I still find it hard to believe myself), you can find more information about the tour in the following places:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://www.hanselman.com/scotland">http://www.hanselman.com/scotland</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://scottishdevelopers.com/2012/05/15/scott-hansleman-scotland-tour/">http://scottishdevelopers.com/2012/05/15/scott-hansleman-scotland-tour/</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>For getting the most up to date information regarding each of the events, make sure that you follow the following Twitter accounts:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Mine <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/gep13">@gep13</a></p></li>
<li><p>The Aberdeen Developers Account <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/adnuguk">@adnuguk</a></p></li>
<li><p>The Scottish Developers Accounts <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/scottishdevs">@scottishdevs</a></p></li>
</ul>


<h1>thanks</h1>

<p>There are too many people to thank for helping to get this tour under way that I won’t be able to list them all here, but hopefully you know who you all are, and I very much appreciate all your help!!</p>

<h1>How did all this start?</h1>

<p>A few of you might be wondering how this event got started, and I thought I should take the time to explain.  First up, a HUGE shout has to go out to Gregor Suttie (<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/gsuttie">@gsuttie</a>), if it were not for him, this tour would not be happening.  Let me explain…</p>

<p>Through the wonders of Twitter, I was having a conversation with Gregor, and he happened to make a throw-away comment along the lines of “…wouldn’t it be great if <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/shanselman">@shanselman</a> came to Scotland!”.  I quickly replied to him saying that yes, this would be great, but really, what are the chances.  Within a few minutes, Scott actually replied to Gregor’s tweet, asking what we were talking about.  We explained, and Scott then offered to talk the conversation offline, and provided me with his email address.  After a few emails it was clear that Scott was very interested in visiting Scotland as he has been able to trace his family tree back to Scotland, and we were only to happy to host him at our User Groups.  With some help from the <a href="http://scottishdevelopers.com/">Scottish Developer</a> guys, plans were quickly put into place to host Scott at the four venues listed above.  Thanks again Gregor!! <img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/wlEmoticon-smile.png" alt="Smile" /></p>

<p>Hopefully see you all there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Lacey on Tour]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/matt-lacey-on-tour-wpug-mrlacey/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-10T20:58:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/matt-lacey-on-tour-wpug-mrlacey</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in October of 2011, I dropped an email to Matt Lacey, of the <a href="http://wpug.net/">Windows Phone User Group</a>, asking whether he would be interested in doing a talk up in Scotland at the <a href="http://aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/">Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group</a>.  This was a bit of a long shot, but I was always brought up with the saying, “If you don’t ask, you don’t get”, so I thought the worst that he could say would be “No”.</p>

<p>I am thrilled to say that Matt agreed that coming up to Aberdeen would certainly be a possibility, and in fact, he would be interested in doing a tour of the user groups up in Scotland.  Once again, with the help of the <a href="http://aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/post/2011/12/10/Scottish-Meetup-Network.aspx">Scottish Meetup Network</a>, I am delighted to say that we have been able to secure Matt to do 3 User Group Sessions.</p>

<p>The schedule for the tour breaks down as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Tuesday 21 February</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.edinburgh.bcs.org/events/2011-12/120221.htm">What and why every developer needs to know about mobile development - BCS Edinburgh and Scottish Developers</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Wednesday 22nd February</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://dwsmattlacey.eventbrite.com/">What and why every developer needs to know about mobile development - Dundee Web Standards</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Thursday 23rd February</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://adnuguk-feb2012.eventbrite.com/?ref=ebtn">Getting started with Windows Phone – Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>This is a very busy schedule, and hopefully you will be able to catch Matt at one of the above events.  I will update the above with links to full details of all the above events as and when they become available.</p>

<p>If you require any additional information about the above tour, please feel free to get in touch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
