<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Office 365 | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/office-365/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-02T21:24:11+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Office 365 Is Now Free for User Groups]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/office-365-is-now-free-for-user-groups/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-20T07:29:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/office-365-is-now-free-for-user-groups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in June 2011, I asked an <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/can-net-user-groups-get-office365-for-free/">open question</a> to the community regarding Office 365.  The question was simple….</p>

<blockquote>Can .Net User Groups get Office 365 for free?</blockquote>


<p>To me, it seemed like a simple enough question, however, at the time, it seemed that there was no simple answer.  Once the Office 365 Beta that I was using for managing the <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/">Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group</a> email expired, I transitioned to using a paid P1 plan.  This was for a number of reasons:</p>

<ol>
<li><p> The Office 365 Service is very good!  It does exactly what it says on the tin, and I had already done the hard work of setting up the domain, and getting it all working.</p></li>
<li><p> As I mentioned in my earlier blog post, it is not a huge amount of money for the service, so I was happy to pay for it.  The only slight problem being that other members of the User Group simply use email aliases, rather than having a full-blown mailbox, as we couldn’t warrant paying for an account for everyone.</p></li>
<li><p> There was still no confirmation on whether we could, or could not get it for free.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>However, thanks to an email from Andrew Westgarth (<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/apwestgarth">@apwestgarth</a>), I am happy to be able to let you know that through <a href="https://www.technicalcommunity.com/Pages/default.aspx">UGSS</a> (User Group Support Services), it is now possible to get an E3 Office 365 Plan for your User Group.  Full details of the offer can be found here:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.microsofttraining.com/office365/">http://www.microsofttraining.com/office365/</a></p>

<p>I have just started the registration process, so I haven’t got this all setup yet, but if I run into any problems, I will let you know.  I am hoping that there isn’t going to be a problem with already having a paid Office 365 Plan, as the registration instructions mention starting a trial Office 365 Plan, but we will wait and see.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Lync 2010 for Windows Phone – Won’t Connect to Office 365]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/microsoft-lync-2010-for-windows-phone-wont-connect-to-office-365/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-12T12:37:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/microsoft-lync-2010-for-windows-phone-wont-connect-to-office-365</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/clip_image002.jpg"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/clip_image002_thumb.jpg" alt="clip_image002" /></a></p>

<p>This morning, thanks to the medium of Twitter I found out that the Lync 2010 Client for Windows Phone had been released. A quick search on the Marketplace, and the application was downloading onto my Phone.</p>

<p>I immediately went and typed in the credentials for my Office 365 account expecting that it would just work, however, it came back with an error saying that it was “Unable to Sign In” and that I should check my sign in details, and server etc.</p>

<p>The first thing I checked was that Lync was still connecting fine from my desktop application, and it was. The second thing I tried was to manually type in the server name (or what I thought was the server name) into the necessary places, however, this didn’t work either.</p>

<p>After a bit of googling/binging, I found this:</p>

<p><a href="http://community.office365.com/en-us/w/lync/1040.aspx">http://community.office365.com/en-us/w/lync/1040.aspx</a></p>

<p>Which suggested that I needed to add another CNAME record to my DNS configuration in order for the Windows Phone application to work correctly. However, as per this <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=260">blog post</a> I believed that I had already setup the required DNS Settings. Time to investigate…</p>

<p><strong><em>NOTE: What follows is only required is your are managing your own DNS entries for your Office 365 Domain.</em></strong></p>

<p>After logging into my Office 365 account, I selected:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Home</p></li>
<li><p>Admin</p></li>
<li><p>Management | Domains</p></li>
<li><p>Selected the domain of interest, and then click “Manage DNS”</p></li>
</ul>


<p>And sure enough, the required DNS Records for Office 365 had changed since I last looked at it:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/clip_image0024.jpg"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/clip_image0024_thumb.jpg" alt="clip_image002[4]" /></a></p>

<p>There is a new CNAME entry for lyncdiscover.gep13.co.uk. And actually, the requirement for the second SRV record has been removed, replaced with another CNAME record.</p>

<p>I then set about making the required changes with my domain registrar, and after the required propagation time, I am happy to report that I am now able to connect my Windows Phone running Lync 2010 to my Office 365 account.</p>

<p>It would be nice to know if there were notifications about the changes to the DNS requirements for Office 365. If anyone knows where I can get these, I would be very interested to hear about it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can’t Access #Office365 From Office Hub on #WP7]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/cant-access-office365-from-office-hub-on-wp7/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-20T17:09:09+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/cant-access-office365-from-office-hub-on-wp7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As some of you may know, I have been using the <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=260">Office365</a> for some time now. I use it both for my personal email accounts, as well as the email accounts for the <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/">Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group</a>. Personally, I think it is a great product, however, I have recently found out something rather <em><strong>annoying</strong></em> (that was the polite version of the word I wanted to use).</p>

<p>As advertised here:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/office365/plans/small-business/office-web-apps.aspx#fbid=0-IIc1QYd7Q">http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/office365/plans/small-business/office-web-apps.aspx#fbid=0-IIc1QYd7Q</a></p>

<p>one of the biggest selling points is the integration with mobile devices such as Windows Phone 7. Notice in the above link that I should be able to:</p>

<blockquote>  
> 
> Access and view files in high fidelity from your mobile device. 
> 
> </blockquote>


<p>Now, during the Office365 Beta, it was well understood that this functionality wasn’t available, however, when Office365 rolled out, it was going to be available to both the Professional and Small Business Plans for Office365.</p>

<p><em>NOTE: I am currently using the Small Business Plan</em></p>

<p>Now that the Beta is finished, and everything has settled down, I set about trying to get access to my SharePoint Team Site using the Office Hub on my Windows Phone 7, but I was disheartened to find out that it didn’t work.</p>

<p>Every time I try, I get the error message:</p>

<blockquote>  
> 
> SharePoint doesn’t support non-SharePoint servers and can’t open the requested content. You can try opening the content in your browser instead.
> 
> </blockquote>


<p>I have spoken to a couple people I know who also have a Windows Phone 7 handset and who use Office365, and they have told me that they can get this to work without any problems.</p>

<p>To start with, I thought that there must be something wrong with my setup, however, after doing some digging, it turns out that the problem is the plan that I am on! Namely, the P1 Small Business Plan.</p>

<p>At the minute, Windows Phone 7 Office Hub only supports access to SharePoint online via an HTTPS connection, and unfortunately, this is not offered in the P1 Small Business Plan. I can access the site through Internet Explorer Mobile, however, this doesn’t offer the high fidelity access to files that was promised above!!</p>

<p>A bit more digging turned up this:</p>

<p><a href="http://community.office365.com/en-us/w/sharepoint/527.aspx">http://community.office365.com/en-us/w/sharepoint/527.aspx</a></p>

<p>In my opinion, Microsoft have got the messaging very wrong here, and they need to do something to correct it, <em><strong>fast</strong></em>!!</p>

<p>I think both the Windows Phone 7 device and Office365 are great products, and I am willing to wait until Mango ships so that I can get them to work together, but I can understand how newcomers to either platform will be very disappointed to find out that what it promised isn’t actually possible yet!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can .Net User Groups Get @Office365 for Free?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/can-net-user-groups-get-office365-for-free/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-29T07:40:37+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/can-net-user-groups-get-office365-for-free</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For a few months now I have been using the Office365 Beta to run the email accounts for the <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/">Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group</a> and I am happy to say that it has been working really well, and in all honesty, it “just” works.</p>

<p>I have it hooked up through Outlook on my desktop as an Exchange Account, and also through my Windows Phone 7. Initially, there were a couple teething problems to get the <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=260">required DNS entries sorted out</a>, but that was more of a problem with my hosting provider than anything else.</p>

<p>As a User Group we are “toying” with the idea of perhaps using the supplied SharePoint Team Site to host the actual .Net User Group Website and fully utilise the built in Document Library functionality of SharePoint to share documents/slide decks with our users, as well as collaborate on User Group documents.</p>

<p>Now comes the problem though…</p>

<p>Since the Office365 program is now out of Beta, you now have to pay for the service. <img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/wlEmoticon-sadsmile2.png" alt="Sad smile" /></p>

<p>Don’t get me wrong, this is not a huge amount of money, it starts at £4 per user, per month (full details can be found <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-gb/office365/online-software.aspx">here</a>), but given that we are a User Group who runs free events for the community, there simply isn’t any budget allocated for this type of service.</p>

<p>So, as an open question to Microsoft (are you there?) I would like to request that this service be provided free of charge to .Net User Groups across the country.</p>

<p>We (.Net User Groups) are investing a lot of time in energy in bringing events to our members and informing them about your technology stack so I think it would be a great idea if this service could be provided to help us continue to do this.</p>

<p>So…</p>

<p>What do you think?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Configure DNS Settings for Office 365]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/configure-dns-settings-for-office-365/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-15T12:36:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/configure-dns-settings-for-office-365</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the last few weeks I have been trying to sort of my installation of the <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/office365/online-software.aspx">Office 365 Beta</a>. I am not a business, but the Beta is open to individuals as well as corporate people. There are several reasons that I wanted to play with it:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Sheer curiosity. I heard a lot about it while I was at the <a href="http://www.sharepointbestpractices.co.uk/">BPCUK conference</a></p></li>
<li><p>Wanted to try out the full integration experience with Windows Phone 7</p></li>
<li><p>Try out some sandboxed SharePoint solutions</p></li>
<li><p>Set up a meeting place for the administrators of the <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/">Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>When you get your invite to the Beta you will be asked to hand over a domain to Office 365 to take over the administration of. The majority of the time, that shouldn’t really be a problem as the domain that you are likely to want to host on Office 365 will be a dedicated one for that purpose, however, if like me you use the domain for other stuff, or you administer your own DNS settings, you won’t want to hand over the domain to their control.</p>

<p>Although not mentioned when you first log into the Office 365 setup page, you are able to configure the DNS settings yourself, the end result is that the domain entries simply point to Office 365, rather than being under their direct control.</p>

<p>Now, before we go too much further, let me state that I actually know very little about setting up DNS entries, and it was only through the help of <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/ianmoran">@ianmoran</a> that I was actually able to get mine working.</p>

<p><em>NOTE: Ian has a post </em><a href="http://www.konnexion.com/?p=177"><em>here</em></a><em> that I used as an aid to get up and running</em></p>

<p><em><strong>Required DNS Records</strong></em></p>

<p>In order to know the DNS settings that you need to configure you have to log into the administration section of Office 365. Once in there, click on Admin. From there, click on Domains in the left hand menu, then click on the domain that you want to administer. Once there, click on DNS Manager, and you will see something like the following:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/image4.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/image_thumb4.png" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p>These are all the records that you will need to configure on your domain. The first set are used for the Exchange Email and the second set are used of setting up <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/mssmallbiz/archive/2010/11/16/microsoft-lync-2010-information-and-resources-for-you.aspx">Lync 2010</a>.</p>

<p>If like me, you will be able to set up the majority of these records without too much trouble. It is just a case of logging into your hosting provider and adding the records. I did this without any problems through <a href="http://www.blacknight.com/">Blacknight’s</a> control panel for the MX, CNAME and TXT records.</p>

<p>However, when it came to the SRV records, I was stumped. I had never heard of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SRV_record">SRV</a> (Service Record) before, and through the Blacknight control panel it appeared that I was only able to create the <em>tcp protocol record, there was no option to create a </em>tls protocol record. A quick email to the support team confirmed this, but I was told that they would be able to create the record on my behalf, phew!</p>

<p>With all the records created, I set about testing it. The Exchange email started working straight away, both through Outlook on the desktop, Webmail on the Internet, and through Outlook on my Windows Phone 7. Success!!</p>

<p>However, when it came to Lync 2010, I just couldn’t get it to work!</p>

<p><strong><em>Manual Lync 2010 Configuration</em></strong></p>

<p>With the help of Ian, I was able to set up Lync 2010 manually, to prove that it worked at all. This was done by going into Lync and selecting Tools | Options, and from there click “Advanced…”</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/image5.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/image_thumb5.png" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p>Then, in the Advanced Connection Settings dialogue, manually configure the internal and external server names to be sipdir.online.lync.com:443:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/image6.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/image_thumb6.png" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p>And this will allow you to log into Lync using your user that you set up in Office 365.</p>

<p><strong><em>Testing SRV Records</em></strong></p>

<p>Although manually settings the records was “fine” I wanted to figure out what was wrong with my set up. In order to do that, I had to figure out what the records were set up as. The feedback that I was getting from Blacknight was that everything was fine on their end, but I had no way of verifying that. I had a report that they were using <a href="http://linux.die.net/man/1/dig">dig</a> to confirm the records, however, I don’t have a linux server to use that command, and even though I installed the Windows version of <a href="http://members.shaw.ca/nicholas.fong/dig/">dig</a>, I just couldn’t get it to work.</p>

<p>I fell back on trying to use nslookup to get the information that I needed, and I was finally able to figure out how to do this.</p>

<ol>
<li><p> Start | run</p></li>
<li><p> Type cmd then press enter</p></li>
<li><p> Type nslookup and then press enter</p></li>
<li><p> Type set type=srv and then press enter</p></li>
<li><p> Type <em>sip.</em>tls.<your domain name here> and press enter</p></li>
<li><p> You will then get the record back</p></li>
<li><p> Type <em>sipfederationtls.</em>tcp.<your domain name here> and press enter</p></li>
<li><p> You will then get your record back</p></li>
</ol>


<p>The output should look something like this:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/SRV-Records.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/SRV-Records_thumb.png" alt="SRV Records" /></a></p>

<p><em>NOTE: There records are the ones that are misconfigured</em></p>

<p>Now, when I looked at this, I thought everything looked ok, when compared to the above screen shot for the DNS Manager settings within Office 365. However, when I showed this to Ian, who must have a keener eye than me, he told me that the _tls entry was incorrect. Notice how the svr hostname is appended with .aberdeendevelopers.co.uk? That is incorrect. Turns out that the SRV record which had been entered by Blacknight was missing a trailing period, which meant that the domain name was getting appended. I didn’t realise setting up DNS entries was this complicated!!</p>

<p>Another quick email to Blacknight support cleared up this problem, and I was then able to connect to Lync 2010, win!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
