<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<link rel="self" href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/" />
	<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
	<title>Gary Ewan Park</title>
	<rights>2018</rights>
	<updated>2018-11-25T13:51:43Z</updated>
	<subtitle>Ramblings and Ponderings of a Microsoft Fan Boy...</subtitle>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/introducing-chocolatey-vscode-extension" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/introducing-chocolatey-vscode-extension</id>
		<title>Introducing the Chocolatey VS Code Extension</title>
		<updated>2018-11-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;This announcement blog post is a &amp;quot;little&amp;quot; late.  The first version of this &lt;a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=gep13.chocolatey-vscode"&gt;VS Code Extension&lt;/a&gt; was created back in January 2016, however, it is only recently that it has been given a new lease of life, with some additional functionality around executing Chocolatey commands from within VS Code.  As a result, I thought this was a good time to introduce it properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-is-it"&gt;What is it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=gep13.chocolatey-vscode"&gt;Chocolatey Extension for VS Code&lt;/a&gt; brings with it a number of commands and snippets to help with the creation and packaging of Chocolatey packages.  There are plans for adding more commands into the extension as time permits, and if you are interested in helping out with adding more functionality, please feel free to get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="why-is-this-needed"&gt;Why is this needed?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When getting started with Chocolatey, it can be a little daunting to get up to speed with the various commands that are required to create, pack and push, Chocolatey packages.  While there is extensive documentation to guide you through this process, it can be a little overwhelming.  This extension is an attempt to help with some of these tasks, to help guide you through this process, via the use of snippets, and most recently, commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="installation"&gt;Installation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installing the &lt;a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=gep13.chocolatey-vscode"&gt;Chocolatey Extension for VS Code&lt;/a&gt; is simple, it installs in the same way as any other extension.  Open Extensions from the left hand side section of VS Code, or select View | Extensions.  Then do a search for &amp;quot;chocolatey&amp;quot; and the extension with an author of &amp;quot;Gary Ewan Park&amp;quot; should be returned.  Go ahead and install the extension:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/11/25/Chocolatey-Extension-Install.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Chocolatey Extension Install" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When prompted, click the Reload button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/11/25/Chocolatey-Extension-Reload.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Chocolatey Extension Reload" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="usage"&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="snippets"&gt;Snippets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you are editing your Chocolatey Packaging scripts, you can begin typing the word &lt;code&gt;choco&lt;/code&gt; and it will bring up some snippets to help with the creation of some of the Chocolatey Helper methods, as shown here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/11/25/Chocolatey-Snippets.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Chocolatey Snippets" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After selecting one, you will then have the option of pressing the tab key on your keyboard, to start stepping through the various parameters, filling in the ones that are required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/11/25/Chocolatey-Snippet-Output.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Chocolatey Snippet Output" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The snippets that are generated are based on the Chocolatey Best Practices from the output of the default template from the &lt;code&gt;choco new&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="commands"&gt;Commands&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you open the command palette for VS Code, and type &lt;code&gt;choco&lt;/code&gt;, you will be met with two commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create new Chocolatey Package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pack Chocolatey Package(s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/11/25/Chocolatey-Commands.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Chocolatey Commands" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first will take as an input the name of the Chocolatey Package that you want to create, and it will then execute the &lt;code&gt;choco new&lt;/code&gt; command, placing the output into the root of the current workspace which is open in VS Code.  You can see the output here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/11/25/Chocolatey-New-Output.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Chocolatey New Output" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second command will look through the current workspace, and find any &lt;code&gt;*.nuspec&lt;/code&gt; files that are contained with it.  Then, you can either select an individual nuspec file, or all of them, to then execute the &lt;code&gt;choco pack&lt;/code&gt; command on them.  You will be prompted for any additional arguments that you would like to pass into this command.  For example, you might want to pass something like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-sh"&gt;--output-directory=&amp;quot;'c:/temp'&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To have the generated &lt;code&gt;*.nupkg&lt;/code&gt; files placed into a different directory, rather than being generated next to the nuspec file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="notes"&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you can install this extension in VS Code running on other operating systems, it will only work in its entirity on a Windows Machine.  Attempting to run the commands on another operating system, will result in the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/11/25/Chocolatey-Not-Installed.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Chocolatey Not Installed" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find additional documentation for this extension here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://gep13.github.io/chocolatey-vscode/"&gt;https://gep13.github.io/chocolatey-vscode/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;:  At the time of writing this blog post, there is little to no documentation, but the scaffolding is there to get some added, so if you are interested, please feel free to jump in and help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="resources"&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in hear about new functions that are being added into the Extension, I have a YouTube Playlist &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL84yg23i9GBhIhNG4LaeXNHwxZYJaSqgj"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, where I will push short videos of the new functionality as each version is released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="source-code"&gt;Source Code&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code for this Extension can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/gep13/chocolatey-vscode"&gt;https://github.com/gep13/chocolatey-vscode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="chat-room"&gt;Chat Room&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this Extension, then please feel to drop into the Gitter Chat room:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://gitter.im/gep13/chocolatey-vscode?utm_source=badge&amp;amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pr-badge&amp;amp;utm_content=badge"&gt;&lt;img src="https://badges.gitter.im/gep13/chocolatey-vscode.svg" class="img-fluid" alt="Join the chat at https://gitter.im/gep13/chocolatey-vscode" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="thanks"&gt;Thanks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The execution of the Chocolatey commands in this extension would not have been possible without the amazing work of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/felixrieseberg/vsc-ember-cli"&gt;Ember CLI VS Code extension&lt;/a&gt;, as this was used as the basis for creating this feature in this extension. Huge thanks to &lt;a href="Fhttps://github.com/felixrieseber"&gt;Felix Rieseberg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;This announcement blog post is a "little" late.  The first version of this &lt;a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=gep13.chocolatey-vscode"&gt;VS Code Extension&lt;/a&gt; was created back in January 2016, however, it is only recently that it has been given a new lease of life, with some additional functionality around executing Chocolatey commands from within VS Code.  As a result, I thought this was a good time to introduce it properly.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/stack-overflow-reputation-history" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/stack-overflow-reputation-history</id>
		<title>Stack Overflow Reputation History</title>
		<updated>2018-11-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;Anyone that knows me, knows that I like numbers.  I like to track numbers over time, and see how things are changing.  Are they getting better?  Worse?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with this in mind, a couple months ago, I was looking at my Stack Overflow profile, and I was curious about how, if at all, my reputation points (you know, those Internet points, that don't really mean anything to anyone, but it is still nice to have them?!?), had changed over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-problem"&gt;The Problem&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the main Stack Overflow Profile page, you are met with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/11/04/Stack-Overflow-Reputation.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Stack Overflow Reputation" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, granted, I can hover over this little bar graph, and I see a tooltip for what is was at a particular point in time, but it isn't very clear on what date it correlates to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-did-you-do"&gt;What did you do?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I went googling, thinking that this must be something that can be done better.  Stack Overflow is made by a bunch of developers, who likely also like numbers.  What I turned up was that there is a REST API for getting additional information back from Stack Overflow, but in all honesty, I didn't want to have to go to that length to have to get this information.  I even sent out a Tweet about it, as I thought that this &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; be possible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jonskeet?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;&amp;#64;jonskeet&lt;/a&gt; random question for you... Do you know if this is possible? &lt;a href="https://t.co/pYggrm2lUv"&gt;https://t.co/pYggrm2lUv&lt;/a&gt; It was suggested that it was, but I didn&amp;#39;t get a follow up.  Thanks in advance!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Gary Ewan Park (&amp;#64;gep13) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gep13/status/975662609176387584?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-was-the-outcome"&gt;What was the outcome?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a bit of digging, I found that you can get MUCH more information on your Network Profile page, rather than simply your Stack Overflow Profile page.  For those that aren't aware, you can get to this from here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/11/04/Link-To-Network-Profile.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Link to Network Profile" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And once there, if you click on the reputation tab, you get a much larger line graph, with much more detail about your reputation, and on what day it changed, etc.  So now you can rejoice in more data than you will ever need on these particular Internet Points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/11/04/Network-Profile-Reputation.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Network Profile Reputation" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is mainly for me to remember where I can get this information again if I ever need it, and I thought that is might be useful to other like minded, numbers oriented people.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Anyone that knows me, knows that I like numbers.  I like to track numbers over time, and see how things are changing.  Are they getting better?  Worse?&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/chocolatey-error-hashes-do-not-match" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/chocolatey-error-hashes-do-not-match</id>
		<title>Chocolatey Package Error - Checksums do not match</title>
		<updated>2018-10-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;Earlier today on Twitter, I was asked this question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gep13?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;&amp;#64;gep13&lt;/a&gt; I tried installing &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JuliaLanguage?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;&amp;#64;JuliaLanguage&lt;/a&gt; but I get this error: &lt;a href="https://t.co/QEvqqayjSU"&gt;https://t.co/QEvqqayjSU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;I would appreciate if you could help&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Foad Sojoodi Farimani (&amp;#64;fsfarimani) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fsfarimani/status/1056873572344356864?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 29, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to write a response, but I realised that it was going to take more than 240 characters to explain, so I thought I would write a blog post about it instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-error"&gt;The Error&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error that is being reported by Chocolatey is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/29/checksums-do-not-match.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Checksums do not match" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I verified that I was getting the same error message by testing the installation on the local Chocolatey Testing Environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-does-this-mean"&gt;What does this mean?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's great, but what does that actually mean?  Let's break this log down a little bit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progress: 100% - Completed download of C:\Users\Administrator\AppData\Local\Temp\chocolatey\Julia\1.0.0\julia-1.0.0-win64.exe
(52.83 MB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tells us that Chocolatey successfully went into the chocolateyInstall.ps1 file and found the download URL that the package maintainer put in there.  Notice that it has downloaded the 64-bit version of this installer, since I ran it on a 64-bit operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download of julia-1.0.0-win64.exe (52.83 MB) completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tells us that Chocolatey was successfully able to download a file from the specified URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Error - hashes do not match. Actual value was '001874185A26F598ABE2E7FC287CACF66387C68CAA3251F5AA6EF97FB22020DD'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where things start to go wrong.  When the download of a file has been completed, Chocolatey will take a checksum (i.e. a hash) of the file.  This can then be compared to the checksum (if provided) by the package maintainer.  In this case, the package maintainer expected the checksum of the file to be &lt;code&gt;3bf5572cbcbc7848b235dcf21caf24ce26b9fb3839eb13db1a7170d20cdf834d&lt;/code&gt; but it was actually &lt;code&gt;001874185A26F598ABE2E7FC287CACF66387C68CAA3251F5AA6EF97FB22020DD&lt;/code&gt;.  Since Chocolatey is secure by default, the installation of the package immediately exits, and an error is thrown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERROR: Checksum for 'C:\Users\Administrator\AppData\Local\Temp\chocolatey\Julia\1.0.0\julia-1.0.0-win64.exe' did not meet '3b
f5572cbcbc7848b235dcf21caf24ce26b9fb3839eb13db1a7170d20cdf834d' for checksum type 'sha256'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id="why-do-we-need-checksums"&gt;Why do we need checksums?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chocolatey introduced the concept of checksums for package installation to provide some assurance to the end users of Chocolatey that the application installers that are being downloaded are correct/valid.  At the time of creating a package, we ask package maintainers to include the checksum for the files that are being downloaded, so that at installation time, this checksum can be asserted to ensure that what is being installed is what is expected.  This protects the user from any malicious tampering of the application installer.  When creating the package, the maintainer can sometimes find the published checksum of the files on the vendor website, or they can calculate the checksum of the file(s) themselves once they have tested to make sure that it is installed correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="so-why-did-this-go-wrong"&gt;So why did this go wrong?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, all of this makes perfect sense, and will work flawlessly, until one of two common things happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, some packages (like Google Chrome) don't included versioned URL's for their application installer.  As a result, you can only ever download the Chrome installer from one location, namely &lt;code&gt;https://dl.google.com/tag/s/dl/chrome/install/googlechromestandaloneenterprise64.msi&lt;/code&gt;.  As a result, whenever Google push out a new version of Chrome, which happens quite frequently, the most recent package version of Chrome on Chocolatey.org is immediately broken.  This is due to the fact that the checksum within the Chocolatey package is still the checksum for the old installer available at that URL, which has now been replaced with the new one.  In the case of the Google Chrome package, it is part of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/chocolatey/chocolatey-coreteampackages"&gt;Core Team Packages&lt;/a&gt; which checks for new package versions every 6 hours, and automatically pushes out a new package when detected.  As a result of this, the Google Chrome package is normally only &amp;quot;broken&amp;quot; for a short period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second way that checksums will break is if vendor &amp;quot;change&amp;quot; the application installer once it has been published, without changing the version number.  Unfortunately, this happens more often than you would think.  Let's walk this through...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A vendor creates a new version of their application, let's call it 1.0.0, and publishes it to their website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Chocolatey Package maintainer spots that there is a new version pf the application, and sets about creating the Chocolatey package.  They download the installer, test that it is all working, and then calculate the checksum, update their packaging scripts, run &lt;code&gt;choco pack&lt;/code&gt; and push the package version to Chocolatey.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The automated checks on Chocolatey.org then kick in to make sure that the package does indeed download and install correctly, including verifying that the hashes match.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The package is then moved to human moderation, and the package is ultimately approved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some time later, the vendor then notices that there is a problem with the installer, and rather than increment the version number, they simply re-build the installer, and replace it on their website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To anyone installing the application directly from the website, there are no problems.  However, to anyone installing the Chocolatey package, there will be error, as the checksum on the file which is downloaded, compared to the checksum in the Chocolatey package, will no longer match.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we know that the package in question completed the automated installation test, we know that at one point the checksum on the installer did match what is in the package, however, this installer no longer has this checksum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-can-i-do-about-it"&gt;What can I do about it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to fix this problem would be to reach out to the maintainers of the package and ask them to push a new package version that includes the correct checksum.  In the case of this package, there is actually a new version of the application available, so this package is due to be updated.  If there wasn't a new version available, then the maintainer could push a new package version using what is known as the &lt;a href="https://chocolatey.org/docs/create-packages#package-fix-version-notation"&gt;package fix notation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this isn't an option, or you need the installation &amp;quot;right&amp;quot; now, you have two options, both of which are mentioned in the error message above.  The first would be to run this command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-powershell"&gt;choco install julia --checksum64 001874185A26F598ABE2E7FC287CACF66387C68CAA3251F5AA6EF97FB22020DD
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The checksum in question is actually reported from Chocolatey, so what you need to ascertain is whether you trust that checksum.  To be safe, you would probably want to go to the vendor download page and verify this yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final option would be to run the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-powershell"&gt;choco install julia --ignore-checksums
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is by far the least secure method, and it isn't one that I recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the fact that Chocolatey is secure by default, there are situations like this that do occur.  However, please bear in mind that Chocolatey is trying to protect you from what could be a malicious installer.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Earlier today on Twitter, I was asked this question:&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/introducing-cake.discord-addin" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/introducing-cake.discord-addin</id>
		<title>Introducing the Cake.Discord Addin</title>
		<updated>2018-10-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;h1 id="what-is-it"&gt;What is it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/Cake.Discord/"&gt;Cake.Discord&lt;/a&gt; is an addin for Cake that allows you to send messages to a Discord Channel on a Server.  This allows for example sending a notification to a channel when a build fails, or succeeds.  Or perhaps when a new release of an application has been created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; While it is possible to send much more complicated messages to a Discord server, this initial release of the addin only caters for the basic versions of the messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="usage"&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started using this addin, all you need to do is add the following to your Cake script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;#addin &amp;quot;nuget:https://www.nuget.org/api/v2?package=Cake.Discord&amp;amp;version=0.1.0&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Depending on the currently released version, you might want to change the above to reflect the current version number. The above is shown to ensure that the best practice of pinning your Cake Addin version numbers is adhered to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that done, you can then send a basic message using something like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;Information(&amp;quot;This is a 'normal' message...&amp;quot;);

var postMessageResult = Discord.Chat.PostMessage(
    webHookUrl:&amp;quot;https://your_web_hook_url&amp;quot;,
    content:&amp;quot;This is a normal message.&amp;quot;
);

if (postMessageResult.Ok)
{
    Information(&amp;quot;Message {0} successfully sent&amp;quot;, postMessageResult.TimeStamp);
}
else
{
    Error(&amp;quot;Failed to send message: {0}&amp;quot;, postMessageResult.Error);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also possible to send a more complex message using something like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;Information(&amp;quot;This is a custom avatar and name message...&amp;quot;);

var postMessageResult = Discord.Chat.PostMessage(
    webHookUrl:&amp;quot;https://your_web_hook_url&amp;quot;,
    content:&amp;quot;This is a custom avatar and name message.&amp;quot;,
    messageSettings: new DiscordChatMessageSettings {
        UserName = &amp;quot;gep13&amp;quot;,
        AvatarUrl = new Uri(&amp;quot;https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/1271146?s=400&amp;amp;v=4&amp;quot;)
    }
);

if (postMessageResult.Ok)
{
    Information(&amp;quot;Message {0} successfully sent&amp;quot;, postMessageResult.TimeStamp);
}
else
{
    Error(&amp;quot;Failed to send message: {0}&amp;quot;, postMessageResult.Error);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h1 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find additional documentation for this addin here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cake-contrib.github.io/Cake.Discord/"&gt;https://cake-contrib.github.io/Cake.Discord/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="source-code"&gt;Source Code&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code for this addin can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.Discord"&gt;https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="chat-room"&gt;Chat Room&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this addin, then please feel to drop into the Gitter Chat room for all the addins and modules which exist in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib"&gt;cake-contrib organisation&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://gitter.im/cake-contrib/Lobby?utm_source=badge&amp;amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pr-badge&amp;amp;utm_content=badge"&gt;&lt;img src="https://badges.gitter.im/cake-contrib/Lobby.svg" class="img-fluid" alt="Join the chat at https://gitter.im/cake-contrib/Lobby" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="other-notification-addins"&gt;Other Notification Addins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This addin adds to the collection of addins which help with sending notifications out to the various platforms that exist.  For example, there are addins to help with sending notifications to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.CakeMail/"&gt;CakeMail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.Email/"&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.Gitter/"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.HipChat/"&gt;HipChat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/Ninglin/Cake.Jira/"&gt;Jira&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.MicrosoftTeams/"&gt;Microsoft Teams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.SendGrid/"&gt;SendGrid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.Slack/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.Twitter/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there any other notification systems that you feel should be catered for in Cake?  If so, feel free to reach out, or create your own.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/Cake.Discord/"&gt;Cake.Discord&lt;/a&gt; is an addin for Cake that allows you to send messages to a Discord Channel on a Server.  This allows for example sending a notification to a channel when a build fails, or succeeds.  Or perhaps when a new release of an application has been created.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/installing-mojave" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/installing-mojave</id>
		<title>Installing macOS Mojave</title>
		<updated>2018-10-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I got this notification on my Mac:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/should-i-do-this.jpg_large" class="img-fluid" alt="Should I do this" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since getting my Mac at the start of this year when I started working for Chocolatey Software, Inc, this is the first major operating system update that I have been presented with, so I was a little anxious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reached out to Twitter, and the overall responses seemed to be positive, so I thought I would go for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Should I do this?  Any known problems? &lt;a href="https://t.co/hk9900cYZG"&gt;pic.twitter.com/hk9900cYZG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Gary Ewan Park (&amp;#64;gep13) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/gep13/status/1054355206048284672?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 22, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After making sure that everything was backed up via Time Machine, and Backblaze, I clicked the install button...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-did-it-go"&gt;How did it go?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy to say that overall, the process was fairly straight forward, as shown in the series to screenshots below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/first-step.png" class="img-fluid" alt="First Step" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/dock-icon.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Dock Icon" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/getting-started.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Getting started" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/accept-the-license.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Accept the license" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/install-mojave.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Install Mojave" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where did I put that power cord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/give-me-power.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Give me power" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/give-me-access.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Give me access" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How good is the Apple Random Number Generator?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/10-minutes-remaining.png" class="img-fluid" alt="10 minutes remaining" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out it was pretty good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/click-to-restart.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Click to restart" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the Mac restarted a couple times, and proceeded to show the Apple Icon for about 30 minutes, while it did it's work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After selecting a few options, including selecting the new Dark Theme, I was welcomed with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/mojave-desktop.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Mojave Desktop" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having played with it for a little while now, everything seems to be working fine.  The only slight issue that I have noticed is that when starting up some applications, I see something that looks like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/access-the-microphone.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Access the microphone" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in this latest version of the Operating System there are some additional permissions that applications need to request in order to continue doing what they were doing before.  I have seen this also pop up on applications like VMWare Fusion, Slack, etc.  Seems to be anything that has the ability to interact with the hardware of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE: 24 Oct 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After switching on computer this morning, I was met with a slightly more scary warning from the Backblaze Application:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/10/23/backblaze-notification.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Backblaze notification" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was different from all the others as it required additional changes to the security settings to allow Backblaze to function as it had before.  Full details of this can be found in their blog post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://help.backblaze.com/hc/en-us/articles/360009644134-MacOS-10-14-Mojave-FAQ-"&gt;https://help.backblaze.com/hc/en-us/articles/360009644134-MacOS-10-14-Mojave-FAQ-&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With those changes made, everything seems to be working again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I got this notification on my Mac:&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/introducing-cake.dotnettool.module" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/introducing-cake.dotnettool.module</id>
		<title>Introducing the Cake.DotNetTool.Module</title>
		<updated>2018-10-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;h1 id="what-is-it"&gt;What is it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in version &lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-build/cake/releases/tag/v0.13.0"&gt;0.13.0&lt;/a&gt; of Cake a feature known as &lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-build/cake/issues/646"&gt;Module Support&lt;/a&gt; was released.  This provided the ability to both extend and replace some of the built in functionality of Cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these extension points is the registration of &lt;a href="http://cakebuild.net/api/Cake.Core.Packaging/IPackageInstaller/"&gt;IPackageInstaller&lt;/a&gt;'s, which deal with installing tools and addins during the Cake Script execution.  The DotNet Tool Module utilizes this extension point to allow tools to be resolved using the &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/core/tools/dotnet-tool-install"&gt;DotNet CLI&lt;/a&gt;, specifically, the &lt;code&gt;dotnet tool&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;code&gt;dotnet tool&lt;/code&gt; command deals with the installation of tools.  As a result, it only makes sense for this module to deal with tools, and not addins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="why-is-this-needed"&gt;Why is this needed?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the box, Cake has the ability to install tools and addins from any NuGet source.  This is documented on the &lt;a href="http://cakebuild.net/docs/fundamentals/preprocessor-directives"&gt;Cake Website&lt;/a&gt;.  Recently, &lt;a href="https://github.com/larzw"&gt;Larz White&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://cakebuild.net/blog/2017/01/cake-paket"&gt;showed&lt;/a&gt; how it was possible to use an alternative package manager, namely &lt;a href="https://fsprojects.github.io/Paket/"&gt;Paket&lt;/a&gt; to install those tools and addins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are a growing number of tools that can be installed as Global DotNet Tools (there is a list of these compiled &lt;a href="https://github.com/natemcmaster/dotnet-tools"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; by Nate McMaster).  Cake itself, is actually published as a DotNet Global Tool.  As part of your build process, you might want to have these tools installed, ready to be used.  However, what I want to be able to do is to define the installation of these tools in the same way as I do my other tools and addins, so that everything is in the same place.  For example, I want to put them right here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;///////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////
// TOOLS
///////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////////

#tool nuget:?package=coveralls.io&amp;amp;version=1.3.4
#tool nuget:?package=gitreleasemanager&amp;amp;version=0.5.0
#tool nuget:?package=GitVersion.CommandLine&amp;amp;version=3.6.2
#tool nuget:?package=JetBrains.ReSharper.CommandLineTools&amp;amp;version=2016.3.20161223.160402
#tool nuget:?package=ReSharperReports&amp;amp;version=0.2.0
#tool nuget:?package=KuduSync.NET&amp;amp;version=1.3.1
#tool nuget:?package=Wyam&amp;amp;version=0.16.1
#tool nuget:?package=gitlink&amp;amp;version=2.4.1
#tool nuget:?package=MSBuild.Extension.Pack&amp;amp;version=1.9.0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with all the other tools that I use in my build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is what this Cake Module allows you to do.  You can now add the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#tool dotnet:?package=Octopus.DotNet.Cli&amp;amp;version=4.41.0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which would install version 4.41.0 of the &lt;a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/Octopus.DotNet.Cli/4.41.0"&gt;Octopus.DotNet.Cli package&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; What is different here is that &lt;code&gt;dotnet&lt;/code&gt; is being used, rather than &lt;code&gt;nuget&lt;/code&gt;.  This is what causes Cake to defer to the DotNet Tool Module, rather than using NuGet to resolve the tool installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="installation"&gt;Installation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the fact that Cake Modules are extending and altering the internals of the Cake, the Module Assembly needs to be loaded prior to the main Cake execution.  As documented in the &lt;a href="https://cakebuild.net/docs/fundamentals/preprocessor-directives"&gt;Module section of this page&lt;/a&gt;, you simply have to do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./build.sh --bootstrap
./build.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that the first execution of Cake will inspect your Cake script for any module inclusions in your script, and if there are any, download and install them.  And the second execution will then be able to use those modules, and complete the usage of the module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example of a Cake script which both includes the module definition for the DotNet Tool Module, and which also uses it, is shown below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#module nuget:?package=Cake.DotNetTool.Module&amp;amp;version=0.1.0
#tool &amp;quot;dotnet:?package=Octopus.DotNet.Cli&amp;amp;version=4.41.0&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h1 id="usage"&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, installing a tool using the DotNet Tool Module is as simple as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#tool dotnet:?package=Octopus.DotNet.Cli&amp;amp;version=4.41.0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the tool in question comes from a different source, you can change that as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#tool dotnet:https://www.myget.org/F/gep13/api/v2?package=Octopus.DotNet.Cli&amp;amp;version=4.41.0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, the DotNet Tool Module will install a tool to the location of the defined Cake Tools folder (this is normally simply a &lt;code&gt;tools&lt;/code&gt; folder located beside the Cake Script that is being executed).  It is possible to control the location of this tools folder in the &lt;a href="https://cakebuild.net/docs/fundamentals/default-configuration-values"&gt;normal way&lt;/a&gt;, and additionally, you can opt to install the DotNet Tool globally using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#tool dotnet:?package=Octopus.DotNet.Cli&amp;amp;version=4.41.0&amp;amp;global
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional parameters that can be passed to the pre-processor directive include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;configfile
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specifies which NuGet config file should be used during the execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;framework
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specifies the &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/standard/frameworks"&gt;target framework&lt;/a&gt; to install the tool for. By default, the .NET Core SDK tries to choose the most appropriate target framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you can control the logging verbosity of the underlying &lt;code&gt;dotnet tool&lt;/code&gt; command by altering the overall verbosity of the Cake Script execution.  i.e. running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./build.sh --verbosity=diagnostic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;will cause the &lt;code&gt;dotnet tool&lt;/code&gt; command to be ran with diagnostic verbosity as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parameters that can be used in this pre-processor directive come from the documentation which is available &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/core/tools/dotnet-tool-install"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find additional documentation for this module here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cake-contrib.github.io/Cake.DotNetTool.Module/"&gt;https://cake-contrib.github.io/Cake.DotNetTool.Module/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="source-code"&gt;Source Code&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code for this Module can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.DotNetTool.Module"&gt;https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.DotNetTool.Module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="chat-room"&gt;Chat Room&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this Module, then please feel to drop into the Gitter Chat room for all the addins and modules which exist in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib"&gt;cake-contrib organisation&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://gitter.im/cake-contrib/Lobby?utm_source=badge&amp;amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pr-badge&amp;amp;utm_content=badge"&gt;&lt;img src="https://badges.gitter.im/cake-contrib/Lobby.svg" class="img-fluid" alt="Join the chat at https://gitter.im/cake-contrib/Lobby" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="other-cake-modules"&gt;Other Cake Modules&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of other Cake Modules that perform similar functionality for other Package Managers, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/Cake.Paket.Module/"&gt;Cake.Paket.Module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/Cake.Chocolatey.Module/"&gt;Cake.Chocolatey.Module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/Cake.DNF.Module/"&gt;Cake.DNF.Module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/Cake.APT.Module/"&gt;Cake.APT.Module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/Cake.Npm.Module/0.1.0-unstable0014"&gt;Cake.Npm.Module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Back in version &lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-build/cake/releases/tag/v0.13.0"&gt;0.13.0&lt;/a&gt; of Cake a feature known as &lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-build/cake/issues/646"&gt;Module Support&lt;/a&gt; was released.  This provided the ability to both extend and replace some of the built in functionality of Cake.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/mvp-rd-wall-at-msignite" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/mvp-rd-wall-at-msignite</id>
		<title>MVP and RD Wall at Microsoft Ignite</title>
		<updated>2018-09-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;Last week there was a flurry of pictures on Twitter and Facebook from the &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/ignite"&gt;Microsoft Ignite&lt;/a&gt; Conference, and one in particular caught my eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="mvp-and-rd-wall"&gt;MVP and RD Wall&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was this picture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/09/30/mvp_rd_wall.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="MVP and RD Wall" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Full credit to Joel Lindström on Facebook for this photo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was pointed out to me on Twitter by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/punker76/status/1044343384503209988"&gt;Jan Karger&lt;/a&gt; that my name was included in the wall.  A quick check, and indeed I could see my name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/09/30/gep13_mvp_rd_wall.png" class="img-fluid" alt="My name on the wall" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no idea that Microsoft did this, and I really think it is a nice touch, to show appreciation to all the MVP's and Regional Directors.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Last week there was a flurry of pictures on Twitter and Facebook from the &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/ignite"&gt;Microsoft Ignite&lt;/a&gt; Conference, and one in particular caught my eye.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/hacktoberfest-meetup-2018" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/hacktoberfest-meetup-2018</id>
		<title>Hacktoberfest Meetup 2018</title>
		<updated>2018-09-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group are proud to be hosting a Hacktoberfest event on the 4th October 2018.  Full details of the event can be found on the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Aberdeen-Developers-NET-User-Group/events/254881639/"&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://secure.meetupstatic.com/photos/event/b/f/6/6/highres_474768998.jpeg" class="img-fluid" alt="Hacktoberfest" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-is-hacktoberfest"&gt;What is Hacktoberfest?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last 4 years, DigitalOcean (in conjunction with GitHub) have been running an event called Hacktoberfest. It is a month long event where you are encouraged to contribute to Open Source Projects (hosted on GitHub) and in return you get some cool swag (typically a t-shirt and some stickers). All you have to do is submit 5 pull requests to projects on GitHub during the month of October. Registration for the event is completely free. More information on this event can be found here: &lt;a href="https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/"&gt;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have personally taken part in this event for the last three years, and I can vouch for the quality of the swag that you can get your hands on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="ok-so-what-do-i-get-out-of-it"&gt;Ok, so what do I get out of it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, you will need to &lt;a href="https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/"&gt;register&lt;/a&gt; to indicate that you are going to be participating in the event.  If you open up five pull requests between October 1 and October 31, you will get a free, limited edition Hacktoberfest t-shirt. &lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; These pull requests do not need to be merged in order to be counted.  They just need to be opened during the time frame of the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you needed any further encouragement, you also have the ability to grab a free limited edition Microsoft t-shirt, which has been designed by &lt;a href="https://github.com/ashleymcnamara"&gt;Ashley McNamara&lt;/a&gt;.  This was announced by Microsoft in this &lt;a href="https://open.microsoft.com/2018/09/18/hacktoberfest-2018-microsoft/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.  The rule for this t-shirt is simply to open a single pull request in one of the MANY open source repositories that Microsoft have.  A full list of these can be found in the linked blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-is-going-to-happen-at-the-event"&gt;What is going to happen at the event?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event is going to start with me doing a very brief introduction to contributing to Open Source.  This is something I have been involved in for almost 7 years now, and I am now actually working for a company based on the creation of Open Source software, so I have some great, and not so great, stories to tell about it.  We will walk through the basics of doing your first pull request, and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, we will then jump straight into contributing to Open Source projects.  If you have a particular project in mind that's great.  If not, I can point you in the direction of some projects that I know need some help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="how-do-i-sign-up-for-the-event"&gt;How do I sign up for the event?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply visit the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Aberdeen-Developers-NET-User-Group/events/254881639/"&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;, and indicate that you will be attending.  The number of registrations for this event is smaller than normal, but this is due to the space that we have access to.  So I would ask that you only attend the event if you have every intention of completing the Hacktoberfest event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-should-i-bring-with-me"&gt;What should I bring with me?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that you are going to need in order to participate in this event is yourself, your laptop, and some ideas about the Open Source Projects that you would like to contribute to.  Drinks and some snacks will be being provided by &lt;a href="https://www.codify.ltd.uk/"&gt;Codify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully see you there, and feel free to reach out with any questions you might have.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group are proud to be hosting a Hacktoberfest event on the 4th October 2018.  Full details of the event can be found on the &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/Aberdeen-Developers-NET-User-Group/events/254881639/"&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/problem-running-chocolatey-test-environment" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/problem-running-chocolatey-test-environment</id>
		<title>Problem Running Chocolatey Test Environment</title>
		<updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;During a &lt;a href="https://gitter.im/chocolatey/choco?at=5b59cf471be9bb57bcc5a6e4"&gt;Gitter discussion&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, an interesting
point of discussion came up, so I thought I would capture it here in a blog post.  The short version is that you
probably want to make sure that you are using the latest version of Vagrant when trying to use the Chocolatey Test
Environment, although bear in mind that this might not have been tested by anyone, and may have other problems :-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-problem"&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Chocolatey Community member was trying to run the &lt;a href="https://github.com/chocolatey/chocolatey-test-environment"&gt;Chocolatey Test Environment&lt;/a&gt;]
on his Windows 10 machine, they were running into the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-sh"&gt;Bringing machine 'default' up with 'virtualbox' provider...
 ==&amp;gt; default: Box 'ferventcoder/win2012r2-x64-nocm' could not be found. Attempting to find and install...
    default: Box Provider: virtualbox
    default: Box Version: &amp;gt;= 0
The box 'ferventcoder/win2012r2-x64-nocm' could not be found or
could not be accessed in the remote catalog. If this is a private
box on HashiCorp's Atlas, please verify you're logged in via
`vagrant login`. Also, please double-check the name. The expanded
URL and error message are shown below:

URL: [&amp;quot;https://atlas.hashicorp.com/ferventcoder/win2012r2-x64-nocm&amp;quot;]
Error: The requested URL returned error: 404 Not Found
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to the URL shown in the output above, it did indeed result in a 404.  However, a quick
search of the Vagrant Cloud showed that the base box did in fact exist.  You can find it here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.vagrantup.com/ferventcoder/boxes/win2012r2-x64-nocm"&gt;https://app.vagrantup.com/ferventcoder/boxes/win2012r2-x64-nocm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A further test on my own machine, resulted in the following output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-sh"&gt;Bringing machine 'default' up with 'virtualbox' provider...
==&amp;gt; default: Box 'ferventcoder/win2012r2-x64-nocm' could not be found. Attempting to find and install...
default: Box Provider: virtualbox
default: Box Version: &amp;gt;= 0
==&amp;gt; default: Loading metadata for box 'ferventcoder/win2012r2-x64-nocm'
default: URL: https://vagrantcloud.com/ferventcoder/win2012r2-x64-nocm
==&amp;gt; default: Adding box 'ferventcoder/win2012r2-x64-nocm' (v1.0.0) for provider: virtualbox
default: Downloading: https://vagrantcloud.com/ferventcoder/boxes/win2012r2-x64-nocm/versions/1.0.0/providers/virtualbox.box
default: Progress: 1% (Rate: 2764k/s, Estimated time remaining: 0:30:03)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which correctly worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; The difference in the download URL's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://atlas.hashicorp.com/ferventcoder/win2012r2-x64-nocm"&gt;https://atlas.hashicorp.com/ferventcoder/win2012r2-x64-nocm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;compared to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vagrantcloud.com/ferventcoder/win2012r2-x64-nocm"&gt;https://vagrantcloud.com/ferventcoder/win2012r2-x64-nocm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-solution"&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a bit of digging, it turns out that the Chocolatey Community Member was following the
instructions in the README.md of the linked repository, which suggests using 1.8.1 of vagrant,
where as I was using version 2.0.1.  My guess was that there was &amp;quot;something&amp;quot; in the earlier
version of the vagrant client which no longer worked, i.e. a URL redirect was no longer in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out that this &amp;quot;guess&amp;quot; was pretty much spot on.  Rob Reynolds was able to confirm this by
pointing out this Google Groups post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!msg/vagrant-up/H8C68UTkosU/qz4YUmAgBAAJ"&gt;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!msg/vagrant-up/H8C68UTkosU/qz4YUmAgBAAJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So bascially, if you are wanting to run an earlier version of the Vagrant client, you are going
to need to set the following environment variable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-sh"&gt;# macOS and Linux
export VAGRANT_SERVER_URL=&amp;quot;https://vagrantcloud.com&amp;quot;

# Windows (CMD)
set VAGRANT_SERVER_URL=&amp;quot;https://vagrantcloud.com&amp;quot;

# Windows (Powershell)
$env:VAGRANT_SERVER_URL=&amp;quot;https://vagrantcloud.com&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, upgrade to a newer version of Vagrant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-outcome"&gt;The Outcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to update the Chocolatey Test Environment repository to include some of this
information, so that other people don't also run into this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;During a &lt;a href="https://gitter.im/chocolatey/choco?at=5b59cf471be9bb57bcc5a6e4"&gt;Gitter discussion&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, an interesting
point of discussion came up, so I thought I would capture it here in a blog post.  The short version is that you
probably want to make sure that you are using the latest version of Vagrant when trying to use the Chocolatey Test
Environment, although bear in mind that this might not have been tested by anyone, and may have other problems :-).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/are-you-coming-to-chocolateyfest" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/are-you-coming-to-chocolateyfest</id>
		<title>Are you coming to Chocolatey Fest?</title>
		<updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;When I joined Chocolatey, I knew I was going to be in for an exciting ride, and so far, I have not been disappointed.  To date, I have been able to work on some exciting new features that are due out later this year, and I attended the PowerShell Summit, and interacted directly with people using Chocolatey.  Looking forward, the thing I am most looking forward to in 2018 is &lt;a href="https://chocolateyfest.com/"&gt;Chocolatey Fest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-chocolatey-fest"&gt;What is Chocolatey Fest?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chocolatey Fest is the first ever independent conference in North America focused exclusively on Windows Automation (WinOps).  It is a one day event, which is going to be hosted at the Park Central Hotel in San Francisco, on the 8th October 2018.  I am planning on travelling to attend this event, and I very much looking forward to hearing about how people are using Chocolatey personally and in their Organisations, as well as the larger picture about Windows Automation.  I have a feeling that this is going to be a great event, and I would encourage you if you are in the area, to come along and join in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in attending, you can find the registration page &lt;a href="https://chocolateyfest.com/register"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Will yours be the Golden Ticket?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="will-willy-wonka-make-an-appearance"&gt;Will Willy Wonka make an appearance?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You never know who you might see at the event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Dd67CnHU0AAm11-.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Rob Reynolds dressed as Willy Wonka for Halloween" title="Rob Reynolds dressed as Willy Wonka for Halloween" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="announcement-blog-post"&gt;Announcement Blog Post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about the event, check out the official announcement blog post of &lt;a href="https://chocolatey.org/blog/chocolatey-fest-conference-coming-october-8"&gt;chocolatey.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;When I joined Chocolatey, I knew I was going to be in for an exciting ride, and so far, I have not been disappointed.  To date, I have been able to work on some exciting new features that are due out later this year, and I attended the PowerShell Summit, and interacted directly with people using Chocolatey.  Looking forward, the thing I am most looking forward to in 2018 is &lt;a href="https://chocolateyfest.com/"&gt;Chocolatey Fest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/how-to-get-console-output-from-wpf-application" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/how-to-get-console-output-from-wpf-application</id>
		<title>How to get console output from a WPF application</title>
		<updated>2018-07-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;While implementing a recent feature addition to &lt;a href="https://github.com/chocolatey/ChocolateyGUI/pull/613"&gt;Chocolatey GUI&lt;/a&gt;, I stumbled across something that I thought was blog worthy, so I thought I would add some notes here for future me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-problem"&gt;The problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chocolatey GUI is a WPF application, but the feature that was being added here was the ability to execute Chocolatey GUI from the command line in order to enable/disable features within the application.  i.e. you will be able to run commands like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-powershell"&gt;chocolateygui feature enable -n=&amp;lt;featureName&amp;gt;
chocolateygui feature disable -n=&amp;lt;featureName&amp;gt;
chocolateygui feature list
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started writing this feature, I thought that this was going to be simple.  What I didn't know is that when compiled with an &lt;code&gt;OutputType&lt;/code&gt; of &lt;code&gt;WinExe&lt;/code&gt;, which a WPF application is, it doesn't output anything to the console.  As a result, trying to do something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;Console.Write(&amp;quot;This is a test&amp;quot;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;results in nothing happening.  There are also no errors at runtime, so it is not immediately clear what is going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-solution"&gt;The solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, after searching around, it was clear that I wasn't the first person to stumble into this.  There are a number of different solutions out there (including attempting to attach to the existing console, creating a new console, etc.), however, none of them felt quite right until I found this article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.rsuter.com/write-application-can-act-console-application-wpf-gui-application/"&gt;https://blog.rsuter.com/write-application-can-act-console-application-wpf-gui-application/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to Rico Suter for this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The magic sauce that makes this work is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;    [DllImport(&amp;quot;kernel32.dll&amp;quot;, SetLastError = true, ExactSpelling = true)]
    static extern bool FreeConsole();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pinvoke call is completely opposite to how I was originally thinking about it.  Rather than attempting to attach to an existing console, or create a new one, this technique starts out assuming that there is a console, and if that console isn't required, get rid of it.  i.e. &lt;code&gt;FreeConsole&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for this to work, it is necessary to change the output type of you WPF project to be a Console Application, and also add an &lt;code&gt;InitialzeComponent()&lt;/code&gt; call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Chocolatey GUI, the startup code then looks like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;        public App()
        {
            InitializeComponent();
        }

        internal static SplashScreen SplashScreen { get; set; }

        [STAThread]
        public static void Main(string[] args)
        {
            if (args.Length != 0)
            {
                // Run as Console Application
                ParseArgumentsAndRunCommand(args);
            }
            else
            {
                // Run as WPF Application
                FreeConsole();

                // Do Stuff
            }
        }

        [DllImport(&amp;quot;kernel32.dll&amp;quot;, SetLastError = true, ExactSpelling = true)]
        private static extern bool FreeConsole();

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the &lt;a href="https://github.com/chocolatey/ChocolateyGUI/pull/613"&gt;Pull Request&lt;/a&gt; to Chocolatey GUI for the complete implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;While implementing a recent feature addition to &lt;a href="https://github.com/chocolatey/ChocolateyGUI/pull/613"&gt;Chocolatey GUI&lt;/a&gt;, I stumbled across something that I thought was blog worthy, so I thought I would add some notes here for future me.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/introducing-cake.eazfuscator.net-addin" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/introducing-cake.eazfuscator.net-addin</id>
		<title>Introducing the Cake.Eazfuscator.Net Addin</title>
		<updated>2018-06-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;h1 id="what-is-it"&gt;What is it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.Eazfuscator.Net"&gt;Cake.Eazfuscator.Net&lt;/a&gt; is a Cake Addin which provides the ability to execute the &lt;a href="https://www.gapotchenko.com/eazfuscator.net"&gt;Eazfuscator.Net.exe&lt;/a&gt;.  This is a tool that allows you to securely obfuscate your generated code, so that you can protect your investment in your code base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="usage"&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get started using this addin, all you need to do is add the following to your Cake script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;#addin &amp;quot;nuget:https://www.nuget.org/api/v2?package=Cake.Eazfuscator.Net&amp;amp;version=0.1.0&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Depending on the currently released version, you might want to change the above to reflect the current version number. The above is shown to ensure that the best practice of pinning your Cake Addin version numbers is adhered to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that done, you can perform a basic obfuscation of your code base using the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-csharp"&gt;var CERT_PATH = EnvironmentVariable(&amp;quot;PATH_TO_CERTIFICATE&amp;quot;) ?? &amp;quot;&amp;quot;;

Task(&amp;quot;ObfuscateExecutable&amp;quot;)
    .WithCriteria(() =&amp;gt; {
        return !string.IsNullOrWhiteSpace(CERT_PATH) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; FileExists(CERT_PATH);
    })
    .Does(() =&amp;gt;
    {
        var filesToObfuscate = new List&amp;lt;FilePath&amp;gt;();
        filesToObfuscate.Add(&amp;quot;YourExecutable.exe&amp;quot;);

        var settings = new EazfuscatorNetSettings();
        settings.KeyFile = CERT_PATH;

        EazfuscatorNet(filesToObfuscate, settings);
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will result in the selected file(s) being obfuscated, using the settings defined (most likely) in the AssemblyInfo.cs file for the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various settings available which can additionally control how the obfuscation is performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find additional documentation for this addin here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cake-contrib.github.io/Cake.Eazfuscator.Net/"&gt;https://cake-contrib.github.io/Cake.Eazfuscator.Net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="source-code"&gt;Source Code&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code for this addin can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.Eazfuscator.Net"&gt;https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.Eazfuscator.Net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="chat-room"&gt;Chat Room&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this addin, then please feel to drop into the Gitter Chat room for all the addins and modules which exist in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib"&gt;cake-contrib organisation&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://gitter.im/cake-contrib/Lobby?utm_source=badge&amp;amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pr-badge&amp;amp;utm_content=badge"&gt;&lt;img src="https://badges.gitter.im/cake-contrib/Lobby.svg" class="img-fluid" alt="Join the chat at https://gitter.im/cake-contrib/Lobby" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cake-contrib/Cake.Eazfuscator.Net"&gt;Cake.Eazfuscator.Net&lt;/a&gt; is a Cake Addin which provides the ability to execute the &lt;a href="https://www.gapotchenko.com/eazfuscator.net"&gt;Eazfuscator.Net.exe&lt;/a&gt;.  This is a tool that allows you to securely obfuscate your generated code, so that you can protect your investment in your code base.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/chocolatey-gui-v0.16.0-released" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/chocolatey-gui-v0.16.0-released</id>
		<title>Chocolatey GUI v0.16.0 released</title>
		<updated>2018-02-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;h3 id="get-it-while-its-hot"&gt;Get it while it's hot!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the latest release of Chocolatey GUI, version 0.16.0, in the useful &lt;a href="https://chocolatey.org/packages/ChocolateyGUI"&gt;place&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you already have it installed, then simply do &lt;code&gt;choco upgrade chocolateygui&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="so-whats-new"&gt;So what's new?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest addition to this release of Chocolatey GUI is the tile view.  You can now view packages in a tile format, which shows the icon of the underlying application, if there is one.  You can see an example of this here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/02/15/chocolatey_gui_tile_view.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Chocolatey GUI Tile View" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been a much sought after feature, so we are very happy to have this finally land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other biggest feature in this release in the increased amount of languages that are supported by Chocolatey GUI.  The supported languages now include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Russian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;French&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Norwegian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portuguese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dutch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;German&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swedish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Japanese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spanish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge thank you has to go out to everyone who has joined the &lt;a href="https://www.transifex.com/chocolatey/chocolatey-gui/dashboard/"&gt;Transifex&lt;/a&gt; team to make this happen.  If you are interested in helping out in translating Chocolatey GUI into another language, then please reach out, and we can get that included in the next release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="release-notes"&gt;Release Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in seeing the complete set of release notes for v0.16.0, then you can check them out &lt;a href="https://github.com/chocolatey/ChocolateyGUI/releases/tag/0.16.0"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;You can find the latest release of Chocolatey GUI, version 0.16.0, in the useful &lt;a href="https://chocolatey.org/packages/ChocolateyGUI"&gt;place&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/and-so-the-adventure-begins" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/and-so-the-adventure-begins</id>
		<title>And so the adventure begins...</title>
		<updated>2018-01-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/01/28/and-so-the-adventure-begins.png" class="img-fluid" alt="And so the adventure begins..." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="https://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/2017-a-retrospective"&gt;2017 retrospective blog post&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned that there was going to be some amazing news at the end of January.  Well, now it is time to announce that news...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="i-am-joining-chocolatey-software-inc"&gt;I am joining Chocolatey Software, Inc.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/01/28/logo_long.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Chocolatey" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's right!  I am joining &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ferventcoder"&gt;Rob Reynolds&lt;/a&gt; and the rest of the &lt;a href="https://chocolatey.org/"&gt;Chocolatey&lt;/a&gt; team, delivering the best package manager for Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most of you reading this blog will know, I have been a long time contributor to the Chocolatey project.  In actual fact, my first foray into the world of Open Source Software was a &lt;a href="https://github.com/chocolatey/chocolatey/pull/238"&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; into the original Chocolatey GitHub repository.  Since that pull request, I have worked on various parts of the Chocolatey Project including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Answering questions on GitHub, Stack Overflow and Gitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Becoming a moderator of packages which are pushed to chocolatey.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking about Chocolatey at local User Group events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping triage and fixing issues with the core Chocolatey project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintaining and contributing to the Chocolatey GUI project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributing to the package validator and verifier projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In August 2015 I was invited to join the Chocolatey Organisation on GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the time that I have been contributing, I have watched with pride as Chocolatey has grown in popularity, and also how it has expanded into the commercial side of things, by offering licensed versions that contain additional features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was around the middle of 2017 that I was approached to join this Chocolately adventure, and after some discussion with family and friends, I decided that it really was too good an offer to pass up.  I am very excited about getting started contributing to Chocolatey in this new role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about my new role, or Chocolatey in general, then please feel to reach out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/01/28/and-so-the-adventure-begins.png" class="img-fluid" alt="And so the adventure begins..."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/2018-speaking-tour" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/2018-speaking-tour</id>
		<title>2018 Speaking Tour</title>
		<updated>2018-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;h2 id="going-on-the-road"&gt;Going on the road&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in January, and I am going to be doing something that I have never done before...  Visting a number of User Groups around the world doing talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have done the odd talk here and there over the years, but this tour will see me hitting 6 different venues in just under 2 weeks.  As you might well imagine, I am really looking forward to this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are the list of places that you can find me, along with some stickers to give away!  (Who doesn't like stickers!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="kc.net-user-group"&gt;KC .NET User Group&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While visting the States for a week, I am going to be attending the Kansas City .NET User Group on the 30th January 2018 to do a presentation on &lt;a href="https://cakebuild.net/"&gt;Cake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The registration website is here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/KC-NET-User-Group/events/245865487/"&gt;https://www.meetup.com/KC-NET-User-Group/events/245865487/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Rob and Duane for helping to set this up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="net-oxford"&gt;.NET Oxford&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first of a series of visits to .NET User Groups in England.  On the 6th February I will be visiting .NET Oxford to do a presentation on &lt;a href="https://cakebuild.net/"&gt;Cake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The registration website is here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/dotnetoxford/events/245316949/"&gt;https://www.meetup.com/dotnetoxford/events/245316949/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Dan for helping to set this up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="london.net-user-group"&gt;London .NET User Group&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second stop in this series of events sees me visiting the London .NET User Group on the 7th February 2018, again, to present a talk on &lt;a href="https://cakebuild.net"&gt;Cake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The registration website is here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/London-NET-User-Group/events/245941127/"&gt;https://www.meetup.com/London-NET-User-Group/events/245941127/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Dylan for helping to set this up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="dotnetsheff"&gt;dotnetsheff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next stop in the series has me visiting Sheffield on the 8th February 2018, to do another talk on &lt;a href="https://cakebuild.net"&gt;Cake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The registration website is here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/dotnetsheff/events/244481731/"&gt;https://www.meetup.com/dotnetsheff/events/244481731/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Kevin for helping to set this up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="dotnetyork"&gt;dotnetYork&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last in the series of User Group visits has me in York on the 9th February 2018, with a final talk on &lt;a href="https://cakebuild.net"&gt;Cake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The registration website is here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/dotnetYork/events/244481648/"&gt;https://www.meetup.com/dotnetYork/events/244481648/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Kevin for helping to set this up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ddd-scotland"&gt;DDD Scotland&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final stop on this tour before heading home is to present a talk at DDD Scotland.  I submitted a few sessions to this event, and the one that was voted in by the Community was my talk entitled &amp;quot;Adding a layer of Chocolate(y)&amp;quot;, which is a talk all about &lt;a href="https://chocolatey.org/"&gt;Chocolatey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the event can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ddd.scot/Home"&gt;https://ddd.scot/Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to Christos, Carole and Andrew for organising this event, and thanks again to everyone who voted for it!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Starting in January, and I am going to be doing something that I have never done before...  Visting a number of User Groups around the world doing talks.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/2017-a-retrospective" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/2017-a-retrospective</id>
		<title>2017 - A Retrospective</title>
		<updated>2018-01-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;h2 id="looking-back-on-2017"&gt;Looking back on 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many ways, 2017 has been an amazing year, with lots of stuff happening both from a personal stand point, as well as other stuff.  It has also been a very sad year with the passing of both my Granny and my cousin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As per the &lt;a href="https://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/2016-a-retrospective"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; that I did last year, this post is a brief recap, in no particular order, of some of the highlights of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="baby-park-2"&gt;Baby Park #2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 17th February, we welcomed our second child, &lt;a href="https://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/amelia-mabel-park"&gt;Amelia Mabel Park&lt;/a&gt; into the world.  To say that the last 10 months have just flown by would be an understatement.  My wife and I have had so much fun watching Amelia grow and form her own little personality.  Alivia has taken to being a big sister very well, and she loves her little sister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/01/10/alivia-and-amelia.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Alivia and Amelia" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="microsoft-mvp"&gt;Microsoft MVP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July, I was awarded the &lt;a href="https://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/i-am-a-microsoft-mvp"&gt;Microsoft MVP Award&lt;/a&gt;.  Although I knew I had been nominated for this award, it still came as a very nice surprise to actually be awarded.  Unfortunately, I am not able to make it to the MVP Summit in 2018. I'm obviously hoping to be renewed again next year so that I can make it along to the Summit, as I have heard that it is a very good experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="github-contributions"&gt;GitHub Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following on from 2016's increased level of contributions to GitHub, I sort of got onto a little bit of a run in 2017, and once I got started, I didn't want to stop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/01/10/GitHub-Contributions-2017.png" class="img-fluid" alt="GitHub Contributions for 2017" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple months into the streak, I started wondering whether it would be possible to keep up the contributions for the entire year, and the rest as they say is history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eagle eyed amongst you might notice that there is a blip on the 2nd March.  To be honest, I am not sure what happened here, as I did have a contribution on this day.  Shrug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/01/10/GitHub-Contribution-Blip.png" class="img-fluid" alt="GitHub Contribution Blip" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="podcasts"&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, I was invited to appear on two podcasts.  The first was my second appearance on the &lt;a href="https://cynicaldeveloper.com/podcast/36/"&gt;Cynical Developer podcast&lt;/a&gt; where I got to talk about all things &lt;a href="https://chocolatey.org/"&gt;Chocolatey&lt;/a&gt;.  And the second was an appearance on the &lt;a href="http://www.gonemobile.io/58"&gt;Gone Mobile&lt;/a&gt; podcast, where myself and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/devlead"&gt;Mattias&lt;/a&gt; talked about all things Cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="talks"&gt;Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the arrival of Amelia in the first part of the year, my ability to attend conferences this year wasn't the same as last year.  As a result, I was only able to submit and speak at 2 conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first was at &lt;a href="http://developerdeveloperdeveloper.com"&gt;DDD Reading&lt;/a&gt; where I did a talk entitled &amp;quot;Control your GitHub releases with GitVersion and GitReleaseManager&amp;quot;, where I talked about two tools that I use on almost all the Open Source Projects that I work on.  I also presented the same talk at &lt;a href="https://www.dddeastanglia.com"&gt;DDD East Anglia&lt;/a&gt;.  If you are interested in checking out this talk you can find a recording of it on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/SlM02V1tkSc"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I plan on doing a lot more talks. In fact, I already have 6 speaking engagements lined up.  I will have a follow-up blog post with links to where I will be speaking in case you are able to make it along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hacktoberfest"&gt;Hacktoberfest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what is now turning into a yearly tradition, I once again took part in &lt;a href="https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/"&gt;Hacktoberfest&lt;/a&gt;.  If you haven't heard about this event, I strongly encourage you to check it out.  All it takes is 4 pull requests in the month of October. It is a great bit of fun and at the end of it, you get some quality swag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is the swag I mentioned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/01/11/hacktoberfest-2017-swag.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Hacktoberfest 2017 Swag" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pull-requests"&gt;24 Pull Requests&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there is no swag involved in this contest, it is still great fun, and once again I encourage everyone to take part in &lt;a href="https://24pullrequests.com/"&gt;24 Pull Requests&lt;/a&gt;.  It is a great way to get involved in Open Source, and give back something to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year was slightly different from last year because &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/teabass"&gt;Andrew&lt;/a&gt; invited me to join the 24 Pull Requests GitHub Organisation.  This was mainly due to me hanging out in the Gitter Chat Room and helping out where I could when questions were being asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="stack-overflow-contributions"&gt;Stack Overflow Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, I made a committed effort to answer more questions on Stack Overflow, focusing on questions surrounding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chocolatey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitFlow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All topics which are important to me, and which I think I am capable of answering questions on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Reputation on Stack Overflow increased to 4797 (an increase on 2074):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/01/10/Reputation%20-%202018-01-03_14-24-06.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Stack Overflow Reputation" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also increased the number of badges which I have earned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/01/10/Badges%20-%202018-01-03_14-24-56.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Stack Overflow Badges" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Including the &lt;code&gt;Fanatic&lt;/code&gt; badge (which meant visiting the site on 100 consecutive days), which sort of went hand in hand with my GitHub Contribution streak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And according to the site, I have reached 87 thousand people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/01/10/Impact%20-%202018-01-03_14-25-28.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Stack Overflow Impact" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="youtube-videos"&gt;YouTube Videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017 I ventured into an area which I had never been before, namely creating and publishing videos to YouTube.  This really came about after watching the work that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GeoffreyHuntley"&gt;Geoffrey Huntley&lt;/a&gt; was doing, and I wanted to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find my YouTube Channel &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/GaryEwanPark"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I have created some videos on AppVeyor and Cake (mainly around releases of the VSCode Extension for Cake), but I am planning on expanding to include some more topics this year.  So be sure to subscribe to my channel to catch the new videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="winops-conf-2017-and-powershell-dev-day"&gt;WinOps Conf 2017 and PowerShell Dev Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my third year in a row attending the WinOps Conf, and I am happy to say that it didn't disappoint.  Once again it was a great event, thank you to all the organisers and helpers for making it a great day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year was a slightly different experience, since I was helping out at the other side of the fence.  I was there representing Chocolatey, who were both a sponsor of the event, as well as doing a Full Day Workshop and Presentation.  This was the first time that I was able to meet &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ferventcoder"&gt;Rob&lt;/a&gt; in person!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had loads of great conversations across the two days, and it was great to see the excitement that people have for Chocolatey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was me chatting with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/stevenmurawski"&gt;Steve Murawski&lt;/a&gt; at the Chocolatey booth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2018/01/11/winops-steve-murawski.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Chatting with Steve Murawski" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While in London, I was also able to attend the &lt;a href="https://psday.uk/"&gt;PowerShell Dev Day&lt;/a&gt;, which was also a great event.  I would encourage anyone to go to this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tretton37-knowabunga"&gt;tretton37 Knowabunga&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was quite simply an AMAZING event!  For those of you that haven't heard of this before, you can find some information &lt;a href="http://thecodejunkie.com/2014/02/12/creating-value-by-sharing-knowledge/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://tretton37.com/blog/knowabunga-day-june"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the story goes like this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the blue, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thecodejunkie"&gt;Andreas&lt;/a&gt; asked me if I wanted an all expenses paid trip to Sweden, to spend the day representing Cake at their all day Open Source event.  Obviously, I said that I would love to go, so off I went!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The format of the day was that there were a number of people from the Open Source Community there representing their projects, and different members of the tretton37 team were assigned to each project.  With that part done, we then set about hacking on the project.  This included a brief overview of what the project is, and then jumping in to work on some issues that were currently open.  In the end, I think we had 9 Pull Requests submitted, across a number of the Cake Repositories.  Also included in the day was a panel discussion about Open Source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say that I had an amazing day in Sweden (my first time visiting), and I was, and still am, amazed at the &lt;a href="https://tretton37.com/"&gt;tretton37&lt;/a&gt; Organisation for their commitment to Open Source and its Community.  Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="aberdeen-developers"&gt;Aberdeen Developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With one thing or another, I haven't been as active at Aberdeen Developers as I would have liked, but I am very happy to say that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nyami"&gt;Douglas&lt;/a&gt; has been keeping things ticking over nicely.  Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017 saw events from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/march-2017-mark-allan/"&gt;Mark Allen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/march-2017-microsoft-special/"&gt;Martin Kearn and Martin Beeby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/june-2017-donovan-brown-zero-to-devops/"&gt;Donovan Brown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/jun-2017-richard-campbell-history-of-net/"&gt;Richard Campbell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow!  An amazing list of speakers.  Aberdeen is very lucky to have these people come and speak.  I am looking forward to getting more involved in Aberdeen Developers in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="chocolatey-contributions"&gt;Chocolatey Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the year, I have been working on a number of things related to Chocolatey, but there are two things that stand out for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first is the release of Chocolatey GUI 0.15.0.  There is more information about this release &lt;a href="https://chocolatey.org/blog/chocolatey-gui-0.15.0-released"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Put simply, this was a HUGE release, and saw essentially a complete re-write of major parts of the application.  There are loads more things planned for Chocolatey GUI (including a much awaited Tile View), so be sure to keep an eye out for that in the next release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second is with regard to &lt;a href="https://github.com/dtgm/chocolatey-packages"&gt;dtgm's Chocolatey Packages&lt;/a&gt;.  For those of you that don't know, dtgm has LOADS of Chocolatey packages, almost all of which are automated using ketarin.  However, dtgm hasn't been able to spend as much time maintaining these packages as he once did, and as a result, these packages have started to fail.  After a number of attempts to reach out to him, I was finally able to get access to his GitHub repository, and as a result, I have been able to start merging some of the long awaited PR's to fix some packages, and as well as to migrate some of his packages to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/chocolatey/chocolatey-coreteampackages"&gt;Core Team Packages repository&lt;/a&gt;.  Now that I have access to this repository, I am hoping to be able to fix more of the packages that require attention, as well as migrate more of his packages to the Core Team packages repository.  If you are interested in helping with this work, please feel free to reach out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cake-contributions"&gt;Cake Contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been loads of exciting announcements for Cake in 2017, not least &lt;a href="https://cakebuild.net/blog/2017/11/intellisense-vscode"&gt;Intellisense for Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, my main focus this year has been growing the Cake-Contrib Organisation.  For those of you who know me, I am very passionate about the longevity and maintainability of Open Source Projects, and to that end, I am a HUGE advocate of not working in silos.  Instead, I much prefer to see projects being worked on within a GitHub Organisation, so that if the worst should happen or life gets in the way, other people can step in and help out.  That is what the Cake-Contrib Organisation is all about.  A place where Cake maintainers can place their repositories, knowing that they will still have full access to the repository, but also know that others can help out should the need arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related to this, is the cake-contrib user on NuGet.org.  Whenever I see a new Cake Addin being released, one of the first things that I do is submit an issue to the maintainer to add the cake-contrib user as a co-owner of the package.  This is really for two reasons.  The first being that it increases the publicity of that package, as people as able to &lt;a href="https://www.nuget.org/profiles/cake-contrib"&gt;find it easier&lt;/a&gt; as all packages are in one place.  The second is that it means other people can push a new package version, rather than it being locked down to a single user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, we were able to grow the Cake-Contrib Organisation to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;43 People now a member of the Organisation on GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;110 Repositories now in the Organisation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;202 Packages associated with the cake-contrib user on NuGet.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3,397,862 downloads of addins and modules associated with the cake-contrib user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put simply, this is amazing, and I am grateful to all the Cake Contributors who have chosen to join this Organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting side effect of this work is the synchronisation of permissions and settings that needs to happen between GitHub and AppVeyor (our main CI platform).  For the longest time, I was doing this manually, but it got to the point that this was completely unmanageable.  As a result, I now have a set of scripts that helps with the synchronisation of permissions and settings between GitHub and AppVeyor.  This will likely be the topic of a YouTube video this year, so keep an eye out for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is still work to be done here, and I will continue to reach out to the maintainers of addins and modules to see if they are interested in joining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="office-hours"&gt;Office Hours&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, after watching the work that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GeoffreyHuntley"&gt;Geoffrey Huntley&lt;/a&gt; has been doing, I signed up for &lt;a href="https://officehours.io/people/gep13"&gt;Officehours&lt;/a&gt;.  Put simply, I think this is a great idea, and a great service.  If you have anything you wanted to talk to me about, whether about Cake, or Chocolatey, Build System, or Open Source in general, feel free to reach out and we can get something scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="thats-a-wrap"&gt;That's a wrap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that as they say, is that!  Looking back, it has been a very busy, but very enjoyable year (aside for the sad times).  2018 is shaping up to be as busy, and I am truly excited to share some amazing news that will be happening at the end of January.  It is amazing!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;In many ways, 2017 has been an amazing year, with lots of stuff happening both from a personal stand point, as well as other stuff.  It has also been a very sad year with the passing of both my Granny and my cousin.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/introducting-a-postman-collection-for-appveyor" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/introducting-a-postman-collection-for-appveyor</id>
		<title>Introducing a Postman Collection for AppVeyor</title>
		<updated>2017-08-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;For a while now, I have been hacking on the AppVeyor API.  This has been in order to setup some automation between the various GitHub Teams that I have, and the AppVeyor Roles that allow access to the projects in AppVeyor.  This can of course be done manually, but when you start having over 30 teams, and over 70 projects, this becomes a bit of a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While doing this, I found myself continually referring to the &lt;a href="https://www.appveyor.com/docs/api/"&gt;AppVeyor Documentation&lt;/a&gt; which is actually very good, and then doing little tests here and there using &lt;a href="https://www.getpostman.com/"&gt;Postman&lt;/a&gt; to verify things that I was trying to automate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It got to the point where I had created the same request a couple of times on different days, so it was time to do something else, as this was wasted effort!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, without further ado, let me introduce a &lt;a href="https://github.com/gep13/appveyor-postman"&gt;Postman Collection&lt;/a&gt; for all the requests that you can make against the AppVeyor API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A video explaining what this is, and how you can use it, can be seen here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="853" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U8mVjJxt_ts" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going forward, I intend to keep this collection up to date with any new API requests that are added to AppVeyor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please let me know if you have any comments or suggestions on how this can be improved.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;For a while now, I have been hacking on the AppVeyor API.  This has been in order to setup some automation between the various GitHub Teams that I have, and the AppVeyor Roles that allow access to the projects in AppVeyor.  This can of course be done manually, but when you start having over 30 teams, and over 70 projects, this becomes a bit of a problem.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/mvp-award-kit" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/mvp-award-kit</id>
		<title>MVP Award Kit</title>
		<updated>2017-07-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;At the end of last week, I received my MVP Award Kit from Microsoft, but I am really only just now getting a chance to sit down and have a proper look at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see photos of the unboxing below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="flickrembed"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;small style="display: block; text-align: center; margin: 0 auto;"&gt;Powered by &lt;a href="https://flickrembed.com"&gt;flickr embed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;script src="https://flickrembed.com/embed_v2.js.php?source=flickr&amp;layout=responsive&amp;input=72157684028641824&amp;sort=0&amp;by=album&amp;theme=default&amp;scale=fit&amp;skin=default&amp;id=5850544461b40"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say that I am very impressed with the kit.  It is a very nice gift to receive in addition to the recognition that goes with it.  Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;At the end of last week, I received my MVP Award Kit from Microsoft, but I am really only just now getting a chance to sit down and have a proper look at it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/how-to-use-appveyor-cache" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/how-to-use-appveyor-cache</id>
		<title>How to use AppVeyor Build Cache</title>
		<updated>2017-07-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;Another important feature offered by AppVeyor is it's &lt;a href="https://www.appveyor.com/docs/build-cache/"&gt;Build Cache&lt;/a&gt;.  Due to the fact that every AppVeyor build uses a fresh copy of the Build Agent Virtual Machine, any files and folders that were created as part of the build are not persisted between project builds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for example, if as part of your build you restore lots of NuGet packages, or you install packages from Chocolatey, then these things will have to happen on every build.  This is problematic for two reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It means that your builds are going to be slightly slower than they could be as they are having to restore these dependencies on every build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The success of your build is dependent on 3rd party websites being available.  So for example, if NuGet.org isn't working properly, your build is going to fail as those required packages can't be downloaded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making use of the AppVeyor Build Cache fixes both of these problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set up the Build Cache is really simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cache:
  - tools -&amp;gt; build.cake, tools/packages.config
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this entry in your &lt;code&gt;.appveyor.yml&lt;/code&gt; file, at the end of the build all files and folders within the &lt;code&gt;tools&lt;/code&gt; folder will be added to the Build Cache, and restored on the next build.  Additionally, if either of the &lt;code&gt;build.cake&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;tools/packages.config&lt;/code&gt; file change between Project Builds, then the tools folder in the Build Cache will be invalidated and re-created during the build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This configuration gives us full flexibility and control over the Build Cache, which results in a more resilient and re-producible build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have created a short video with walks through this entire process, and shows the Build Cache in action, in the context of a build which uses the &lt;a href="http://cakebuild.net/"&gt;Cake Build Automation tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="853" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ELb8l9nvWok" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Another important feature offered by AppVeyor is it's &lt;a href="https://www.appveyor.com/docs/build-cache/"&gt;Build Cache&lt;/a&gt;.  Due to the fact that every AppVeyor build uses a fresh copy of the Build Agent Virtual Machine, any files and folders that were created as part of the build are not persisted between project builds.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/how-to-use-appveyor-remote-desktop-connection" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/how-to-use-appveyor-remote-desktop-connection</id>
		<title>How to use AppVeyor Remote Desktop Connection</title>
		<updated>2017-07-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about AppVeyor is that it is a &lt;strong&gt;completely online Continuous Integration Server&lt;/strong&gt;.  You as a user don't have to worry about installing the latest version of it, or applying security patches, etc.  You can simply get on with the task at hand.  However, one of the worst things about AppVeyor is that it is a &lt;strong&gt;completely online Continuous Integration Server&lt;/strong&gt;.  Those times when the build isn't working, and you have no idea why, it can be difficult to figure it out solely based on the output logs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is where AppVeyor's unique ability to get a Remote Desktop Connection to the Build Agent is incredibly powerful!  You get complete administrator access to the VM for 60 minutes (either at the start of the build, or at the end of it), which gives to time to debug and figure out exactly what is going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this is explained in the AppVeyor &lt;a href="https://www.appveyor.com/docs/how-to/rdp-to-build-worker/"&gt;documentation site&lt;/a&gt; but I thought I would create a short video explaining exactly how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="853" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5OHsXduezIw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h1 id="gotcha"&gt;Gotcha&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only gotcha that I ran into while creating this video is that although it isn't mentioned, the password that you create for logging into the server is subject to the standard complexity rules, for example mixed upper and lower case letters, use of numbers and special characters, etc.  If you use a password that doesn't meet with these requirements, you will get a build error similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2017/07/23/appveyor_rdp_password_error.png" class="img-fluid" alt="AppVeyor RDP Password Error" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about AppVeyor is that it is a &lt;strong&gt;completely online Continuous Integration Server&lt;/strong&gt;.  You as a user don't have to worry about installing the latest version of it, or applying security patches, etc.  You can simply get on with the task at hand.  However, one of the worst things about AppVeyor is that it is a &lt;strong&gt;completely online Continuous Integration Server&lt;/strong&gt;.  Those times when the build isn't working, and you have no idea why, it can be difficult to figure it out solely based on the output logs.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
</feed>