<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<link rel="self" href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/" />
	<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
	<title>Gary Ewan Park</title>
	<rights>2016</rights>
	<updated>2016-12-14T22:55:17Z</updated>
	<subtitle>Ramblings and Ponderings of a Microsoft Fan Boy...</subtitle>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/ddd-scotland-call-for-speakers-now-open" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/ddd-scotland-call-for-speakers-now-open</id>
		<title>DDD Scotland 2016 Call For Speakers Is Now Open</title>
		<updated>2016-01-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h1 id="call-for-speakers"&gt;Call For Speakers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Call For Speakers for DDD Scotland is now fully open.  If you have a topic that you would like to speak on, then now is your opportunity to register the talk for consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who are not familiar with the format of DDD events, it goes a little something like this...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential Speakers submit their sessions for consideration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community Voting is then opened, and the Community decides on which talks they want to see&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The speakers with the sessions with the most votes are then contacted, and the sessions are then scheduled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't been to a DDD event before, I thoroughly recommend to give one a try.  They really are great fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want more information about the event you can find information on the &lt;a href="http://ddd.scot"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; or reach out on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dddscot"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/ddd-scotland-call-for-speakers-now-open' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'DDD Scotland 2016 Call For Speakers Is Now Open';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/ddd-scotland-call-for-speakers-now-open' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;The Call For Speakers for DDD Scotland is now fully open.  If you have a topic that you would like to speak on, then now is your opportunity to register the talk for consideration.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/strange-error-when-signing-xap-file-for-windows-phone-8-1-silverlight-application" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/strange-error-when-signing-xap-file-for-windows-phone-8-1-silverlight-application</id>
		<title>Strange Error When Signing XAP File for Windows Phone 8.1. Silverlight Application</title>
		<updated>2016-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h2 id="signtool-error-this-file-format-cannot-be-signed-because-it-is-not-recognized"&gt;SignTool Error: This file format cannot be signed because it is not recognized.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the best part of the last two days, I have been staring at various incarnations of error messages from the SignTool executable, most notably the one above.  What follows are some notes on what I was doing, and why, in the hope that if I run into this again, I will have a chance at remembering what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tldr"&gt;TL/DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are seeing this error, check what version of Silverlight you have installed on your machine.  If you have this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2016/1/29/SilverlightVersionOne.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Silverlight Version 5.1.20513.0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i.e. Silverlight version 5.1.20513.0, then this could very well be causing your issue.  Install the latest version, at the time of writing this was 5.1.41212.0, and try signing the XAP file again.  This worked for me, but I have no idea why.  Huge shout out to &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/4550683/potricos"&gt;potricos&lt;/a&gt; on this &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/28433317/671491"&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt; post where this suggestion was mentioned.  I honestly didn't see how this would ever solve the problem, but I thought I would give it a try, and I am glad I did!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="so-what-was-i-doing"&gt;So, what was I doing?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been working on a Windows Phone 8.1 Silverlight application, and development and deployment had been working without any problems whatsoever.  As these things have a tendency to do, the development work stopped on the project, waiting for testing with the client.  Some time passed, and eventually the application was tested, and as a result of that testing, some minor issues were identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I cracked open Visual Studio, made the necessary changes, checked in the code, updated the release notes, tagged the repository. generated the XAP file, and handed this over for testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job done I hear you say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, no!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we tried to deploy the XAP file onto the Windows Phone (using an Enterprise Certificate) it simply wouldn't install.  There were no errors, no exceptions, no dialogues, no nothing.  When we went back and re-installed the old version of the application is worked fine.  So this told me that the Enterprise Certificate was good, and I wasn't running into any issues with certificate expiration.  So what did that leave?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What followed over the next two days were various trial/error approaches to get to the root cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Found another machine from colleague where the generation of the XAP file did result in a successful deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a Virtual Machine to try to mimic the functionality on the colleague machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking apart the build process trying to isolate what could be causing problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extracting the XAP files and doing comparisons between the working and non working versions to try to identify differences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots and lots of googling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots and lots of head scratching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, after digging around in various log files, we stumbled across this error message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-sh"&gt;Done Adding Additional Store
Number of files successfully Signed: 0
Number of warnings: 0
Number of errors: 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which was found when the build script was executing the MDILXAPCompile step that is described &lt;a href="http://gep13.me/20xBO6z"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After extracting the actual command that was being run by the tool at this point in time, and directly running it, we got some more information returned which wasn't captured in the log:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2016/1/29/SignToolOutput.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Verbose Output from SignTool"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once this was discovered, and some more hunting around, we were led to this &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/28433317/671491"&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt; post, which was initially disregarded as not being relevant.  However, on checking, the laptop on which the build/deployment was working had a later version of Silverlight compared to the machines that it wasn't working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After installing the latest version, which took the Silverlight version to 5.1.41212.0:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2016/1/29/SilverlightVersionTwo.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Silverlight Version 5.1.41212.0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The build/deployment then proceeded to work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still am no wiser on "why" this is now working, but I am happy that it is.  I could understand there being a difference if I had updated the Silverlight SDK, but seeing a difference after installing the Silverlight Runtime, doesn't really make any sense to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone can shed any light on what is going on here, I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/strange-error-when-signing-xap-file-for-windows-phone-8-1-silverlight-application' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Strange Error When Signing XAP File for Windows Phone 8.1. Silverlight Application';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/strange-error-when-signing-xap-file-for-windows-phone-8-1-silverlight-application' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;For the best part of the last two days, I have been staring at various incarnations of error messages from the SignTool executable, most notably the one above.  What follows are some notes on what I was doing, and why, in the hope that if I run into this again, I will have a chance at remembering what to do.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-from-talk-at-scotsoft2015" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-from-talk-at-scotsoft2015</id>
		<title>Slides from Talk at ScotSoft2015</title>
		<updated>2015-09-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h2 id="semantic-versioning-with-gitversion"&gt;Semantic Versioning with GitVersion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday 17th September 2015, I presented a talk entitled "Semantic Versioning with GitVersion" at the first Developer Forum as part of the &lt;a href="http://www.scotlandis.com/scotsoft2015/"&gt;ScotlandIS ScotSoft2015&lt;/a&gt; event.  The abstract for the talk was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever needed to control the version number of your application?  If so, you will know that this isn't something that you "get for free".  It's hard!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have tried to use some form of auto incrementing number from your Continuous Integration Server, or store a text file in source control and update it each time the build happens.  Both of these approaches will work, but they don't account for more complicated scenarios where you are working on multiple releases at the same time, or you want to use multiple Continuous Integration Servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session, we will look at how we can improve the versioning of your application using a combination of branching strategies (either Gitflow or Githubflow) and an open source tool called GitVersion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitVersion is a tool which allows you to easy generate the Semantic Version number for your application, based on the current state of your code base in it's Git Repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thoroughly enjoyed doing this presentation, and there were quite a few questions after the talk was finished, so I feel that people were able to get something from it.  If there are any follow-up questions, then please feel free to get in touch, and I will do my best to respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="slides"&gt;Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in seeing the slide from the talk, you can find them displayed below, or you can find the full version on SlideShare &lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/gep13/semantic-versioning-with-gitversion"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/HzZm8AmIJpZ0Sf" width="595" height="485" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;" allowfullscreen=""&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style="margin-bottom:5px"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-from-talk-at-scotsoft2015' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Slides from Talk at ScotSoft2015';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-from-talk-at-scotsoft2015' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;On Thursday 17th September 2015, I presented a talk entitled "Semantic Versioning with GitVersion" at the first Developer Forum as part of the &lt;a href="http://www.scotlandis.com/scotsoft2015/"&gt;ScotlandIS ScotSoft2015&lt;/a&gt; event.  The abstract for the talk was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-for-dunddd-2014-is-now-open" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-for-dunddd-2014-is-now-open</id>
		<title>Registration for DunDDD 2014 is now open</title>
		<updated>2014-11-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h1 id="grab-your-ticket-for-dunddd-quickly-so-you-dont-miss-out"&gt;Grab your ticket for DunDDD quickly so you don't miss out!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The call for speakers at the Scottish Community Event (organised by the &lt;a href="http://scottishdevelopers.com/"&gt;Scottish Developers&lt;/a&gt;) known as &lt;a href="http://dun.dddscotland.co.uk/speaker"&gt;DunDDD &lt;/a&gt;has now closed and the registration has opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="dunddd-is-now-in-its-fourth-year"&gt;DunDDD is now in its fourth year&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be the 4th DunDDD, built on the popular foundation of the Developer! Developer! Developer! conference series which has spread to all corners of the UK and the international arena. &amp;nbsp;DDD conferences are community-run days where passionate and enthusiastic people come together to learn, share ideas, and to network within the many hubs of the development community. Best of all DDD events are &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt; to everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year DunDDD will be featuring an entire track dedicated to the &lt;strong&gt;Not Only SQL&lt;/strong&gt; movement and &lt;strong&gt;Big Data&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go and grab your &lt;a href="http://dun.dddscotland.co.uk/registration"&gt;ticket now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-for-dunddd-2014-is-now-open' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Registration for DunDDD 2014 is now open';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-for-dunddd-2014-is-now-open' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;The call for speakers at the Scottish Community Event (organised by the &lt;a href="http://scottishdevelopers.com/"&gt;Scottish Developers&lt;/a&gt;) known as &lt;a href="http://dun.dddscotland.co.uk/speaker"&gt;DunDDD &lt;/a&gt;has now closed and the registration has opened.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/improve-appveyor-build-times-using-build-cache" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/improve-appveyor-build-times-using-build-cache</id>
		<title>Improve AppVeyor build times using build cache</title>
		<updated>2014-10-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h2 id="take-minutes-off-overall-build-time"&gt;Take minutes off overall build time...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By making use of the &lt;a href="http://www.appveyor.com/docs/build-cache"&gt;build cache&lt;/a&gt; within &lt;a href="http://www.appveyor.com/"&gt;AppVeyor&lt;/a&gt;.  For both this blog, and also the &lt;a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/"&gt;Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group&lt;/a&gt; blog, I was able to reduce the overall build time by over 3 minutes.  Find out how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a recent &lt;a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/setup-appveyor-to-deploy-octopress-site-to-github-pages/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, I described how I was able to use AppVeyor to generate and then deploy an Octopress site to GitHub Pages.  The process is very simple to setup, the only slight downside is the time that it takes to generate the site itself, which can take over 7 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the grand scheme of things, this isn't a long time, but if you are pushing a quick change, and want to see whether it worked before moving onto something else, these 7 minutes can seem like an entirity.  Looking at the build log, it was clear that the thing that was taking the longest was this command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-yaml"&gt;  - cmd: bundle install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason that this is required is due to the fact that each time a build on AppVeyor runs, it is using a brand new instance of the &lt;a href="http://www.appveyor.com/docs/installed-software"&gt;Build Worker Image&lt;/a&gt;.  This is both good and bad.  It means that you are always starting from a known point.  However, it also means that anything you installed to get your build to work, is no longer there the next time the build runs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, there are almost 50 rubygems that need to be installed in order for Octopress to work correctly.  This means that these gems have to be downloaded from the internet, installed and verified, and then used in the build process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, AppVeyor has the concept of using a build cache.  This basically means that, once setup, AppVeyor will first extract all the cached files back onto the Build Worker Image, and then start the build proper.  As a result, when I run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-yaml"&gt;  - cmd: bundle install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gems are already installed, and no longer need to be downloaded and installed.  Then, at the end of the build, the folders of interest are then re-cached, ready for extraction when the next build kicks off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; There is a limit of 100MB applied to the build cache.  If you are trying to cache more files than this, you will have to get in contact with AppVeyor support to see if there is anything that can be done to increase this number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="enough-already-show-me-the-configuration"&gt;Enough already, show me the configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting this up is as simple as this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-yaml"&gt;cache:
  - C:\Ruby193\lib\ruby\gems\1.9.1
  - C:\Ruby193\bin
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally started out trying to cache only the &lt;code&gt;gems&lt;/code&gt; folder, however, with the help of Feodor Fitsner over at the &lt;a href="http://help.appveyor.com/discussions/questions/585-what-setup-for-build-cache-is-require-for-bundle-install"&gt;AppVeyor Support&lt;/a&gt; pages it became apparent that I would also need to include the &lt;code&gt;bin&lt;/code&gt; folder, as during the installation of gems a number of them put their bash or CMD scripts into this folder so that they can make the tooling work correctly from the command line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there you have it!  With the build cache configured, I was able to reduce the build time for this blog from &lt;code&gt;5 min 37&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;2 min 28 sec&lt;/code&gt;.  Not a bad effort!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This same approach can be used for other artefacts of a build process, for instance, restoring nuget packages.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/improve-appveyor-build-times-using-build-cache' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Improve AppVeyor build times using build cache';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/improve-appveyor-build-times-using-build-cache' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;By making use of the &lt;a href="http://www.appveyor.com/docs/build-cache"&gt;build cache&lt;/a&gt; within &lt;a href="http://www.appveyor.com/"&gt;AppVeyor&lt;/a&gt;.  For both this blog, and also the &lt;a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/"&gt;Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group&lt;/a&gt; blog, I was able to reduce the overall build time by over 3 minutes.  Find out how.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/chocolatey-kickstarter-is-now-live" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/chocolatey-kickstarter-is-now-live</id>
		<title>Chocolatey Kickstarter is now live</title>
		<updated>2014-10-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h2 id="tldr"&gt;tl;dr&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/ferventcoder/chocolatey-the-alternative-windows-store-like-yum"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and back the brand new Chocolatey Kickstarter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="some-more-information"&gt;Some more information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier today, Rob Reynolds (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ferventcoder"&gt;@ferventcoder&lt;/a&gt;) pushed the button on a new Kickstarter, aimed at raising funds to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% blockquote Rob Reynolds https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/ferventcoder/chocolatey-the-alternative-windows-store-like-yum Chocolatey Kickstarter %}
move forward from the Chocolatey experiment to the Chocolatey experience!
{% endblockquote %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This really is an exciting time for Chocolatey, and general application management on Windows.  You can find all the details that you will need to get started, including information about the rewards that you can back on the Kickstarter page (did I mention that one of them actually including actual chocolate?).  Head on &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/ferventcoder/chocolatey-the-alternative-windows-store-like-yum"&gt;over&lt;/a&gt; to check them out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="chocolatey-kickstarter-release-video"&gt;Chocolatey Kickstarter Release Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the release video which explains some of the aims of the Chocolatey Kickstarter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="video-container"&gt;
    &lt;iframe width="480" height="360" src="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/ferventcoder/chocolatey-the-alternative-windows-store-like-yum/widget/video.html" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="new-chocolatey-features-video"&gt;New Chocolatey Features Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the following video which shows some of the soon to be released new features in the C# rewrite of Chocolatey:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="video-container"&gt;
    &lt;iframe width="480" height="360" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/sm_U53sxt2c" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="get-in-quick"&gt;Get in quick!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, there is almost 40 people already signed up to the Kickstarter, so be sure to get in quick so you don't miss out of the exciting oppurtunity to help Chocolatey grow into &lt;strong&gt;the&lt;/strong&gt; application package manager for Windows.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/chocolatey-kickstarter-is-now-live' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Chocolatey Kickstarter is now live';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/chocolatey-kickstarter-is-now-live' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/ferventcoder/chocolatey-the-alternative-windows-store-like-yum"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and back the brand new Chocolatey Kickstarter!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/our-daughter-is-1-year-old-today" />
		<link rel="enclosure" type="image" href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/images/birthday_collection" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/our-daughter-is-1-year-old-today</id>
		<title>Our Daughter is 1 Year Old Today!</title>
		<updated>2014-09-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h2 id="is-it-really-1-year"&gt;Is it really 1 year?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As amazing as it sounds, our daughter is 1 year old today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was always told that time would start passing quickly as soon as you had your first child, but I honestly didn't expect that it would be this fast!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is Alivia's 1st Birthday!  I can remember being in the hospital holding for the first time as if it were yesterday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much as happened since Alivia came into our lives, but I wouldn't change anything, I love being a dad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learned to walk (well almost)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learned to swim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learned to say "dad"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learned to sign "mum"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learned to clap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learned to sleep through the night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learned to blow raspberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and so much more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to teaching her so many new things in the next year!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/our-daughter-is-1-year-old-today' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Our Daughter is 1 Year Old Today!';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/our-daughter-is-1-year-old-today' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;As amazing as it sounds, our daughter is 1 year old today!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/using-a-basic-gallery-plugin-on-octopress-site" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/using-a-basic-gallery-plugin-on-octopress-site</id>
		<title>Using a basic gallery plugin on Octopress Site</title>
		<updated>2014-09-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h2 id="i-have-a-lot-of-photos-but-where-to-put-them"&gt;I have a lot of photos, but where to put them?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have collected a number of photos from various trips that I have been on, and I share them in various places, i.e. Facebook, Twitter, Flickr, etc.  However, from time to time, I want to include them easily into blog posts as well.  This is something that "should" be easy, but my experience over the last few days is that it isn't as simple as it should be.  This is especially useful when doing a tutorial blog post, and you want to capture a number of screen-shots and show them in order in a gallery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having finally figured out how to get it working, I thought I would list the steps here for anyone else that might be running into the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-do-i-want"&gt;What do I want?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The requirements that I am looking for break down as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once set-up, I should be able to upload one or more images into a gallery folder and they should automatically added to associated blog post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thumbnail images should be automatically generated for photos uploaded into gallery folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when clicked, thumbnail images should open a pop-up with a larger image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;images in the same gallery should allow browsing left and right when an image is in popup window&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;should work in a range of devices, desktop, tablet, phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;should work as part of my AppVeyor build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After hunting around, and trying various different options, I finally settled on using this &lt;a href="https://github.com/yortz/octopress_gallery"&gt;plugin&lt;/a&gt;.  From it's description, it should have been easy to get set up and running, but unfortunately, it took a bit of head scratching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the description for the plugin there is no mention of the dependency on an application called &lt;code&gt;ImageMagick&lt;/code&gt;.  Now, in hindsight, it is clear that this will be required, but when I was reading through the simple steps of setting this up, it never occurred to me.  So first up, let's get &lt;code&gt;ImageMagick&lt;/code&gt; installed.  If you are using &lt;a href="http://chocolatey.org/"&gt;Chocolatey&lt;/a&gt; then this is as simple as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;choco install imagemagick.tool&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that installed, step through the remaining instructions on the plugin page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to those steps, I also decided to add support for &lt;a href="http://fancybox.net/"&gt;Fancybox&lt;/a&gt; to make the experience a little nicer.  This involved the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a slight modification to the &lt;code&gt;gallery_tag.rb&lt;/code&gt; to work with Fancybox.  This basically involved adding a class definition to teh anchor tag, and also changing the rel attribute to be the gallery name, so that Fancybox groups the images in the gallery together.  The final version of the change can be seen &lt;a href="https://github.com/gep13/gep13.github.io/commit/8f597cd922ffc3556481e7148990bcaa675dcceb#diff-dc86fc94e212fa637e5f2689a8379e1fR10"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href="http://fancyapps.com/fancybox/#license"&gt;Fancybox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unblock/extract the zip file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the contents of the source folder to &lt;code&gt;source\fancybox&lt;/code&gt; as I have done &lt;a href="https://github.com/gep13/gep13.github.io/tree/source/source/fancybox"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the following additions to your &lt;code&gt;source\_includes\custom\head.html&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-javascript"&gt;    &amp;lt;script src="ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.7.2/jquery.min.js" type="text/javascript"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;script type="text/javascript"&amp;gt;
    jQuery.noConflict(); // ender.js conflicts with jQuery
    &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="/fancybox/jquery.fancybox.css" /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;script src="/fancybox/jquery.fancybox.pack.js" type="text/javascript"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;script language="Javascript" type="text/javascript"&amp;gt;
    // ender.js gobbles jQuery's ready event: Use ender.js $ instead
    $(document).ready(function() {
        jQuery(".fancybox").fancybox();
    });
    &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create your gallery folder, and add the necessary changes to your config.yml file.  You can see the sample changes that I made &lt;a href="https://github.com/gep13/gep13.github.io/commit/8f597cd922ffc3556481e7148990bcaa675dcceb"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the gallery tag to your blog post.  In my case, this was &lt;code&gt;{% raw %}{{ 'gallery_1' | image_list }}{% endraw %}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then do a &lt;code&gt;rake generate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assuming everything has worked, do a &lt;code&gt;rake preview&lt;/code&gt; and view your hard work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id="issue-when-doing-rake-generate"&gt;Issue when doing rake generate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first tried to do the above, the issue that I ran into looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C:/projects/gep13-github-io/public/images/galleries/gallery_1/thumbs/6.jpg
149jekyll 2.3.0 | Error:  No such file or directory - identify -ping C:/Users/appveyor/AppData/Local/Temp/mini_magick20140907-3000-6k90ct.jpg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This translates as, you don't have &lt;code&gt;ImageMagick&lt;/code&gt; installed, go and get it.  I tried a few different installations, and ran into other issues with having the right developer DLL's and includes.  The upshot was, I couldn't find a solution to using the installed version of &lt;code&gt;ImageMagick&lt;/code&gt;.  If however, I used the portable version, it works fine.  Go figure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="setting-up-appveyor"&gt;Setting up AppVeyor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the final piece of the puzzle, at least for me, was to get the same process working on AppVeyor, so that as part of the build process the thumbnails etc are generated.  Turns out again, thanks to AppVeyor extensibilty system, this is remarkably easy.  In fact, the changes that I need to make are exactly what I did on my own machine, i.e. install &lt;code&gt;ImageMagick&lt;/code&gt; using Chocolatey.  Now, unlike my machine, the AppVeyor build machines don't have Chocolatey already installed, so we need to get it onto them.  This can be done using the &lt;code&gt;install&lt;/code&gt; steps, as documented &lt;a href="http://www.appveyor.com/docs/appveyor-yml"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final result was the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-yaml"&gt;install:
  - ps: iex ((new-object net.webclient).DownloadString('https://chocolatey.org/install.ps1'))
  - ps: choco install imagemagick.tool
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two simple steps.  The first to install Chocolatey, and the second to install &lt;code&gt;ImageMagick&lt;/code&gt; portable edition.  This will now happen each time my AppVeyor build runs, and it will generate the thumbnails for each of my galleries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job done!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/using-a-basic-gallery-plugin-on-octopress-site' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Using a basic gallery plugin on Octopress Site';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/using-a-basic-gallery-plugin-on-octopress-site' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have collected a number of photos from various trips that I have been on, and I share them in various places, i.e. Facebook, Twitter, Flickr, etc.  However, from time to time, I want to include them easily into blog posts as well.  This is something that "should" be easy, but my experience over the last few days is that it isn't as simple as it should be.  This is especially useful when doing a tutorial blog post, and you want to capture a number of screen-shots and show them in order in a gallery.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/setup-appveyor-to-deploy-octopress-site-to-github-pages" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/setup-appveyor-to-deploy-octopress-site-to-github-pages</id>
		<title>Setup AppVeyor to deploy Octopress site to GitHub Pages</title>
		<updated>2014-09-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h2 id="history-of-this-blog"&gt;History of this blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog has now been through a number of iterations.  It started out as a custom built blog application in ASP.NET, then it moved to BlogEngine.net for a very short period.  It then made an appearance as a WordPress Blog, and now, in it's current incarnation, it is using Octopress hosted on GitHub Pages.  This way of hosting my blog was very much inspired by the work of &lt;a href="http://hadihariri.com/2013/12/24/migrating-from-wordpress-to-jekyll/"&gt;Hadi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://jake.ginnivan.net/blog/2014/06/10/low-friction-octopress-github-pages-setup/"&gt;Jake&lt;/a&gt; in setting up their blogs, so thanks go to them for their help!  Hadi pointed me in the right direction in terms of migrating initially from Wordpress, and Jake showed how it was possible to deploy automagically to GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slightly different technique that I have used, and the reason for this post, is that I have used &lt;a href="http://www.appveyor.com/"&gt;AppVeyor&lt;/a&gt; to do the deployment of the generated static HTML to GitHub.  What follows are the steps to make this happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="i-love-teamcity-but"&gt;I love TeamCity, but...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Jake's &lt;a href="http://jake.ginnivan.net/blog/2014/06/10/low-friction-octopress-github-pages-setup/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, he shows how you can use &lt;a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/teamcity/"&gt;TeamCity&lt;/a&gt; to listen for changes in the &lt;code&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; branch of your Octopress Git Repository, generate the static html, and then push to the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch of the same repository.  This is incredibly simple to do with TeamCity, but it obviously needs an available instance of TeamCity.  Unfortunately, this is not something that I have access to for personal (i.e. outside of work) projects.  As a result, I had to look elsewhere for a solution.  And for me, the solution was &lt;a href="http://www.appveyor.com/"&gt;AppVeyor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a &lt;a href="http://help.appveyor.com/discussions/questions/491-use-appveyor-to-deploy-changes-to-octopress-blog"&gt;small hiccup&lt;/a&gt; with setting up AppVeyor (which, by the way was resolved VERY quickly!), configuring AppVeyor to generate and deploy an Octopress site is very simple!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="setting-up-continuous-deployment-from-appveyor"&gt;Setting up continuous deployment from AppVeyor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you don't already have one, &lt;a href="https://ci.appveyor.com/signup/free"&gt;create an account&lt;/a&gt; with AppVeyor (which is completely free, assuming your repository is public), and authenticate with either GitHub, BitBucket, Visual Studio Online, or Kiln, depending on where your blog source code is going to be hosted.  Since I am using GitHub Pages, I will be referring to that for the rest of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click New Project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2014/6/7/NewProject.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Click New Project"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select your blog source code repository, in my case gep13.github.io, and AppVeyor will set about provisioning a new Project, ready to accept build steps and configuration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, you could start using the AppVeyor User Interface to setup the build, and this is what I started with.  However, I quickly realised that I would need to start using the &lt;a href="http://www.appveyor.com/docs/appveyor-yml"&gt;appveyor.yml&lt;/a&gt; file.  This was due to the fact that I wanted to be able to pass in a secure variables to the build process, namely my GitHub password, and this is not possible through the User Interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the same way that Jake did, I have setup my GitHub repository to use the source branch as the default.  This can be done through the settings page of your repository in GitHub&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2014/6/7/DefaultSourceBranch.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Set source branch as default in GitHub"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create an appveyor.yml file in the root of the source branch of your repository.  You can see mine &lt;a href="https://github.com/gep13/gep13.github.io/blob/source/appveyor.yml"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are four important things in this file.  Firstly, the init section.  In order to push changes back to GitHub, you need to let the newly created Virtual Machine that AppVeyor is running for you know the git credentials that you want to use.  This can be done using the standard &lt;code&gt;git config --global&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-yaml"&gt;init:
- git config --global user.email "&amp;lt;Your Email Address&amp;gt;"
- git config --global user.name "&amp;lt;Your User Name&amp;gt;"
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next important section is environment.  This is where you can specify 1 or more vaiables that you want to have available during your build steps.  If required, you can use the &lt;a href="https://ci.appveyor.com/tools/encrypt"&gt;encrypt data tool&lt;/a&gt; within AppVeyor to encrypt sensitive information.  This is exactly what I did with my GitHub password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-yaml"&gt;environment:
GithubUsername: gep13
GithubPassword:
  secure: XSuLygmr83zEpWcXIXMXGocN0QbooLud1eIMA3mQWKkT9LAU4TyrijLBcJIo7bD7
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next up, we need to specify the actual operations that we want to perform.  These have been lifted exactly out of Jakes configuration.  The especically important thing to notice here is the &lt;code&gt;%GithubUsername%&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;%GithubPassword%&lt;/code&gt; variables.  They refer to the environment variables that were configured above. &lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt;  As I found out, the &lt;code&gt;gen_deploy&lt;/code&gt; rake task does both a generate and a deploy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-yaml"&gt;build_script:
  - cmd: bundle install
  - cmd: if not exist _deploy (git clone https://%GithubUsername%:%GithubPassword%@github.com/%GithubUsername%/%GithubUsername%.github.io.git _deploy)
  - cmd: cd _deploy
  - cmd: git checkout master
  - cmd: cd ..
  - cmd: rake gen_deploy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start="0"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The final things that I needed to do was to specify that I didn't want to run any tests after the main build steps were completed.  This can be done using:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-yaml"&gt;test: off
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the above file checked into your repository, AppVeyor will set about doing the build.  The output of which should hopefully look something like this (the full output can be seen &lt;a href="https://ci.appveyor.com/project/GaryEwanPark/gep13-github-io/build/1.0.22"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2014/6/7/SuccessfulBuild.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Successful AppVeyor Build"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that, as they say, is that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, everytime you make a change in the &lt;code&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; branch of your Octopress Repository, AppVeyor will collect all the changes, execute the build steps, and deploy your latest changes to the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch, ready for viewing on your site.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/setup-appveyor-to-deploy-octopress-site-to-github-pages' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Setup AppVeyor to deploy Octopress site to GitHub Pages';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/setup-appveyor-to-deploy-octopress-site-to-github-pages' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;This blog has now been through a number of iterations.  It started out as a custom built blog application in ASP.NET, then it moved to BlogEngine.net for a very short period.  It then made an appearance as a WordPress Blog, and now, in it's current incarnation, it is using Octopress hosted on GitHub Pages.  This way of hosting my blog was very much inspired by the work of &lt;a href="http://hadihariri.com/2013/12/24/migrating-from-wordpress-to-jekyll/"&gt;Hadi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://jake.ginnivan.net/blog/2014/06/10/low-friction-octopress-github-pages-setup/"&gt;Jake&lt;/a&gt; in setting up their blogs, so thanks go to them for their help!  Hadi pointed me in the right direction in terms of migrating initially from Wordpress, and Jake showed how it was possible to deploy automagically to GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/old-new-sculpt-ergonomic" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/old-new-sculpt-ergonomic</id>
		<title>Out with the old, in with the new - Microsoft Sculpt Ergonomic</title>
		<updated>2014-06-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h1 id="tldr"&gt;tl;dr&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really nice keyboard, and would definitely recommend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="getting-started-with-my-new-sculpt-keyboard"&gt;Getting started with my new Sculpt Keyboard&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; I have only been using this keyboard for about&amp;nbsp;2 hours. The opinions shared here may change over time, and if they do, I will update the blog post to reflect this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For over five years now, I have been the proud owner of the Microsoft Natural Ergonomic Keyboard 4000. I liked this keyboard so much that I actually bought two of them. One for the office, and one for home. However, as with most things, there comes a time when items need to be replaced. For me, with this particular keyboard, this was mainly due to the fact that on my work version, the “y” key had become flaky. Every so often, even though it was definitely being pushed, it simply wouldn’t work. The "solution" was to hit the key really hard, and it would eventually work. When I decided to leave my old job, I also decided it was time to replace the keyboard, and have a new one for my new job. New beginnings and all that…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was given some Amazon vouchers as part of my leaving present, I thought that this would be the perfect opportunity to get the new keyboard, and so I bought &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/hardware/en-gb/p/sculpt-ergonomic-desktop/L5V-00006"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have since had this delivered, and I am in fact using it to write this blog post. What are my thoughts so far I hear you ask? Well, let me tell you…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-keyboard"&gt;The Keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like it! It is much smaller than the 4000, but this is mainly due to the keys that it doesn’t have, i.e. the NumPad. You can see the Sculpt Keyboard sitting on top of the 4000 in the picture below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2014/6/7/WP_20140607_19_36_45_Pro-1024x576.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Sculpt sitting on top of 4000"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keyboard itself feels very solid, which is good. Access to the battery compartment is via a magnetised cover (all the devices, keyboard, mouse and Number Pad, all share this feature), which makes inserting/changing the batteries very simple. The keys feel much less mechanical than the 4000, which was a common complaint of that device, and they don’t take as much movement of the fingers to depress the keys. It actually feels more like typing on a laptop keyboard, but with the benefit of the split keyboard layout&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the aid of a toggle switch, each function key can be used as a shortcut for Windows 8 functions, such as Search, Share, Settings, etc. This isn’t something that I think I will be making use of. I will keep it in Function Key mode, and simply use keyboard shortcuts like "Windows+C" to get to the required functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, the split space bar seemed a little to me, however, having used it, this makes sense. I typically hit the space bar with my right thumb, and I am finding it much easier to press, as you are not having to depress a much larger key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-mouse"&gt;The Mouse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I took the mouse out of the box, my immediate reaction was, euch! What is that bulbous, monstrosity!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2014/6/7/WP_20140607_19_35_44_Pro-1024x576.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Microsoft Sculpt Mouse"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, having used it for a while, I am actually getting used to it, and I think I will like it. The addition of the Windows key, to take you to the Start Screen is a nice touch, and the back button (which I have come to rely on with my mice) is a very welcome addition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-number-pad"&gt;The Number Pad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I say, it’s a Number Pad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2014/6/7/WP_20140607_19_35_56_Pro-576x1024.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Microsoft Sculpt Number Pad"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does exactly what it says on the tin. While using the trio of devices, I have found myself looking for the Number Pad directly to the right of the keyboard (when entering an IP address, for instance) and it hasn’t been there. I think that will take a minute to get used to, but on the whole, the Number Pad is not a common input mechanism for me, so I don’t think I will mind having to move further to find it when required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-transceiver"&gt;The Transceiver&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This to me seems quite big, I would have expected it to be smaller, similar to that of my Fitbit or Garmin connector, shown below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://gep13wpstorage.blob.core.windows.net/gep13/2014/6/7/WP_20140607_19_37_52_Pro-1024x576.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Sculpt Transceiver compared to Garmin one"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing I can think is that it needs to be larger due to the fact that it is a single transceiver for all three devices. When not required, or being transported, there is a slot in the inside of the mouse for storing it. Again, this is a magnetized slot, so immediately when stored, it feels secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One word of warning though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://twitter.com/ijonas/status/463983735365697536&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-setup"&gt;The setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This really was a snap! Took everything out of the box, removed the battery savings strips, plugged in the transceiver, small driver install, and everything worked. I am running Windows 8.1.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/old-new-sculpt-ergonomic' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Out with the old, in with the new - Microsoft Sculpt Ergonomic';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/old-new-sculpt-ergonomic' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Really nice keyboard, and would definitely recommend!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-code-continuous-integration-101-talk-dunddd" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-code-continuous-integration-101-talk-dunddd</id>
		<title>Slides and code from Continuous Integration 101 talk at DunDDD</title>
		<updated>2013-12-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h1 id="continuous-integration-101"&gt;Continuous Integration 101&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 23rd November 2013, I presented a talk entitled "Continuous Integration 101" at the &lt;a href="http://dun.dddscotland.com/"&gt;DunDDD Conference in Dundee&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;The abstract for the talk was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="blockquote"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is well understood that "Continuous Integration" is a development best practice, however, it is also something that is not often implemented within development teams. Typical reasons include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is difficult to set up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is difficult to maintain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It takes too long&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session we will look at how you can incrementally work your way to fully implementing Continuous Integration into your development process. This talk will focus on using TeamCity as the Continuous Integration Server and psake build engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I was quite happy with how the talk went, and it seems to go down quite well. &amp;nbsp;There was a fair bit of interaction with the audience, with several questions, which I hope that I was able to answer. &amp;nbsp;If there are any follow-up questions, then please feel free to get in touch, and I will do my best to respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="slides-and-code"&gt;slides and code&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in seeing the slides from the talk, you can find them displayed below, and also available for download [here](/assets/posts/2013-12-02-slides-code-continuous-integration-101-talk-dunddd/Continuous Integration 101.pdf).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{% slideshare 28819037 %}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to check out what little code was used during the presentation, you can find it &lt;a href="http://gep13.me/CIDemos"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-code-continuous-integration-101-talk-dunddd' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Slides and code from Continuous Integration 101 talk at DunDDD';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-code-continuous-integration-101-talk-dunddd' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 23rd November 2013, I presented a talk entitled "Continuous Integration 101" at the &lt;a href="http://dun.dddscotland.com/"&gt;DunDDD Conference in Dundee&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;The abstract for the talk was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/bsod-windows-81-using-internet-connection-sharing-windows-phone-8" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/bsod-windows-81-using-internet-connection-sharing-windows-phone-8</id>
		<title>BSOD on Windows 8.1 when using Internet Connection Sharing on Windows Phone 8</title>
		<updated>2013-11-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h1 id="but-there-is-a-fix"&gt;But there is a fix...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the update of my laptop to Windows 8.1, every time I would tether to my Windows Phone 8 using Internet Connection Sharing, I would get a Blue Screen Of Death (BSOD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/posts/2013-11-07-bsod-windows-81-using-internet-connection-sharing-windows-phone-8/WP_20131025_07_11_25_Pro-1024x576.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="BSOD when using ICS 1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/posts/2013-11-07-bsod-windows-81-using-internet-connection-sharing-windows-phone-8/WP_20131025_06_56_38_Pro-1024x576.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="BSOD when using ICS 2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wouldn't happen if I was connected to a standard wireless connection, it was only when I was using the wireless hot spot which is made available through Internet Connection Sharing on my Windows Phone 8. &amp;nbsp;After a bit of googling, I turned up this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gadgets.itwriting.com/1986-fixing-blue-screen-using-internet-connection-sharing-in-windows-phone-8.html#comment-35511"&gt;http://gadgets.itwriting.com/1986-fixing-blue-screen-using-internet-connection-sharing-in-windows-phone-8.html#comment-35511&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which seemed to explain exactly what I needed to do, however, for the life of me, I couldn't find the dialogue box in Windows 8.1 that would give me access to the FIPS setting to fix the issue. &amp;nbsp;I asked the author of the blog post if he could help, and happily he was able to, check the comments of the blog post from that information on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, while I was waiting for his reply, I reached out to my friendly neighborhood IT expert, namely &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MarkLeHuray"&gt;Mark Le Huray&lt;/a&gt;, who was able to point me in the direction of a command line way of setting the required parameter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MarkLeHuray/status/393664176012267520"&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/posts/2013-11-07-bsod-windows-81-using-internet-connection-sharing-windows-phone-8/Twitter_Help.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Twitter Help from Mark Le Huray"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here "ur wireless name" is actually the name of the wireless endpoint, i.e. the SSID for the connection. &amp;nbsp;This is what is displayed in the Internet Sharing page on your windows phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opening the command prompt, and executing this command was all the is required to get rid of the BSOD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/posts/2013-11-07-bsod-windows-81-using-internet-connection-sharing-windows-phone-8/2013-11-05_0741.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Fixing BSOD by setting FIPS"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to Mark for all his help in getting this sorted, and also Tim who pointed me in the right direction!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/bsod-windows-81-using-internet-connection-sharing-windows-phone-8' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'BSOD on Windows 8.1 when using Internet Connection Sharing on Windows Phone 8';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/bsod-windows-81-using-internet-connection-sharing-windows-phone-8' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;Following the update of my laptop to Windows 8.1, every time I would tether to my Windows Phone 8 using Internet Connection Sharing, I would get a Blue Screen Of Death (BSOD).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/battery-life-nokia-lumia-920-really-fantastic" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/battery-life-nokia-lumia-920-really-fantastic</id>
		<title>The battery life of the Nokia Lumia 920 really is fantastic...</title>
		<updated>2013-10-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h1 id="when-you-turn-off-all-data-connections"&gt;...when you turn off all data connections!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id="tldr"&gt;tl;dr;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the radios and antennas switched off on my Nokia Lumia 920, the battery has lasted from the 28th October through to today, the 7th November. &amp;nbsp;A total of 11 days! &amp;nbsp;This has included some fairly solid use, listening to podcasts, audio books and music, as well as using it as my alarm clock.  This is far more than I thought it would last, very impressed. &amp;nbsp;See the gallery at the end of the post for pictures of how the battery was discharging. &amp;nbsp;The spikes are when I was syncing the phone with the desktop to grab some new podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="now-the-full-story"&gt;Now the full story...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently did a &lt;a href="http://gep13.me/1gbHdfP"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about how I started using my old Nokia Lumia 920 as my alternative to both a TomTom and an iPod. &amp;nbsp;Apart from a couple synchronisation issues between iTunes and the Windows Phone Desktop Application, I am happy to report that this little experiment has been going really well. &amp;nbsp;I use the phone pretty much every day, listening to podcasts on the commute to work, and music while in the office, and also taking photos/videos of Alivia (that's our new-born baby daughter :-)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing that has _really&amp;nbsp;_stood out for me though is the battery life of the Nokia Lumia 920. &amp;nbsp;As soon as you turn on flight mode, i.e. disabling all the data connections that the phone has to offer (Bluetooth, wi-fi, mobile, etc), the battery quite literally goes for days! &amp;nbsp;When using my Nokia Lumia 925 as a _phone,&amp;nbsp;_I am lucky if I can go a day without needing to charge it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I charged the 920 for what I think is the first time since I made the switch to using this device as my media device, although I think I must have charged it in between, otherwise it would have been over 2 weeks without a charge, which would be a bit of a stretch I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-gb/store/app/insider/d9b7989e-1592-4f25-a556-4755c06bf2e9"&gt;Insider&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;application, it is currently estimating 6 days and 4 hours before the next charge for the Nokia Lumia 920, and 1 day and 2 hours for the Nokia Lumia 925. &amp;nbsp;See the screenshots below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="assets/posts/2013-10-28-battery-life-nokia-lumia-920-really-fantastic/wp_ss_20131028_0001-180x300.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Insider Application running on Nokia Lumia 925"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="assets/posts/2013-10-28-battery-life-nokia-lumia-920-really-fantastic/wp_ss_20131028_0001-180x300.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Insider Application running on Nokia Lumia 920"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I firmly believe that the Nokia Lumia 925 will need charged tomorrow morning, but I am very curious to see how the Nokia Lumia 920 lasts before needing another charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, here is a gallery of how the battery was discharging through the 11 days that it was being used. &amp;nbsp;Very impressive!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/battery-life-nokia-lumia-920-really-fantastic' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'The battery life of the Nokia Lumia 920 really is fantastic...';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/battery-life-nokia-lumia-920-really-fantastic' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;With all the radios and antennas switched off on my Nokia Lumia 920, the battery has lasted from the 28th October through to today, the 7th November. &amp;nbsp;A total of 11 days! &amp;nbsp;This has included some fairly solid use, listening to podcasts, audio books and music, as well as using it as my alarm clock.  This is far more than I thought it would last, very impressed. &amp;nbsp;See the gallery at the end of the post for pictures of how the battery was discharging. &amp;nbsp;The spikes are when I was syncing the phone with the desktop to grab some new podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-dunddd-2013-now-open" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-dunddd-2013-now-open</id>
		<title>Registration for DunDDD 2013 is now open</title>
		<updated>2013-10-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h1 id="grab-your-ticket-for-dunddd-quickly-so-you-dont-miss-out"&gt;Grab your ticket for DunDDD quickly so you don't miss out!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The call for speakers at the Scottish Community Event (organised by the &lt;a href="http://scottishdevelopers.com/"&gt;Scottish Developers&lt;/a&gt;) known as &lt;a href="http://dun.dddscotland.co.uk/speaker"&gt;DunDDD &lt;/a&gt;has now closed and the registration has opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="dunddd-is-now-in-its-third-year"&gt;DunDDD is now in its third year&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be the 3rd DunDDD, built on the popular foundation of the Developer! Developer! Developer! conference series which has spread to all corners of the UK and the international arena. &amp;nbsp;DDD conferences are community-run days where passionate and enthusiastic people come together to learn, share ideas, and to network within the many hubs of the development community. Best of all DDD events are &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt; to everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year DunDDD will be featuring an entire track dedicated to Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go and grab your &lt;a href="http://dun.dddscotland.co.uk/registration"&gt;ticket now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-dunddd-2013-now-open' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Registration for DunDDD 2013 is now open';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-dunddd-2013-now-open' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;The call for speakers at the Scottish Community Event (organised by the &lt;a href="http://scottishdevelopers.com/"&gt;Scottish Developers&lt;/a&gt;) known as &lt;a href="http://dun.dddscotland.co.uk/speaker"&gt;DunDDD &lt;/a&gt;has now closed and the registration has opened.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/started-using-nokia-lumia-920-ipod-tomtom-replacement" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/started-using-nokia-lumia-920-ipod-tomtom-replacement</id>
		<title>Started using my Nokia Lumia 920 as an iPod and TomTom replacement</title>
		<updated>2013-10-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h1 id="and-i-cant-see-myself-looking-back"&gt;And I can't see myself looking back!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now using my spare Nokia Lumia 920 as a replacement for both my failing Classic iPod, and my TomTom. &amp;nbsp;I have always liked to keep music and GPS devices separate from my phone, as using these types of services is a big drain on battery. &amp;nbsp;Now though, I am using two phone devices to service all of these needs. &amp;nbsp;No more need to carry around 3 separate devices!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="heres-the-story"&gt;Here's the story...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently upgraded my mobile phone to the Nokia Lumia 925, and I love it! &amp;nbsp;I upgraded from the Nokia Lumia 920, but there were a couple of things happening with the 920 which made me want to move away from it. &amp;nbsp;The first of which was that a single pixel, all the way down the screen, is stuck on a single colour. &amp;nbsp;This started happening after the warranty ran out on it, so there was nothing I could do aside from an expensive repair. &amp;nbsp;I opted to reset the device in order to send it to something like Mazuma mobile to get some money for it, however, the reset didn't go well and it got stuck on the spinning gears. &amp;nbsp;Doh!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last few months, the 920 has been nothing more than a paper weight on my desk, but after a Twitter conversation the other day, I was pointed at the following &lt;a href="http://mobileworld.appamundi.com/blogs/petevickers/archive/2013/09/13/what-do-i-do-if-my-lumia-shows-spinning-gears-and-won-t-restart.aspx"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/petevick"&gt;Pete Vickers&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Now, don't get me wrong, I was skeptical. &amp;nbsp;The key combination sounded like something from a Street Fighter Special Move, but I gave it a shot. &amp;nbsp;After 3 attempts, the 920 rebooted, and after a period of time, I was booted into the main screen. Result!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then went ahead and grabbed the latest update for the phone, taking the phone up to the GDR 2 release, and then went ahead and installed all the necessary applications, including the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-gb/store/app/here-drive/31bbc68c-503e-4561-8d85-a294d54df06f"&gt;HERE Drive+&lt;/a&gt; - Navigation application (uses the HERE Maps application)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-gb/store/app/here-maps/efa4b4a7-7499-46ce-aa95-3e4ab3b39313"&gt;HERE Maps&lt;/a&gt; -&amp;nbsp;Mapping application that allows for downloading maps using a WiFi Connection, and then using locally on device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-gb/store/app/here-transit/adfdad16-b54a-4ec3-b11e-66bd691be4e6"&gt;HERE Transit&lt;/a&gt; - Provides routes between two selected places&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-gb/store/app/nokia-music/f5874252-1f04-4c3f-a335-4fa3b7b85329"&gt;Nokia Music&lt;/a&gt; - free music streaming application (also plays local music files)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nokia Pro Cam - quite simply amazing!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nokia Smart Cam - great camera application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these applications in place, and my music and podcasts synced to the phone and required maps downloaded, I have a perfectly functioning iPod and TomTom replacement, taking the number of devices that I need to carry around from 2, to 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I was in a unique position where I had a spare Nokia Lumia 920 to serve this purpose, there is nothing to stop you doing something similar using one of the many cheap, lower end devices, that are coming onto the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="amazing-deal-at-tesco-on-the-nokia-lumia-510"&gt;Amazing deal at Tesco on the Nokia Lumia 510&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night while shopping at Tesco, I saw the following deal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_2146" align="alignnone" width="1632"]&lt;a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/started-using-nokia-lumia-920-ipod-tomtom-replacement/wp_20131012_18_47_32_pro/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/WP_20131012_18_47_32_Pro.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Nokia Lumia 510 only £80"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Nokia Lumia 510 only £80[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is quite simply amazing! &amp;nbsp;When you put it together with the services that you get from both Microsoft and Nokia, this little device makes for a compelling choice. &amp;nbsp;It is not hard to understand why these lower end Lumia's are the fastest selling devices at the moment. &amp;nbsp;They are very affordable, and offer the end-user a lot of options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you compare the above to something like the iPod, starting at £199, it would seem an obvious choice. &amp;nbsp;The functionality and available applications is comparable. &amp;nbsp;The Nokia Lumia 510 only has 4GB of hard drive space compared to the 16GB of the iPod, but if you don't need a lot of storage space,or are happy to use the free 7GB of cloud storage, or stream data from the free Nokia Music service, then this is not really a problem. &amp;nbsp;You could also look to something like the Nokia Lumia 520, which has an option for an expandable micro SD card up to 64GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-setup-of-the-nokia-lumia-920"&gt;The setup of the Nokia Lumia 920&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The start screen of my Nokia Lumia 920 now looks like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_2147" align="alignnone" width="768"]&lt;a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/started-using-nokia-lumia-920-ipod-tomtom-replacement/wp_ss_20131013_0001/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/wp_ss_20131013_0001.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Nokia Lumia 920 Start Screen"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Nokia Lumia 920 Start Screen[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, all the "normal" tiles, such as messaging, phone, email, etc, have all been removed, leaving only the tiles for the essential applications, such as navigation and music. &amp;nbsp;Since all the required maps for the navigation application that Nokia provide can be downloaded ahead of time using the phone's wireless connection, there is no need for a network connection while using it. &amp;nbsp;In fact, I have actually went as far as to enable the phones flight mode, and will only enable the wireless connection when required.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/started-using-nokia-lumia-920-ipod-tomtom-replacement' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Started using my Nokia Lumia 920 as an iPod and TomTom replacement';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/started-using-nokia-lumia-920-ipod-tomtom-replacement' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;I am now using my spare Nokia Lumia 920 as a replacement for both my failing Classic iPod, and my TomTom. &amp;nbsp;I have always liked to keep music and GPS devices separate from my phone, as using these types of services is a big drain on battery. &amp;nbsp;Now though, I am using two phone devices to service all of these needs. &amp;nbsp;No more need to carry around 3 separate devices!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/northern-lights-2013-conference" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/northern-lights-2013-conference</id>
		<title>Northern Lights 2013 Conference</title>
		<updated>2013-10-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h1 id="get-your-tickets-now"&gt;Get your tickets now!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to let you know about an upcoming event in Aberdeen that I have been helping to arrange. It is taking place on Friday 18th October 2013. &amp;nbsp;The event in question is the Northern Lights 2013 Conference.&amp;nbsp; The website for the conference can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/"&gt;http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event is in its third year, and this year the theme is tools.&amp;nbsp; Both the tools that we use, and the tools we build.&amp;nbsp; There is a wide range of speakers available, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/hadi-hariri.html"&gt;Hadi Hariri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/kendall-miller.html"&gt;Kendall Miller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/24/sarah-drummond.html"&gt;Sarah Drummond&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/kate-stone.html"&gt;Kate Stone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/10/02/maria-gutierrez.html"&gt;Maria Gutierrez&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/niall-merrigan.html"&gt;Niall Merrigan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/glenn-henriksen.html"&gt;Glenn Hendrickson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are offering up an exciting line up of talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, there will be two open spaces at the conference, where attendees will have an opportunity to suggest a topic for an interactive conversation with other attendees and speakers.&amp;nbsp; If you haven’t been to an open space before, they are fantastic.&amp;nbsp; It is a perfect opportunity to interact with other like mind people about a topic that you are interested in.&amp;nbsp; The best way to get something out of this is to suggest a topic that you are especially interested in, and hopefully other people will get involved as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tickets are £15 for the day, which includes coffee and lunch for regular attendees, and Students tickets to the talks are free, plus you can buy a lunch ticket for £5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope to see you there.&amp;nbsp; If you have any questions about the event, then please don’t hesitate to get in touch with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know anyone else who would be interested in attending this event, I would really appreciate it if you could forward on this email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event is lovingly sponsored by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Aberdeen - &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.abdn.ac.uk"&gt;http://www.abdn.ac.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neo -&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.neo.com"&gt;http://www.neo.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fifth Ring -&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.fifthring.com"&gt;http://www.fifthring.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Codify - &lt;a href="http://www.codify.ltd.uk"&gt;http://www.codify.ltd.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arnold Clark -&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.arnoldclark.com"&gt;http://www.arnoldclark.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AAA -&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.aaajobs.co.uk"&gt;http://aaajobs.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/northern-lights-2013-conference' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Northern Lights 2013 Conference';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/northern-lights-2013-conference' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to let you know about an upcoming event in Aberdeen that I have been helping to arrange. It is taking place on Friday 18th October 2013. &amp;nbsp;The event in question is the Northern Lights 2013 Conference.&amp;nbsp; The website for the conference can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/windows-phone-8-gdr2-update-finally-arrives-nokia-lumia-925-3-network" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/windows-phone-8-gdr2-update-finally-arrives-nokia-lumia-925-3-network</id>
		<title>Windows Phone 8 GDR2 Update finally arrives for my Nokia Lumia 925 on the 3 network</title>
		<updated>2013-10-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;p&gt;I am happy to report that the GDR2 update for my Nokia Lumia 925 has finally arrived. &amp;nbsp;I say finally because it is almost 1 month after it arrived for my wife's phone! &amp;nbsp;We are not on the same operator, so this is obviously showing the difference in turning around the updates for the Windows Phone eco-system, and it has to be said that this really is a sad state of affairs! &amp;nbsp;I really hope that this turn around time for pushing out the updates improves, as getting the latest features for my handset is very important to me. &amp;nbsp;Almost important enough to consider switching mobile phone providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost 1 month ago, I convinced my wife that she should upgrade her mobile phone to the Nokia Lumia 925. &amp;nbsp;To my annoyance, one day after receiving the handset, she was prompted that there was an update available for the phone. &amp;nbsp;I started the update process, which actually consisted of two back to back updates, and after checking, this update was the much rumored &lt;a href="http://winsupersite.com/windows-phone/complete-guide-windows-phone-8-gdr2"&gt;GDR2 update&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the update, the various version numbers changed as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**Original**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**First Update**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**Second Update**&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**OS Version:**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8.0.10327.0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8.0.10327.0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8.0.10328.0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**Firmware revision number:**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3040.0000.1322.2004&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3040.0005.1323.3004&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3047.0000.1326.2006&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**Hardware revision number:**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.0.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.0.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.0.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**Radio software version:**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3.2.04018.1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3.2.04018.1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3.2.04028.1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**Chip SOC version:**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8960&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8960&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8960&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward 1 month, and after a twitter conversation with the support team at 3, which was a little coincidental (by the way, I am not claiming responsibility for getting the update released :-)), the GDR2 update arrived for my phone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://twitter.com/gep13/status/384990097176657922&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting thing is that although the OS version between the two phones is the same, the firmware version numbers are different. &amp;nbsp;You can see the comparison table between the original and update on my phone below. &amp;nbsp;Both the firmware revision number, and the radio software version numbers on my phone are higher than on my wife's phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**Original**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**Update**&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**OS Version:**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8.0.10327.0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8.0.10328.0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**Firmware revision number:**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3040.0000.1322.2003&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3049.0000.1330.0004&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**Hardware revision number:**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.0.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1.0.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**Radio software version:**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3.2.04018.1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3.2.04033.1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;**Chip SOC version:**&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8960&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8960&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarize, in addition to the huge difference in time between pushing out the updates between the mobile phone providers, it also looks like they are choosing to release different updates. &amp;nbsp;It would be really interesting to find out why they are doing this. &amp;nbsp;To me, this seem a little bit troubling. &amp;nbsp;I know the carriers have a right to decide which updates are released to the handsets that they are in charge of, but to go an entire month after one of your competitors releases the update seems very excessive to me. &amp;nbsp;Let's hope the release process improves with the forthcoming GDR3 update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see a gallery of the screenshots that I took during the update process below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[gallery type="rectangular" ids="2124,2126,2127,2128,2129,2130,2131,2132"]&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/windows-phone-8-gdr2-update-finally-arrives-nokia-lumia-925-3-network' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Windows Phone 8 GDR2 Update finally arrives for my Nokia Lumia 925 on the 3 network';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/windows-phone-8-gdr2-update-finally-arrives-nokia-lumia-925-3-network' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;I am happy to report that the GDR2 update for my Nokia Lumia 925 has finally arrived. &amp;nbsp;I say finally because it is almost 1 month after it arrived for my wife's phone! &amp;nbsp;We are not on the same operator, so this is obviously showing the difference in turning around the updates for the Windows Phone eco-system, and it has to be said that this really is a sad state of affairs! &amp;nbsp;I really hope that this turn around time for pushing out the updates improves, as getting the latest features for my handset is very important to me. &amp;nbsp;Almost important enough to consider switching mobile phone providers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/jon-skeet-scotland-tour" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/jon-skeet-scotland-tour</id>
		<title>Jon Skeet Scotland Tour</title>
		<updated>2013-06-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h1 id="jon-skeet-taking-a-quick-break-from-stack-overflow"&gt;Jon Skeet - Taking a quick break from Stack Overflow&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is with great pleasure that I can announce that I have been able to confirm Jon Skeet, &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/22656/jon-skeet"&gt;legendary contributor to Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;, and author of &lt;a href="http://www.manning.com/skeet3/"&gt;C# in Depth&lt;/a&gt;, to do User Group Presentations in Glasgow, Aberdeen and Edinburgh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say a big thank you to Jon for taking the time out of his busy schedule to come up to Scotland to do these talks, it really is very much appreciated! &amp;nbsp;Jon will be talking to two topics, "Semantics Matter" and "Abusing C#". &amp;nbsp;The Abusing C# talk will be repeated in both Aberdeen and Edinburgh, so if you can't make it to one, you have the option to attend the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out more information about Jon Skeet on his site &lt;a href="http://msmvps.com/blogs/jon_skeet/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="glasgow-event"&gt;Glasgow Event&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the help of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.scottishdevelopers.com/"&gt;Scottish Developers&lt;/a&gt;, this meeting, entitled "Semantics Matter", will be taking place on Wednesday 7th August 2013, in the Mercure Hotel, starting at 7 o'clock in the evening. &amp;nbsp;For full details of the event, and to register, check out the Eventbrite page&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://jonskeet-glasgow.eventbrite.com/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="aberdeen-event"&gt;Aberdeen Event&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This meeting, entitled "Abusing C#", will be taking place on Thursday 8th August 2013, at the RGU St Andrews Street building at 6 o'clock in the evening. &amp;nbsp;For full details of the event, and to register, check out the Eventbrite page&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://adnuguk-aug2013.eventbrite.com/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="edinburgh-event"&gt;Edinburgh Event&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, with the help of &lt;a href="http://www.scottishdevelopers.com/"&gt;Scottish Developers&lt;/a&gt;, this meeting, entitled "Abusing C#", will be taking place on Friday 9th August, For full details of the event, and to register, check out the Eventbrite page &lt;a href="http://jonskeet-edinburgh-2013.eventbrite.co.uk/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="questions"&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about either of these events, please don't hesitate to get in touch!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/jon-skeet-scotland-tour' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Jon Skeet Scotland Tour';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/jon-skeet-scotland-tour' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;It is with great pleasure that I can announce that I have been able to confirm Jon Skeet, &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/22656/jon-skeet"&gt;legendary contributor to Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;, and author of &lt;a href="http://www.manning.com/skeet3/"&gt;C# in Depth&lt;/a&gt;, to do User Group Presentations in Glasgow, Aberdeen and Edinburgh.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/bill-wager-scotland-tour" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/bill-wager-scotland-tour</id>
		<title>Bill Wagner Scotland Tour</title>
		<updated>2013-06-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h1 id="bill-wagner-taking-a-break-from-golf"&gt;Bill Wagner - Taking a break from Golf&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is with great pleasure that I can announce that I have been able to confirm Bill Wagner, author of &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Effective-Covers-4-0-Development-ebook/dp/B003BXRNZI/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1370544140&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=effective+c%23"&gt;Effective C#&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/More-Effective-Specific-Development-ebook/dp/B001FA0MAC/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1370544140&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=effective+c%23"&gt;More Effective C#&lt;/a&gt;, to do User Group Presentations in both Glasgow and Aberdeen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to send out a huge thank you to Mark Rendle (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/markrendle"&gt;@markrendle&lt;/a&gt;) for the initial introductions, and obviously a special thank to Bill for agreeing to visit these User Groups. &amp;nbsp;Bill is taking time out of a busy golfing holiday (which I am very jealous of) to present topics on Async and Await Practices in C# 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out more information about Bill Wagner at his site &lt;a href="http://billwagner.azurewebsites.net/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="aberdeen-event"&gt;Aberdeen Event&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This meeting, entitled "Async/Await Practices in C# 5", will be taking place on Thursday 4th July 2013, at the RGU St Andrews Street building at 6 o'clock in the evening. &amp;nbsp;For full details of the event, and to register, check out the Eventbrite page &lt;a href="http://adnuguk-jul2013.eventbrite.com/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="glasgow-event"&gt;Glasgow Event&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the help of &lt;a href="http://www.scottishdevelopers.com/"&gt;Scottish Developers&lt;/a&gt;, this meeting, entitled "Async/Await Practices in C# 5", will be taking place on Saturday 13th July 2013, in the Mercure Hotel, starting at 10 o'clock in the morning. &amp;nbsp;For full details of the event, and to register, check out the Eventbrite page &lt;a href="http://billwagner-glasgow.eventbrite.com/#"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="questions"&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about either of these events, please don't hesitate to get in touch!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/bill-wager-scotland-tour' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Bill Wagner Scotland Tour';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/bill-wager-scotland-tour' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;It is with great pleasure that I can announce that I have been able to confirm Bill Wagner, author of &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Effective-Covers-4-0-Development-ebook/dp/B003BXRNZI/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1370544140&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=effective+c%23"&gt;Effective C#&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/More-Effective-Specific-Development-ebook/dp/B001FA0MAC/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1370544140&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=effective+c%23"&gt;More Effective C#&lt;/a&gt;, to do User Group Presentations in both Glasgow and Aberdeen.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/opening-and-editing-an-adobe-illustrator-file-using-expression-design" />
		<id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/opening-and-editing-an-adobe-illustrator-file-using-expression-design</id>
		<title>Opening and editing an Adobe Illustrator file using Expression Design</title>
		<updated>2013-05-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<content>
                                        

&lt;h1 id="open-and-edit-a.ai-file-using-expression-design"&gt;Open and edit a .ai file using Expression Design&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other week, I needed to edit the original source files for the Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group in order to change the size of the png's that I use for various things (like avatar's, etc). &amp;nbsp;Unfortunately, these were created using Adobe Illustrator, which I don't have access to. &amp;nbsp;I had a hunt around, but I couldn't find a way to do it. &amp;nbsp;Enter Twitter...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ever knowledgeable Scott Lovegrove (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/scottisafool"&gt;@scottisafool&lt;/a&gt;), made a great suggestion of using Expression Design to open and edit the files. &amp;nbsp;I had thought that Expression Design was only part of the Expression Studio, which I also don't have, but...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="expression-design-is-free"&gt;Expression Design is free!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it used to only be part of the Expression Studio, Express Design is now actually free! &amp;nbsp;You can download it from &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=36180"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="opening-and-editing-the-file"&gt;Opening and Editing the file&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This couldn't be simpler! &amp;nbsp;Open up Expression Design, and open the file. &amp;nbsp;Once open, you will have the option to Export the image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_2076" align="alignnone" width="1171"]&lt;a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Expression-Design-Export-Menu.png"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Expression-Design-Export-Menu.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Expression Design Export Menu"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Expression Design Export Menu[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the next window, you will then be able to choose the output format, and also the size of the resulting image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[caption id="attachment_2077" align="alignnone" width="1206"]&lt;a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Expression-Design-Export-Options.png"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Expression-Design-Export-Options.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Expression Design Export Options"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Expression Design Export Options[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simples! &amp;nbsp;Thanks again Scott!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id="disqus_thread"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'gep13'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname
    var disqus_identifier = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/opening-and-editing-an-adobe-illustrator-file-using-expression-design' + 'S/';
    var disqus_title = 'Opening and editing an Adobe Illustrator file using Expression Design';
    var disqus_url = 'http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/opening-and-editing-an-adobe-illustrator-file-using-expression-design' + '/';

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
        var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
        dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
        (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript"&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink"&gt;comments powered by &lt;span class="logo-disqus"&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
                                </content>
		<summary>&lt;p&gt;The other week, I needed to edit the original source files for the Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group in order to change the size of the png's that I use for various things (like avatar's, etc). &amp;nbsp;Unfortunately, these were created using Adobe Illustrator, which I don't have access to. &amp;nbsp;I had a hunt around, but I couldn't find a way to do it. &amp;nbsp;Enter Twitter...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
	</entry>
</feed>