<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Music Concert | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/music-concert/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-11T06:01:50+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vampires Rock]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/vampires-rock/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-14T19:40:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/vampires-rock</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lynn had organised tickets to go and see <a href="http://www.vampiresrock.com/index.htm">Vampires Rock</a> tonight. I had no idea what it was all about, so had no idea what to expect, but I have to say that it was really good!!!</p>

<p>Steve Steinman, the guy who runs it, also does a Meatloaf Tour which Lynn had also been to, that is how she know about Vampires Rock. It was basically a musical, that followed the story of the Baron, and how he is looking for a new mate. The difference being that the songs are all classic rock songs. It was all very well done!!!</p>

<p>The production also included Toya Wilcox, who also did a great job.</p>

<p>I have to be honest, at the start, I thought the band was faking playing the instruments, but it became clear that they definitely weren&rsquo;t, they were just very talented. The band was called the Lost Boys.</p>

<p>Steinman is coming back to Aberdeen in April next year for another show which I think we are going to go along to as well.</p>

<p>We hung around after the performance and got some autographs, and I got my photo taken with one of the dancers:</p>

<p>[singlepic id=1437 w=320 h=240 float=]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Feeling Concert]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/the-feeling-concert/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-14T08:59:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/the-feeling-concert</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Went along to The Feeling Concert last night at the Music Hall, had a great time, they put on a really good show that had the whole crowd jumping.</p>

<p>They were supported by a very energetic Belgium band called <a href="http://www.daspop.com/">Das Pop</a>. A couple of their songs were catchy but they seemed like quite an odd group. One of the guitar players looked a bit like Grizzly Adams, and the lead singer as well as singing was trying to play the piano, the tambourine, and sing all at the same time, which seemed a bit strange.</p>

<p>The Feeling themselves were very good. Again, I hadn&rsquo;t had a chance to listen to their second album, so a couple of the songs I didn&rsquo;t recognise, but most of them I did. At one point Dan Gillespie jumps into the outstretched arms of the audience and crowd surfed his way along to his awaiting minder, and then went to the upstairs balcony to perform a solo instrumental song. Very well done!!!</p>

<p>This was the second time that I have seen The Feeling, and would definitely go back and see them again.</p>

<p>I took some photos, and you can see them below:</p>

<p>[nggallery id=26]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oasis Concert]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/oasis-concert/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-02T18:37:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/oasis-concert</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Went to see Oasis at the Exhibition Centre last night, it was an amazing concert!!!</p>

<p>This was the first time that I had seen Oasis, and I was really looking forward to it, and they didn&rsquo;t disappoint!!! They played a few of their new songs, which unfortunately I had heard, as I haven&rsquo;t picked up the new album yet, but they also played some of their classics. Don&#8217;&rsquo;t Look Back In Anger, Champagne SuperNova, Wonderwall, I am a Walrus&hellip;</p>

<p>It was great!!!</p>

<p>Only slight downer on the evening was that I must have got hit by about 10 pints of what I am hoping was beer. Had to go home and have a shower after the concert!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
