<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Job | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/job/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-05T12:21:06+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Vacancy: Evoke IT, Aberdeen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/job-vacancy-evoke-it-aberdeen/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-20T18:02:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/job-vacancy-evoke-it-aberdeen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Through the Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group I have been informed about a job opportunity with a local Aberdeen start-up. If you are interested in the position, please contact info at evokeit dot com (replace the at and dot with @ and . respectively. Trying to stop those nasty spiders getting the email address. Details of the job are as follows:</p>

<blockquote>  
> 
> **Evoke IT**
> 
>    
> 
> ****
> 
>    
> 
> Set up in 2011, and based in Aberdeen city centre, Evoke IT is a Microsoft SharePoint consultancy and application development company. Microsoft SharePoint is experiencing phenomenal global growth, and Evoke IT is ideally placed to service the increasing demand through its enthusiastic team with a wealth of industry and technical experience.        
To help provide the highest quality service to our rapidly expanding customer base, we are looking for a new team member.
> 
>    
> 
> **Job Overview**
> 
>    
> 
> ****
> 
>    
> 
> **C# .NET Web Application Developer**
> 
>    
> 
> C# .NET Application Developer required with an excellent background and experience in creating enterprise web applications in .NET framework 3.5.
> 
>    
> 
> The right candidate will work well within a team and have the ability to manage their own workload in terms of ownership and the ability to deliver assigned tasks on time. 
> 
>    
> 
> They will have initiative and the ability to understand and interpret design specifications.
> 
>    
> 
> They must have the knowledge to debug across multiple technologies including Windows Server, Active Directory, IIS and web applications.
> 
>    
> 
> They must always be actively updating their Microsoft Certifications and have a passion to learn new and emerging technologies.
> 
>    
> 
> This is an excellent opportunity to work with cutting edge Microsoft Technologies.
> 
>    
> 
> **Requirements**
> 
>    
> 
>     
>   * Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS) in c# .NET web development 
>      
>   * Excellent knowledge and experience of C# .NET Framework 3.5/4.0 
>      
>   * Excellent knowledge and experience of ADO.NET, Microsoft SQL Server 2005 and above 
>      
>   * In depth knowledge of Microsoft development technologies including Microsoft Visual Studio 2008 and above 
>      
>   * Knowledge and experience of developing XML, Web Services and Windows Services 
>      
>   * Knowledge and experience with IIS 6 and above 
>      
>   * Knowledge and experience of developing against Windows Active Directory 
>       
> 
> **Additional Skills**
> 
>    
> 
>     
>   * Microsoft SharePoint 2010 
>      
>   * Knowledge of Microsoft Windows Workflow Foundation 
>      
>   * Knowledge of Microsoft Silverlight development 
>   </blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Vacancy: Aberdeen University]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/job-vacancy-aberdeen-university/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-30T12:21:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/job-vacancy-aberdeen-university</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group member has informed me about a job opening at the University of Aberdeen.  Details of the job are as follows:</p>

<blockquote>We wish to appoint a programmer to join the programming team within the Health Services Research Unit at the University of Aberdeen. The team provides programming support and data management for multi-centre health care randomised trials and other research studies. This will include preparing randomisation schedules, setting up databases, and programming applications for data collection and assisting with the conduct of the studies (such as monitoring recruitment and scheduling participant follow up).

You should have a relevant degree in computing with demonstrable programming experience. Experience of creating dynamic web applications using ASP.NET and C# and knowledge of database design within SQL Server (2005 or later) is essential.
It is anticipated that the project activities will be completed within 2 years of the agreed post start date. This appointment will be made subject to the usual terms and conditions of employment of the University.

Informal enquiries may be made to Gladys McPherson (tel: 01224 438176 or [g.mcpherson@abdn.ac.uk](mailto:g.mcpherson@abdn.ac.uk))

Criteria:

> 
> 
    
>   * First degree in computing or a relevant subject
> 
    
>   * Experience which demonstrates the skills and capabilities to operate at this level
> 
    
>   * Experience of creating dynamic web applications using ASP.NET
> 
    
>   * Experience of database design within SQL Server
> 
    
>   * Experience of Microsoft Office and knowledge of full software development cycle
> 
    
>   * Extensive previous experience of working in software development
> 
    
>   * The ability to work effectively within a multi-disciplinary research team
> 
    
>   * Ability to communicate software specifications clearly either orally or in writing
> 
    
>   * Ability to work on own initiative as well as possessing good administrative skills
> 
    
>   * Ability to work to deadlines
> 

</blockquote>


<p>If you are interested in this position, you should visit the University of Aberdeen Careers page by doing:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Navigate to <a href="http://www.abdn.ac.uk/jobs">www.abdn.ac.uk/jobs</a></p></li>
<li><p>Click “External Applicants”</p></li>
<li><p>Search by post ref number: 1218141 (or by “programmer”)</p></li>
</ul>


<p>The closing date for applications is 9th January 2012.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows Developer Required – Aberdeen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/windows-developer-required-e28093-aberdeen/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-21T20:49:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/windows-developer-required-e28093-aberdeen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk">ADNUGUK</a> Member has informed me about a vacancy for a Windows Developer looking for a change of career, or indeed someone wishing to create a start up and needs a business partner.</p>

<p>For the Windows Developer role, the following skills would be required.</p>

<p>Knowledge of:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Windows Folders</p></li>
<li><p>RTF Files</p></li>
<li><p>HTML</p></li>
<li><p>Outlook</p></li>
</ul>


<p>If you are interested in the position and would like some more information, then please feel free to contact Peter Gillian on pjg at skylark dot co dot uk, or you can call him on 01330 823950.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consultant Job Opportunity – Aberdeen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/consultant-job-opportunity-aberdeen/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-21T20:40:50+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/consultant-job-opportunity-aberdeen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Through <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk">ADNUGUK</a> I have been made aware about the following job opportunity in Aberdeen so I thought I would post in here in case anyone is interested.</p>

<hr />

<p>Job title: Consultant</p>

<p>Pay: Up to £40,000 + benefits</p>

<p>Location: Aberdeen</p>

<p>Work with an up-and-coming company that will give you a huge amount of opportunity and an environment where new ideas are encouraged, supported and rewarded.</p>

<p>Day-to-Day Requirements:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Software implementation and pilots</p></li>
<li><p>Modelling using VB.Net and Excel</p></li>
<li><p>Client liaison</p></li>
<li><p>Work flow solutions for clients</p></li>
<li><p>Technical support</p></li>
<li><p>Client training</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Person Required:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Experience in C#.Net or VB.Net is essential, with at least a working knowledge of SQL Server or similar database structures (Oracle etc)</p></li>
<li><p>Candidates must be amiable and keen to communicate with clients</p></li>
<li><p>Candidates should be prepared to learn about the Upstream Oil and Gas industry</p></li>
<li><p>A willingness to travel at short notice and work remotely for a couple of weeks is a must, but travel is unlikely to be very frequent</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Qualifications Required</p>

<ul>
<li>Degree qualified in a numerate or IT discipline</li>
</ul>


<p>Interested? Contact Gillies Kleboe on 0131 608 0008/07825 182 815, also <a href="mailto:gk@kleboe.co.uk">gk@kleboe.co.uk</a></p>

<p>Kleboe is an independent recruitment consultancy acting on behalf of the client. All applications are treated with complete confidentiality.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job: Aberdeen/Aberdeenshire Area]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/job-aberdeenaberdeenshire-area/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-27T19:53:40+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/job-aberdeenaberdeenshire-area</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Through the <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/">Aberdeen Developers website</a> I have been made aware of a job vacancy in the Aberdeen area.</p>

<p>The role will be as a software developer working on a brand new browser based product. In the short term, a prospective candidate would benefit from having some Delphi knowledge in order to work with some existing software. In addition, it would be beneficial if the candidate lived in the Aberdeen/Aberdeenshire area. The position would also ideally suit someone who has, or is, working on their own concept and wants to be a “start up”, and is looking for some cash injection, as this type of investment is available.</p>

<p>If you are interested in the position and would like some more information, then please feel free to contact Peter Gillian on pjg at skylark dot co dot uk, or you can call him on 01330 823950.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
