<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Adnug | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/adnug/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-11T10:51:38+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Secrets of a .Net Ninja Talk at #ADNUGUK by @KodefuGuru]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/secrets-of-a-net-ninja-talk-at-adnuguk-by-kodefuguru/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-08T06:46:56+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/secrets-of-a-net-ninja-talk-at-adnuguk-by-kodefuguru</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Thursday 7th July, the Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group was lucky enough to welcome <a href="http://www.kodefuguru.com/">Chris Eargle</a> (<a href="http://twitter.com/kodefuguru">@KodefuGuru</a>), a Telerik Developer Evangelist from Columbia, South Carolina, to do a talk entitled “<a href="http://aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/Meetings/Secrets-of-a--Net-Ninja.aspx">Secrets of a .Net Ninja</a>”.</p>

<p>Due to the format of this presentation, primarily focused around code demonstrations, there was only an introductory set of slides, so I have not posted them here.</p>

<p>However, all of the code (and much, much more) that Chris talked through on the night is available at his CodePlex Project which you can find <a href="http://kodefu.codeplex.com/">here</a>. I am in the process of downloading the latest version as I type <img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/wlEmoticon-smile.png" alt="Smile" />.</p>

<p>There was no messing around in this talk, we jumped straight into talking about:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Private Member Inheritance</p></li>
<li><p>Removing the use of Out Parameters</p></li>
<li><p>Extension Method Refactoring</p></li>
<li><p>Advanced use of LINQ, Lambdas and Anonymous Methods
There was a lot of content in this presentation, and there was certainly a lot of food for thought. The sample code helps in cementing how these techniques can be used in your day-to-day programming activities.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately I wasn’t able to go, but some of the guys took Chris to the <a href="http://www.brewdog.com/">BrewDog</a> bar for a round of <a href="http://www.brewdog.com/sink_the_bismark">Sink The Bismarck</a> after the meeting, I hope he doesn’t miss his flight back home to the states today!</p>

<p>Big thanks to Chris for taking time to visit the <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/Home.aspx">Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group</a>.</p>

<p>Don’t forget about our next event which is happening on the Thursday 21st July 2011. <a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/">Paul Stack</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/stack72">@stack72</a>), a Continuous Integration enthusiast, is travelling up to present his talk entitled “<a href="http://aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/Meetings/Beginners-Guide-to-CI.aspx">Beginners Guide to CI</a>”. I have seen this talk once before (although I know he has added some parts to it since I last saw it so interested to see what he has lined up) and I would encourage anyone who is interested in getting started with CI, or even if you are already using it, to come along.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>NOTE: </strong>As some of you may have noticed, I have switched from using the #ADNUG hash tag to using #ADNUGUK on Twitter. This is due to the fact that there was a clash with the <a href="http://www.adnug.org/">Austin Dot Net User Group</a>, as well as the <a href="http://www.adnug.com/">Adelaide Dot Net User Group</a>, so if you are ever mentioning the Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group can I ask you to use #ADNUGUK.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free TypeMock Isolator Webinar]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/free-typemock-isolator-webinar/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-22T18:59:58+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/free-typemock-isolator-webinar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In case you haven’t seen it, TypeMock are running a free Webinar entitled:</p>

<p><strong>“Test the Untestable: Tips for Easy Unit Testing”</strong></p>

<p>on the 27th June 2011 at 3 PM GMT. The link for signing up is <a href="https://www2.gotomeeting.com/register/365837051">here</a>. All going well, I am planning on attending this event, but the way work has been going, I might have to give it a miss <img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/wlEmoticon-sadsmile1.png" alt="Sad smile" /></p>

<p>TypeMock Isloator is one of the licenses that we are able to give away at the <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/">Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group</a>, so if you have already been lucky enough to win one of these licenses, this Webinar will be a great way to get started using it.</p>

<p>The agenda for the meeting is as follows:</p>

<p>• Common problems with unit testing, and how to solve them    <br/>
• Applying unit testing patterns to legacy code     <br/>
• How to test the untestable     <br/>
• Cutting fluff with Typemock Isolator’s powerful mocking capabilities     <br/>
• How to mock (fake) any dependency (SharePoint, databases, file systems)</p>

<p>One attendee will receive a free license of Typemock Isolator and one attendee will receive a free unit testing t-shirt!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Follow Up From ADNUGUK Refactoring Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/follow-up-from-adnuguk-refactoring-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-02T20:25:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/follow-up-from-adnuguk-refactoring-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Thursday 26th May, the Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group was fortunate enough to welcome <a href="http://garyshort.org/">Gary Short</a> (<a href="http://twitter.com/garyshort">@garyshort</a>) of <a href="http://www.devexpress.com/">DevExpress</a> to do a talk entitled “<a href="http://aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/Meetings/Refactoring-%E2%80%93-Everything-you-Wanted-to-Know-but-we.aspx">Refactoring – Everything you wanted to know but were afraid to ask</a>”.</p>

<p>If you were not able to attend the session you can find the slide deck from the presentation <a href="http://aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/files/Meeting-Presentations/RefactoringDeepDive.aspx">here</a>, big thanks to Gary for giving us a copy of the slide deck.</p>

<p>The presentation was very well received and I am happy to say that outside of the <a href="http://aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/Meetings/What-s-New-in-Silverlight-4-.aspx">Microsoft event</a>, which we held back in November last year, attendance was the highest that it has ever been!!</p>

<p>The User Group now has over 75 registered members, and attendance at our meetings is averaging around the 20 people mark, which is far better than I ever thought it would be an I started out in this little adventure, so I wanted to take this opportunity to say thank you to everyone who has been coming along! The User Group really would be nothing without you guys coming along!</p>

<p>As I mentioned on the night, I am planning on increasing the frequency of the meetings for the User Group. I have decided this for a number of reasons.</p>

<p>Firstly, I have had a lot of interest from speakers who would like to do talks at the User Group, and the bi-monthly cycle meant that I would have to put some speakers off until next year, which isn’t great.</p>

<p>Secondly, I think that a more regular meeting cycle keeps up the level of interest. Based on the show of hands by the attendees on the night, as well as speaking to some other Group Leaders, a regular monthly slot seems to make a lot of sense. If for some reason it doesn’t work for this User Group, then we can easily switch back.</p>

<p>Now, having just spoken about a regular monthly slot, (aiming for the 3rd Thursday of every month), I am going to have to break that rule for the first month. <img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/wlEmoticon-smile.png" alt="Smile" /></p>

<p>I was planning on starting this month, June, but the first speaker was not able to make it, and as a result, we are now going to have two meetings in July.</p>

<p>The first up is <a href="http://www.kodefuguru.com/">Chris Eargle</a> (<a href="http://twitter.com/kodefuguru">@KodefuGuru</a>), a Telerik Developer Evangelist from Columbia, South Carolina, who, while over here to do other talks in the UK, is going to stop by Aberdeen and do a talk entitled “<a href="http://aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/Meetings/Secrets-of-a--Net-Ninja.aspx">Secrets of a .Net Ninja</a>”.</p>

<p>Next up is <a href="http://paulstack.co.uk/blog/">Paul Stack</a> (<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/stack72">@stack72</a>) a Continuous Integration enthusiast, that is going to travel up to Aberdeen to do a talk entitled “<a href="http://aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/Meetings/Beginners-Guide-to-CI.aspx">Beginners Guide to CI</a>”.</p>

<p>I am very much looking forward to both of these talks, and I hope that you will be able to make it along on the night.</p>

<p><strong>NOTE: </strong>As some of you may have noticed, I have switched from using the #ADNUG hash tag to using #ADNUGUK on Twitter. This is due to the fact that there was a clash with the <a href="http://www.adnug.org/">Austin Dot Net User Group</a>, as well as the <a href="http://www.adnug.com/">Adelaide Dot Net User Group</a>, so if you are ever mentioning the Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group can I ask you to use #ADNUGUK.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First StyleCop Presentation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/my-first-stylecop-presentation/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-27T16:41:18+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/my-first-stylecop-presentation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the 24th March 2011, I gave what I am considering to be my first “proper” community presentation at the <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/Home.aspx">Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group</a> (<a href="http://twitter.com/#search?q=%23ADNUG">#ADNUG</a>). When the user group first started, I also did a presentation entitled <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/Meetings/Visual-Studio-2010---An-Introduction.aspx">“Visual Studio 2010 – An Introduction”</a>, but I regarded this as a demonstration of Visual Studio 2010, and the great tooling support that had been added to this release, rather than a full talk on a subject.</p>

<p>Enter <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/Meetings/StyleCop-Barriers-To-Entry.aspx">“StyleCop – Breaking down the barriers to entry”</a>.</p>

<p>I have been a long time advocate of StyleCop, and I was responsible for helping set this up within the development team that I am currently working in. In addition, I have been “toying” with the idea of getting into doing community speaking, and StyleCop seemed like a good entry point for this.</p>

<p>This talk was very much inspired by the excellent <a href="http://developerdeveloperdeveloper.com/ddd9/ViewSession.aspx?SessionID=525">talk</a> that I saw by <a href="http://guysmithferrier.com/">Guy Smith-Ferrier</a> when I was at DDD9 in January. However, I tried to take it a little bit further and explain the real world hurdles that stands in the way of a development team implementing StyleCop in their applications, drawing on the problems that I had personally faced in implementing StyleCop in my team.</p>

<p>On the night, I am happy to say that I think the talk went down really well, although there were a couple fumbles as I tried to remember the order that my slides were in, and the demo where I tried to debug a custom StyleCop rule using two instances of Visual Studio didn’t want to work <img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/wlEmoticon-sadsmile.png" alt="Sad smile" />. If you attended the talk, I would be very interested to hear any feedback that you have, good and bad. This is the only way in which I can get better.</p>

<p>I am also happy to say that this was the first night where I was able to give away lots of <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=107">swag</a> to the User Group members, and this will continue for the foreseeable future, with hopefully more prizes being added as we go.</p>

<p>A big thanks has to go to Emma for the lend of her hat for drawing the names for the prizes! I am going to have to sort out a proper way of doing this for the next meeting (but just in case, if you could bring your hat again, that would be great!!). If anyone has any novel ideas about how we can auction off these prizes, then feel free to let me know.</p>

<p>The slides from my presentation can be found <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/StyleCop-Breaking-down-the-barriers-to-entry.pdf">here</a>, and the demo code that I used can be found <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/StyleCop-Breaking-down-the-barriers-to-entry-Demos.zip">here</a>. If you have any questions, then please feel free to <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?page_id=38">get in touch</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
