<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: General | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-05T11:30:59+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Interesting Kindle Cover]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/an-interesting-kindle-cover/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T17:00:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/an-interesting-kindle-cover</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>DISCLAIMER:</em> I was recently approached by <a href="http://www.gearzap.com/">GearZap.com</a> to do an unbiased review of one of the products from their site.  The following is the result of that review.</p>

<p>Like most developers I know, I have a Kindle.  The ability to carry hundreds of books around with you is a great thing, and a great resource.  Gone are the days of lugging around one epic tomb of a development book, we now carry them all.  However, in order to ensure that your Kindle doesn’t get damaged, you really need to get a cover for it, and if you haven’t already got one, make sure to take a look at the great selection <a href="http://www.gearzap.com/amazon-kindle-accessories/amazon-kindle-covers.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>I was asked to do a review of the <a href="http://www.gearzap.com/tuff-luv-embrace-amazon-kindle-cover-black.html">Tuff-Luv Embrace Amazon Kindle Cover</a>, and I am happy to say that this is a really nice cover.  The unique selling point for this cover is the integrated hand-band, which makes is very easy to hold the Kindle.  The hand-band is really aimed at using your left hand, however, I found that it will also work with your right hand, although I have to say that it didn’t feel as secure when doing it this way.  While using the hand-band, you are easily able to reach the page navigation controls on your Kindle.</p>

<p>When the Kindle is seated within the cover is feels very secure, and I don’t think that I would ever be concerned that it was going to become dislodged.  All round, a nice cover, that I would happy recommend to anyone.</p>

<p>Some photos of the Kindle contained within this cover are shown below:</p>

<p>[gallery]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time to Say Goodbye to an Old Friend]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/time-to-say-goodbye-to-an-old-friend/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-02T19:42:38+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/time-to-say-goodbye-to-an-old-friend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is with a tinge of sadness, that today I had to say goodbye to an old friend. Over 6 years ago, I purchased my first car; a Silver Ford Focus Elle. I had been able to drive since passing my test when I was 17, but it wasn&rsquo;t until after finishing university that I purchased my first car. I loved this car, and I am happy to say that with the exception of having to replace a coil ignition unit, and general wear and tear, I have had no mechanical problems with my car (aside from the damage done to the car while parked outside my old flat, which included being scratched, wing mirrors kicked off, and being spray painted!!!).</p>

<p>But alas, all good things must come to an end, and today was the day that I said goodbye to &ldquo;Elle&rdquo;:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/time-to-say-goodbye-to-an-old-friend/4.-another-view-from-the-front/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/4.-Another-view-from-the-front-224x300.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>Enter the new replacement. A 6 month old Ford Focus Zetec S:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/time-to-say-goodbye-to-an-old-friend/8.-another-view-from-the-front/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/8.-Another-view-from-the-front-300x224.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>I went back to the <a href="http://www.jimreidvehiclesales.co.uk/">Jim Reid Vehicle Sales</a> which is where I bought the first car, and I got a cracking deal, both on the trade in, and with the added extras that were thrown in. If anyone in the North East is looking for a new car, definitely give Jim a shout, I am sure that he would be able to help you out.</p>

<p>I only picked up the car this lunch time, but I am already loving it. Great features include:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Bluetooth hands free kit for mobile phone</p></li>
<li><p>USB Port of connecting iPod</p></li>
<li><p>Rear parking sensors</p></li>
<li><p>Amazing body kit</p></li>
<li><p>DAB Radio</p></li>
</ul>


<p>I am sure that there will be loads more features that I come to find irreplaceable.</p>

<p>Some more photos of both cars can be seen below:</p>

<p>[gallery]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating a Google Search Shortcut for Sites]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/creating-a-google-search-shortcut-for-sites/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-31T13:19:09+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/creating-a-google-search-shortcut-for-sites</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have just read a very interesting blog post from Barry Mooring regarding using the <a href="http://webapps.stackexchange.com/">Web Applications website</a> when you have questions about a particular application. In case you missed it, you can see the blog post <a href="http://blog.codingbadger.com/blog/2012/january/web-applications-you-are-looking-in-the-wrong-place/">here</a>.</p>

<p>Barry makes a really good point about tailoring the place that you are searching for an answer to your question, to the place that will most likely have the answer to your question, rather than simply a blanket Google search. This in itself is a great idea.</p>

<p>However, there is one thing that I think is missing from Barry’s post though (sorry Barry, in no way a criticism <img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/wlEmoticon-smile5.png" alt="Smile" />), and that is first of all going to the Web Applications website to then do your search. Personally, I would prefer to set up a Custom Search Engine within Google Chrome, rather than first navigating to the site. I do this all the time for things that I find myself doing over and over again. For instance, I have a Custom Google Search Engine for <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/google-chrome-search-for-msdn/">finding information on MSDN</a> (NOTE: This blog post needs updating to the latest version of Google Chrome, but you get the idea). And the same thing can be done for Web Applications:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Custom_Google_Search.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Custom_Google_Search_thumb.png" alt="Custom_Google_Search" /></a></p>

<p>Here I have added a Search Engine with the following settings:</p>

<p>  <table cellpadding="2" cellspacing="0" border="0" width="628" ><tbody >       <tr >       <br/>
<td width="200" valign="top" >Name:
</td>        <br/>
<td width="426" valign="top" >Web Applications
</td>       </tr>        <tr >       <br/>
<td width="200" valign="top" >Keyword:
</td>        <br/>
<td width="426" valign="top" >webapp
</td>       </tr>        <tr >       <br/>
<td width="200" valign="top" >URL:
</td>        <br/>
<td width="426" valign="top" ><a href="http://webapps.stackexchange.com/search?q=%s">http://webapps.stackexchange.com/search?q=%s</a>
</td>       </tr>     </tbody></table></p>

<p>This means that in the Google Chrome Omnibox I can simply type:</p>

<blockquote>  
> 
> webapp <then the tab key> &#8220;What you want to search for” <then press the enter key>
> 
> </blockquote>


<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Web_Application_Search.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Web_Application_Search_thumb.png" alt="Web_Application_Search" /></a></p>

<p>This has the benefit of doing the search, and the navigation to the website in one action, rather than two.</p>

<p>Personally, this is a much better flow for me, and one that I use on a daily basis. I highly recommend that you sit back and look at things you are doing over and over again, and look for ways that you can optimize this.</p>

<p>For sites that don’t have a their search page available on the query string, you can use Google’s built in function to limit the search to a specific domain. For instance, over at VBForums, I can use the following Custom Search Engine:</p>

<p> <table cellpadding="2" cellspacing="0" border="0" width="817" ><tbody >     <tr >     <br/>
<td width="200" valign="top" >Name:
</td>      <br/>
<td width="615" valign="top" >VBForums
</td>     </tr>      <tr >     <br/>
<td width="200" valign="top" >Keyword:
</td>      <br/>
<td width="615" valign="top" >vbforums
</td>     </tr>      <tr >     <br/>
<td width="200" valign="top" >URL:
</td>      <br/>
<td width="615" valign="top" ><a href="http://www.google.co.uk/search?q=site:vbforums.com+%s">http://www.google.co.uk/search?q=site:vbforums.com+%s</a>
</td>     </tr>   </tbody></table></p>

<p>Hope this helps!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Merry Christmas Everyone!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/merry-christmas-everyone/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-25T13:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/merry-christmas-everyone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/51904w4lb2o5ndv.jpg"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/51904w4lb2o5ndv_thumb.jpg" alt="51904w4lb2o5ndv" /></a></p>

<p>Just wanted to wish everyone a Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year. Hopefully we will see some of your over the Christmas Period, but if not, we will catch you in 2012!</p>

<p>Gary and Lynn</p>

<p><a href="http://www.freedigitalphotos.net/images/view_photog.php?photogid=2280"><strong>Image gratefully provided by: digitalart / FreeDigitalPhotos.net</strong></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gone, but Not Forgotten…]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/gone-but-not-forgotten/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-17T15:01:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/gone-but-not-forgotten</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Dave-Susan-and-Judy.jpg"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Dave-Susan-and-Judy_thumb.jpg" alt="Dave Susan and Judy" /></a></p>

<p>Happy Birthday to my Auntie Susan and Uncle Dave, both of whom are sadly no longer with us.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
