<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Software | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/software/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-11T12:28:22+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Loupe Desktop Is Now Free]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/loupe-desktop-is-now-free/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-26T21:39:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/loupe-desktop-is-now-free</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>&hellip;that&rsquo;s right, Loupe Desktop is now free!</h1>

<p>In case you hadn&rsquo;t heard, the <a href="http://www.gibraltarsoftware.com/">Gibraltar Software</a> product <a href="http://www.gibraltarsoftware.com/See/Default.aspx">Loupe Desktop</a> is now being released completely free!  For more information about the reasons behind this decision, make sure to check out the blog post <a href="http://rocksolid.gibraltarsoftware.com/announcements/our-best-log-viewer-is-now-free">here</a>.  This announcement comes not long after the recent release of Loupe Desktop 3.5.  You can find out about all the new features <a href="http://rocksolid.gibraltarsoftware.com/loupe/new-loupe-desktop-features-in-loupe-3-5">here</a>.</p>

<p>As yet, I haven&rsquo;t had a proper chance to play with Loupe, but it is most certainly on my list of things to check out, and with it now being free, it is even more appealing!</p>

<h1>Getting Started with ASP.Net and Loupe Desktop</h1>

<p>If you are interested in finding out more about Loupe Desktop, and how it can be used, be sure to check out Gary Short&rsquo;s (<a href="https://twitter.com/garyshort">@garyshort</a>) introductory video below:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ALhL6_pQd3A">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ALhL6_pQd3A</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time Tracking Software]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/time-tracking-software/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-01T21:14:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/time-tracking-software</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago I put out a <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/gep13/status/130396530136981505">tweet</a> asking for recommendations for a piece of software for time tracking:</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/#!/gep13/status/130396530136981505"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/image.png" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p>What I got back was a wealth of options, including:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.timesnapper.com/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/image1.png" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.yast.com/timetracker/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/image2.png" alt="image" /></a><a href="https://www.rescuetime.com/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/image3.png" alt="image" /></a><a href="http://www.yanomo.com/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/image4.png" alt="image" /></a><a href="http://www.paymo.biz/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/image5.png" alt="image" /></a><a href="http://www.fanuriotimetracking.com/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/image6.png" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p>My requirements for this are quite simple. The piece of software needed to be:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Simple and non-intrusive to use</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>If it is overly complicated to use, or takes a long time to do anything with it, it defies the point what I am trying to achieve</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>It has to be free</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>I am doing this as an experiment to track various different tasks, and at the minute, I don’t want to have to fork out money. That doesn’t mean that at some point I wouldn’t transition to a paid service</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>It has to be able to provide a report on the time I have spent</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>In order to be useful, I need to be able to produce reports (in preferably multiple formats) of all the hours that I have worked on a task. Preferably, this would be selectable which regard to which projects to add to the report, which days to report on, etc.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Usable from my mobile</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>It would be good to be able to start and stop timing while on the move and not on my main machine, so having a mobile phone application would be a bonus.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Having looked at the above suggestions, it was clear that it was going to be hard to pick which one to go with. Some I ruled out straight away, based on price and features, others I actually played with before making the final decision.</p>

<p>After a couple days playing around, I decided to give <a href="http://www.yast.com/timetracker/">Yast</a> a full trial run, and I am happy to say that I am not disappointed! Yast is fully web based, there is nothing to install on your machine, a big bonus in a corporate environment.</p>

<p>Its interface is ridiculously easy to use (you can see a live demo on their home page), and it’s reporting capabilities are very good. You have the ability to report in CSV, Excel and PDF.</p>

<p>Unlike some of the other packages which track the applications that you are currently using on you computer and automatically creates time entries for you, Yast relies on you starting and stopping a timer, per task. However, I don’t mind this. I simply keep a web browser open with the Yast page open, and when I need to change task, I simply jump to the web browser, and make the switch. This is actually a useful thing, because when people come up to ask questions, I make a conscious effort to make sure that they see me stopping and starting a timer, that way they know that they are accruing time, that will ultimately get billed to their project. Even if I forget to do this, the editing mechanism is, again, incredibly simple to use.</p>

<p>Yast also comes with <a href="http://m.yast.com">http://m.yast.com</a>, which works perfectly from my Windows Phone 7, so when I am out and about, I can track my time as well.</p>

<p>All in all, I am very happy with using Yast, so much so that I am using the reports that it produces to provide information to my line manager about what I have been working on. I would very much recommend you take a look at this package if you are looking for help tracking your time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mouse Without Borders]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/mouse-without-borders/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-13T11:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/mouse-without-borders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Like most geeks, I have both a desktop PC and a laptop (if I am being honest, I also have a NetBook as well). From time to time, I will be using these at the same time. Whether it is to do the monthly virus scans and updates, or whether it is transferring files between the two, etc.</p>

<p>Before finding “<a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/next/archive/2011/09/09/microsoft-garage-download-mouse-without-borders.aspx">Mouse without Borders</a>” it was a case of switching between the keyboard and mouse of my desktop, over to the keyboard and track pad of the laptop, but no more! Now I just use the same keyboard and mouse, and I get a flawless transition between each desktop.</p>

<p>Once setup, you can position tell “<a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/next/archive/2011/09/09/microsoft-garage-download-mouse-without-borders.aspx">Mouse without Borders</a>” how you want your machines configured, I have mine setup as follows:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/image.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/image_thumb.png" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p>and there are a host of options that you can configure:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/image1.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/image_thumb1.png" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p>There are other products on the market that do a similar job, for instance <a href="http://www.inputdirector.com/">InputDirector</a>, but I have never tried this software.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Print Screen Utility]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/print-screen-utility/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-09T22:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/print-screen-utility</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was introduced to the following utility by a colleague at work:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.fiastarta.com/PrtScr/">www.fiastarta.com/PrtScr/</a></p>

<p>It is a very useful utility, that is very unobtrusive, and I can see me using it on a daily basis.</p>

<p>It basically takes over when you press the “Print Screen” key on your keyboard, and allows you to perform additional activities, such as:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>crop only a selected rectangle</p></li>
<li><p>crop only a selected area by drawing a “lasso” around the desired area</p></li>
<li><p>draw lines onto the selected area, i.e. an arrow, or some text</p></li>
<li><p>drag the highlighted area into other applications, such as Skype, MSN etc</p></li>
<li><p>open the image directly in your default image application</p></li>
<li><p>direct the image directly to an email or your clipboard</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Overall, it is very, very clever!!! And I highly recommend it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mono Binaries for RHEL No Longer Supported]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/mono-binaries-for-rhel-no-longer-supported/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-09T15:54:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/mono-binaries-for-rhel-no-longer-supported</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh no!!!!</p>

<p>I went to the Mono website after learning that 2.0 had been released all ready to download the new packages to install and test. Clicked on the download link, only to find the 1.9.1 downloads. Initially I thought that the link had just not been updated, so I emailed the Mono team to find out what was going wrong.</p>

<p>Couple days later, I checked the Mono download page again, and I saw this:</p>

<h3>Binaries for this platform have been discontinued. Builds may be available from <a href="http://www.mono-project.com/Other_Downloads">unsupported downloads</a>.</h3>

<p>There is nothing in the unsupported downloads section, so looks like I am going to have to try and figure out how to compile Mono from source. I remember trying to do this before, without much luck, still a relative new comer to the Linux world, that is why I ended up using the binaries, but am now being forced to learn how to do this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
