<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: General Web | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/general-web/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-18T09:46:52+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opening and Editing an Adobe Illustrator File Using Expression Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/opening-and-editing-an-adobe-illustrator-file-using-expression-design/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-24T19:51:36+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/opening-and-editing-an-adobe-illustrator-file-using-expression-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Open and edit a .ai file using Expression Design</h1>

<p>The other week, I needed to edit the original source files for the Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group in order to change the size of the png&rsquo;s that I use for various things (like avatar&rsquo;s, etc).  Unfortunately, these were created using Adobe Illustrator, which I don&rsquo;t have access to.  I had a hunt around, but I couldn&rsquo;t find a way to do it.  Enter Twitter&hellip;</p>

<p>The ever knowledgeable Scott Lovegrove (<a href="https://twitter.com/scottisafool">@scottisafool</a>), made a great suggestion of using Expression Design to open and edit the files.  I had thought that Expression Design was only part of the Expression Studio, which I also don&rsquo;t have, but&hellip;</p>

<h1>Expression Design is free!</h1>

<p>Although it used to only be part of the Expression Studio, Express Design is now actually free!  You can download it from <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=36180">here</a>.</p>

<h1>Opening and Editing the file</h1>

<p>This couldn&rsquo;t be simpler!  Open up Expression Design, and open the file.  Once open, you will have the option to Export the image:</p>

<p>[caption id=&ldquo;attachment_2076&rdquo; align=&ldquo;alignnone&rdquo; width=&ldquo;1171&rdquo;]<a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Expression-Design-Export-Menu.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Expression-Design-Export-Menu.png" alt="Expression Design Export Menu" /></a> Expression Design Export Menu[/caption]</p>

<p>On the next window, you will then be able to choose the output format, and also the size of the resulting image:</p>

<p>[caption id=&ldquo;attachment_2077&rdquo; align=&ldquo;alignnone&rdquo; width=&ldquo;1206&rdquo;]<a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Expression-Design-Export-Options.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Expression-Design-Export-Options.png" alt="Expression Design Export Options" /></a> Expression Design Export Options[/caption]</p>

<p>Simples!  Thanks again Scott!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Is Going on With WP Discovery?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-29T18:56:22+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>WP Discovery - Is it all a scam?</h1>

<h1>tl;dr</h1>

<p>I am happy to wait and see - but I&rsquo;ve seen no evidence to suggest it&rsquo;s <strong>NOT</strong> fake.  It all seems like an attempt to gain a large number of followers, to try to earn money.</p>

<p><strong>Update</strong></p>

<p>The WP Discovery Twitter account has now been closed as a result of legal action between Blockfall and WP Discovery.  This was WP Discovery&rsquo;s last tweet on the subject before their account was closed.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/wp_ss_20130101_0004/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/wp_ss_20130101_0004.jpg" alt="wp_ss_20130101_0004" /></a></p>

<p>So to me, it looks as though it was all a scam, and to the best of my knowledge, no Nokia Lumia&rsquo;s, or Surfaces, or anything else, was given away by WP Discovery.</p>

<h1>The full story&hellip;</h1>

<p>In case you haven&rsquo;t been following what is going on over on Twitter, there is a growing concern that the Twitter Account for WP Discovery (<a href="https://twitter.com/wp_discovery">@wp_discovery</a>) is a scam.  For the last few days, perhaps as long as a week, they have been tweeting that they have various pieces of technology to give away.  Including things like Windows Surface RT&rsquo;s, Nokia Lumia 920&rsquo;s, and HTC 8x&rsquo;s, as well as other devices.  All you have to do is follow them, and retweet their tweets, and you are in with a chance to win.</p>

<p>This type of competition on Twitter is not new, and I have been involved in several of them.  I even got a free Office 365 t-shirt from one of them.</p>

<p>However, I personally have been starting to think that these giveaways are a little bit too good to be true.  And it is not just me that thinks that this is a scam.  Tom Warren (<a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren">@tomwarren</a>), Senior Editor at the Verge, tweeted this today:</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/285021015434735616">https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/285021015434735616</a></p>

<p>It was also noted by Phil Jones (<a href="https://twitter.com/philjones88">@philjones88</a>) that the photo of the Surface that are being given away here:</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/wp_discovery/status/284824914849038336">https://twitter.com/wp_discovery/status/284824914849038336</a></p>

<p><strong>NOTE: </strong>This used to link to a full status update from WP Discovery where they were showing two Windows Surface RT&rsquo;s that they were going to be &ldquo;giving away&rdquo;.  This image in question looked like this:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/surfaces_to_give_away/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Surfaces_to_give_away.png" alt="Surfaces_to_give_away" /></a></p>

<p>is exactly the same as the Surfaces that are being sold in this <a href="http://www.ebay.com/itm/NEW-SEALED-MICROSOFT-SURFACE-32GB-WINDOWS-8-RT-BLACK-TOUCH-COVER-BUNDLE-/121007189503">eBay auction</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/ebay_auction_for_surfaces/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Ebay_auction_for_Surfaces.png" alt="Ebay_auction_for_Surfaces" /></a></p>

<p>Now, you could argue that both decided to use the same picture, but surely, if you had a Surface to give away, right in front of you, you would take a picture of the actual devices, right?  WP Discovery later suggested that this is where they had purchased the Surfaces that they were going to be giving away, that is why the pictures were the same.</p>

<p>My suspicions were made even greater when I actually received a DM from WP Discovery.  In the space of 5-10 minutes, I received 3 DM&rsquo;s from them.  They went as follows:</p>

<p>DM Number 1:</p>

<blockquote>Hi. Ready four your DM? :)</blockquote>


<p>DM Number 2:</p>

<blockquote>Please reply in 2min. Since our script runs by itself to choose another winner instead. It&#8217;s your Surface man!</blockquote>


<p>DM Number 3:</p>

<blockquote>Sorry. You did not respond. We are picking a new one now</blockquote>


<p>(NOTE: You will see a screenshot of these DM&rsquo;s below in the gallery)</p>

<p>Now, I don&rsquo;t know about you, but I don&rsquo;t spend every waking minute on Twitter, and notifications from the Windows Phone application that I use takes a while to come through,  so needless to say, I wasn&rsquo;t able to reply within 2 minutes.  I am not sure that anyone would be able to.  Now, you could argue that this was just my bad luck, and good luck to the next guy, but if this were a legitimate competition then surely the DM that I sent back in response would have been answered.  However, it has now been over 6 hours since I DM&#8217;ed them, and I have not had any response from them.</p>

<p>What are your thoughts?  Let me know in the comments below.</p>

<p>I am still tempted to give these guys the benefit of the doubt, but when you see unanswered tweets like this from Scott Hanselman (<a href="https://twitter.com/shanselman">@shanselman</a>)</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/shanselman/status/285080261434175489">https://twitter.com/shanselman/status/285080261434175489</a></p>

<p>you have to wonder what is going on.  If there were just some more visibility about what is going on, and what the &ldquo;rules&rdquo; of the giveaway are, then I think that a lot more people would be willing to believe that this is on the &ldquo;up and up&rdquo;.</p>

<h1>Where to get help</h1>

<p>If you are in a position where you have handed over personal information, and you are worried what will happen to it, there are some places that you can go.  Here are a list of the ones that I know about, and I will update this list as I become aware of others:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://econsumer.gov/">International Consumer Protection and Enforcement Network</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.ic3.gov/default.aspx">Internet Crime Complaint Center (IC3)</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>And of course, you can also block and mark the WP Discovery account.  This will raise the problem with Twitter themselves, and push them to investigate the problem.</p>

<p>Also, take a look at this <a href="http://www.craigmurphy.com/blog/?p=5586">blog post</a> from Craig Murphy, it has some tips on what to look for if something sounds to good to be true!</p>

<h1>Other Bloggers</h1>

<p>Other people who are covering this story can be found here:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://unleashthephones.com/2012/12/30/editorial-lies-damned-lies-and-the-promise-of-free-gadgets/">Editorial: Lies, Damned Lies, and the Promise of Free Gadgets</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://landoftechnology.com/2012/rising-awareness-the-great-wp_discovery-giveaway/">Raising Awareness: The Great @wp_discovery Giveaway</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://stopmalvertising.com/spam-scams/warning-the-great-wp_discovery-giveaway.html">Warning: The Great @wp_discovery Giveaway</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.craigmurphy.com/blog/?p=5586">Free stuff: If it sounds too good to be true&hellip;</a></p></li>
</ul>


<h1>Update 1</h1>

<p>Just read a great article on <a href="http://unleashthephones.com/">Unleash The Phones</a> about why WP Discovery exhibit all the traits of a scam giveaway.  Check it out <a href="http://unleashthephones.com/2012/12/30/editorial-lies-damned-lies-and-the-promise-of-free-gadgets/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+ZomgItsCj+%28UnleashThePhones+-+Mobile+Phone+News%2C+Reviews+and+More%29">here</a>.</p>

<p>Also, remember to check out the comments below for some interesting addendum&#8217;s from the guys at WP Discovery.</p>

<h1>Update 2</h1>

<p>Since writing this blog post, I have been contacted by both WP Discovery, and by <a href="http://areon-development.de/">Areon Development</a>, the company behind the BlockFall game ( a game that WP Discovery seemed to be promoting).  They would like to make it clear that they are in no way connected to WP Discovery, and any promoting of Blockfall done by WP Discovery was done without the knowledge of Areon.  Areon Development have just posted a new blog onto their site, which you can find <a href="http://areon-development.de/?p=183">here</a>.  It reiterates that they are completely independent.</p>

<h1>Update 3</h1>

<p>Seems like last night was a busy night for WP Discovery.  They decided to ask all of their followers to ask them any questions that they might have about the competition.  This led to a number of questions about how it all works, what&rsquo;s involved, etc.  WP Discovery seemed to try to answer all of these questions (including some from me) and their answers didn&rsquo;t do anything to alleviate my concerns.  Some of their responses, and actions, were nothing if not outright rude.  I have begun capturing some screenshots of these conversations, as WP Discovery have a habit of deleting tweets.  If you have any screenshots that you would like to add to this gallery, then feel free to get in touch.</p>

<p>As requested in the comments below, you will see a screenshot of the DM&rsquo;s that I received from WP Discovery.  This was actually quite hard to find.  They no longer exist on the Twitter Website when I log in.  I can only assume that this is a result of WP Discovery blocking me, or something like this.  Lucky, I had them on my phone, which has a local cache of all the items that I have downloaded.</p>

<h1>Update 4</h1>

<p>Looks like a new Twitter account has been created called WP Discovery is Fake, you can find it <a href="https://twitter.com/WPDiscoveryFAKE">here</a>.  For the record, I had nothing to do with setting up this account.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/2012-12-31_2017/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/2012-12-31_2017.png" alt="2012-12-31_2017" /></a></p>

<h1>Update 5</h1>

<p>Thanks to Jesse Leskinen (<a href="https://twitter.com/jessenic">@jessenic</a>), I have just been given some screenshots to a DM exchange between him and WP Discovery.  This exchange shows Jesse actually winning the prize, but then WP Discovery backing out.  Check out these screenshots in the gallery below.  This is looking more and more like a scam.  Let me know what you think.</p>

<h1>Update 6</h1>

<p>Thanks to Miguel Avila (<a href="https://twitter.com/iMusice">@iMusice</a>) we have another DM conversation where WP Discovery have backed out of giving prizes.  Keep them coming! The more evidence that can be collected the better.</p>

<h1>Update 7</h1>

<p>Looks like there is now another &ldquo;parody&rdquo; account for WP Discovery been created.  This time in the form of George Patel (<a href="https://twitter.com/wp_discovery_pr">@wp_discovery_pr</a>).  The profile image and logo for the account are very similar to those of WP Discovery, but it does clearly say in the profile for the account that it is a parody account.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/2012-12-31_1450/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/2012-12-31_1450.png" alt="2012-12-31_1450" /></a></p>

<h1>Update 8</h1>

<p>I have just added another screenshot which confirms that WP Discovery were in fact following Jenna Kelly, which is something that they out right denied.  If nothing else, this proves that they are not honest.</p>

<h1>Update 9</h1>

<p>Yet another screenshot added, this time from Jeff Dunn (<a href="https://twitter.com/Jeff_Dunn">@Jeff_Dunn</a>).  More evidence of WP Discovery trying to gather positive ratings and feedback for applications in the Marketplace.</p>

<h1>Update 10</h1>

<p>Seems like another spoof account of WP Discovery has now popped up, this time in the form of WP Discovery (<a href="https://twitter.com/wp_discovery_">@wp_discovery_</a>), notice the extra underscore at the end of the name.  They have clearly identified themselves as a &ldquo;parody&rdquo; account, but just be careful, as looking at their feed, they seem to be taking the &ldquo;mick&rdquo; but some comments are dubious.  I would personally advise that you stay away from this account.  Again, for the record, I had nothing to do with setting up this account.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/2012-12-31_2007/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/2012-12-31_2007.png" alt="2012-12-31_2007" /></a></p>

<h1>Update 11</h1>

<p>I have added some links that I have seen in both the comments below, and on Twitter to where you can get help if you have inadvertently given out your personal information.  If anyone knows of additional sites to give to people, let me know and I will get them added to the main body of the blog post.</p>

<h1>Update 12</h1>

<p>Looks like more people are becoming aware of this issue.  Kimberly, over at <a href="http://stopmalvertising.com/">StopMalvertising</a> at written an excellent blog post of this topic.  You can find it <a href="http://stopmalvertising.com/spam-scams/warning-the-great-wp_discovery-giveaway.html">here</a>.  I have also added this to the list of bloggers in the main blog post.  I would strongly recommend that you add StopMalvertising to your RSS Feed Reader of choice, lots of interesting information there!</p>

<h1>Update 13</h1>

<p>WP Discovery decided that they should take it upon themselves to warm people about the &ldquo;other&rdquo; fake accounts associated with WP Discovery.  I laughed out loud (lol&#8217;ed for all you cool kids) when I first saw this!</p>

<p><strong>NOTE:</strong> This screenshot was taken on Tuesday 1st January at the time shown in the screenshot, 17:02 GMT.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/p__7e89/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/P__7E89.jpg" alt="P__7E89" /></a></p>

<h1>Update 14</h1>

<p>Changes seem to be afoot..  Craig Murphy (<a href="https://twitter.com/CAMURPHY">@CAMURPHY</a>) has noticed that WP Discovery are starting to delete all the tweets from their time line.</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/CAMURPHY/status/286234160664813571">https://twitter.com/CAMURPHY/status/286234160664813571</a></p>

<p>As a result, I have had to update the text in the main blog post, as I had some links to tweets that no longer exist.</p>

<h1>Update 15</h1>

<p>After deleting all the tweets from their timeline, WP Discovery then left a single tweet on their timeline.  This Tweet changed after about 30 minutes though.  What is shown below are the two different tweets.</p>

<p><strong>NOTE:</strong> These screenshots were taken on Tuesday 1st January at the time shown in the screenshot, 22:21 and  23:10 GMT respectively</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/wp_ss_20130101_0002/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/wp_ss_20130101_0002.jpg" alt="wp_ss_20130101_0002" /></a><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/wp_ss_20130101_0004/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/wp_ss_20130101_0004.jpg" alt="wp_ss_20130101_0004" /></a>.</p>

<h1>Update 16</h1>

<p>I have created a Twitter List of all the accounts that seemed to be caught up in the WP Discovery Incident.  NOTE: Some of these will be innocent by-standers in what WP Discovery were up to, but I have included all the ones that I was made aware of.  You can find this list <a href="https://twitter.com/gep13/wp-discovery-incident/members">here</a>.  If I have missed anyone, then please get in touch.</p>

<h1>Update 17</h1>

<p>Shortly after the above, Blockfall, the game that WP Discovery seemed to be advertising got in contact to say that they had written a <a href="http://areon-development.de/?p=191">blog post</a> on the subject.  The tweets that they sent out are shown below:</p>

<p><strong>NOTE:</strong> These screenshots were taken on Tuesday 1st January at the time shown in the screenshot, 23:12 GMT.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/wp_ss_20130101_0006/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/wp_ss_20130101_0006.jpg" alt="wp_ss_20130101_0006" /></a><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/wp_ss_20130101_0005/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/wp_ss_20130101_0005.jpg" alt="wp_ss_20130101_0005" /></a></p>

<p>These tweets linked to the <a href="http://areon-development.de/">Areon Development Website</a>, where they had created a <a href="http://areon-development.de/?p=191">blog post</a> on the topic, indicating that they had been in direct contact with WP Discovery, and had resulted in getting WP Discovery closed down.  In a short space of time, the blog post had changed slightly.  Both versions can be seen below:</p>

<h2>The Original Version</h2>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/wp_discovery_old/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/wp_discovery_old.jpg" alt="wp_discovery_old" /></a></p>

<h2>The Updated version:</h2>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/wp_discovery2/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/wp_discovery2.jpg" alt="wp_discovery2" /></a></p>

<h1>Update 18</h1>

<p>Craig Murphy (<a href="https://twitter.com/CAMURPHY">@CAMURPHY</a>) has written an excellent blog post on the subject of WP Discovery, focusing on what has happened, and what you can do to prevent yourself getting caught up in something like this again.  I recommend that you take a look at it.  You can find it <a href="http://www.craigmurphy.com/blog/?p=5586">here</a>.</p>

<h1>Update 19</h1>

<p>People seem to be getting the message.  I am happy to say that the number of followers that WP Discovery have seems to be finally going down.  See the following two screenshots:</p>

<p><strong>NOTE:</strong> These screenshots were taken on Tuesday 1st January at the time shown in the screenshot, 23:25 and  23:37 GMT respectively</p>

<h1><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/wp_ss_20130101_0007/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/wp_ss_20130101_0007.jpg" alt="wp_ss_20130101_0007" /></a><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/wp_ss_20130101_0008/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/wp_ss_20130101_0008.jpg" alt="wp_ss_20130101_0008" /></a></h1>

<h1></h1>

<p>Remember, at one point, WP Discovery had over 10000 followers.  Within the 12 minutes that elapsed in the screenshots above, WP Discovery also stopped following the 40 people that they had been following.</p>

<h1>Update 20</h1>

<p>Blockfall seem to have been very busy, they have posted to a PDF in which they show the communication history between themselves and WP Discovery.  They tweeted the existence of this PDF here:</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/Blockfall/status/286263981256105984">https://twitter.com/Blockfall/status/286263981256105984</a></p>

<p>In case this tweet goes away (Blockfall suggested already that they may delete it to stop spambots, you can see it here:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/2013-01-02_1156/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/2013-01-02_1156.png" alt="2013-01-02_1156" /></a></p>

<p>The linked PDF can be found <a href="http://areon-development.de/press/AREON_LD00131.pdf">here</a>.</p>

<h1>Update 21</h1>

<p>I am VERY happy to announce that the WP Discovery Twitter account has now been closed!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/what-is-going-on-with-wp-discovery/2013-01-02_1133/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/2013-01-02_1133.png" alt="2013-01-02_1133" /></a></p>

<h1>Collection of screenshots of WP Discovery activity</h1>

<p>[gallery ids=&ldquo;1651,1650,1646,1680,1647,1648,1649,1664,1665,1666,1667,1669,1671,1663,1672,1683&rdquo;]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use the Cloud9 Online IDE to Hack on WordPress]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/use-the-cloud9-online-ide-to-hack-on-wordpress/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-31T20:37:23+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/use-the-cloud9-online-ide-to-hack-on-wordpress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As some of you may know, I have been <em>hacking</em> on this WordPress blog site recently.  The decision to &ldquo;improve&rdquo; this site has really come from the realisation that WordPress is actually very good at what it does, and I am going to <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/continue-using-wordpress-or-not/">continue using it for the foreseeable future</a>.  With that in mind, there were a few things that were annoying me about the site, so I started digging around the innards of WordPress to figure out what could be changed, and more importantly, how to do it.  To start with, this was done using the always useful FTP application, <a href="http://filezilla-project.org/">FileZilla</a>.  I would download a .php file locally, make some changes to it, and then upload it again.  This cycle repeated for a few iterations, until I realised that there <em>must</em> be a better way to do this!</p>

<h1>Using the WordPress Editor</h1>

<p>Now, WordPress comes with its own built-in file editor, which gives you the ability to edit individual files.  This can be pretty much any file within WordPress, be it, plugins, themes, script files, etc.  However, the editor itself is very basic, and I quickly became annoyed at using it:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/WordPress_Editor.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/WordPress_Editor_thumb.png" alt="WordPress_Editor" /></a></p>

<h1>Using an Online IDE</h1>

<p>Then I remembered about a conversation had with Phil Leggetter (<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/leggetter">@leggetter</a>) and Daniel Elliot (<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/agileguy">@agileguy</a>) while I was at <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/my-impressions-of-givecampuk/">GiveCamp UK</a> last year, and the idea of using an online IDE to do the work started to become more appealing.  This would mean that I could &ldquo;hack&rdquo; on the files directly from within the browser, but still get the added benefits, such as syntax highlighting.  A quick search, and it turns out that there are lots of online IDE&rsquo;s out there.  Here are some of the ones that I tried out:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://coderun.com/ide/">coderun</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://shiftedit.net/">ShiftEdit</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://codeanywhere.net/">codeanywhere</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://c9.io/">Cloud9 IDE</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>The requirements for what I wanted were quite simple:</p>

<ol>
<li><p> Be free (yes, I am a cheap skate, but for now, what I need to use it for doesn&rsquo;t warrant paying for the service)</p></li>
<li><p> Allow editing of files on a FTP Server</p></li>
<li><p> Syntax Highlighting</p></li>
<li><p> Allow private projects</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Due to requirement 1 <a href="http://coderun.com/ide/">coderun</a> was not able to be used.  Don&rsquo;t get me wrong, this is a GREAT application, and if I was looking to code full-blown ASP.Net applications in the cloud, this would definitely be one of the go to applications.  That left three applications to whittle down.</p>

<p>Although it claims to be able to do it, I couldn&rsquo;t get <a href="https://codeanywhere.net/">codeanywhere</a> to connect to my FTP Server (and this wasn&rsquo;t for want of trying) so I gave up on using that.  That left <a href="http://shiftedit.net/">ShiftEdit</a> and <a href="http://c9.io/">Cloud9 IDE</a>.</p>

<p>I played with both of these, on and off, while I was doing my hacking, and I have to say that they are both very good.  Both are free (depending on what you want to do with them), and I found it hard to choose between them.  After a good bit of consideration, I have decided to continue using <a href="http://c9.io/">Cloud9 IDE</a>.  This was for a couple of reasons:</p>

<ol>
<li><p> Although <a href="http://shiftedit.net/">ShiftEdit</a> is free (for what I wanted to do) it didn&rsquo;t offer SSL access, which was a bit of a downer</p></li>
<li><p> <a href="http://c9.io/">Cloud9 IDE</a> seems to be under far more active development, with exciting recent announcements about <a href="http://cloud9ide.posterous.com/windows-azure-on-cloud9">Azure integration</a></p></li>
</ol>


<p>One thing I should note about <a href="http://c9.io/">Cloud9 IDE</a>, is that in order to secure access to your projects you normally need to purchase the premium subscription, i.e:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Create_New_Project.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Create_New_Project_thumb.png" alt="Create_New_Project" /></a></p>

<p>However, when it comes to FTP projects, it is only you that gets access:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Create_New_Project_-_FTP.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Create_New_Project_-_FTP_thumb.png" alt="Create_New_Project_-_FTP" /></a></p>

<p>Now, I have to admit that other people getting access to my FTP Server was something that I was worried about, and I wanted to test to make sure that it wasn&rsquo;t publicly accessible.  To test this I sent a DM on Twitter to Phil Leggetter and asked him to try to get in, and this is what he was met with:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/denied-access.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/denied-access_thumb.png" alt="denied access" /></a></p>

<p>However, what is interesting, is that you &ldquo;can&rdquo; grant access to users through the <a href="http://c9.io/">Cloud9 IDE</a> dashboard, once they request access, which is a really nice touch:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Cloud9_Dashboard.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Cloud9_Dashboard_thumb.png" alt="Cloud9_Dashboard" /></a></p>

<p>Sorry Phil, I denied your request to join the project :).</p>

<p>All in all, this is a VERY polished application, and I would highly recommend checking it out.  The GitHub and BitBucket integration is seamless, and <em>just</em> works!  Make sure you check it out.</p>

<p>If you are interested in checking out the result of my <em>hacking </em>I have uploaded my changes to my GitHub site <a href="https://github.com/gep13/NowReadingReloaded13">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Websites Are Now Being Blacked Out]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/websites-are-now-blacked-out/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-18T07:05:27+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/websites-are-now-blacked-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In case you haven’t heard, there are a number of websites/companies that have decided to black out their web pages today. This is in order to join the protest against the U.S. Congress legislation which is being proposed called SOPA, or Stop Online Piracy Act. You can find out more information about SOPA <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stop_Online_Piracy_Act">here</a> (which strangely enough is a Wikipedia page, so obviously, not all of their pages are going dark).</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page"><strong>Wikipedia</strong></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/wikipedia.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/wikipedia_thumb.png" alt="wikipedia" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://wordpress.org/"><strong>WordPress</strong></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/wordpress.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/wordpress_thumb.png" alt="wordpress" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://oreilly.com/"><strong>O’Reilly</strong></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/oreilly.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/oreilly_thumb.png" alt="oreilly" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.reddit.com/"><strong>reddit</strong></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/reddit.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/reddit_thumb.png" alt="reddit" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://icanhascheezburger.com/"><strong>icanhascheezburger</strong></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/icanhascheezburger.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/icanhascheezburger_thumb.png" alt="icanhascheezburger" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://twitpic.com/"><strong>twitpic</strong></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/twitpic.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/twitpic_thumb.png" alt="twitpic" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.minecraft.net/"><strong>Minecraft</strong></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/minecraft.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/minecraft_thumb.png" alt="minecraft" /></a></p>

<p><strong><a href="http://www.wired.com/">wired</a></strong></p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/wired.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/wired_thumb.png" alt="wired" /></a></p>

<p>There are a number of other well known companies that are against SOPA. You can find a list <a href="http://mashable.com/2012/01/17/sopa-companies-dark-list/">here</a>. However, there are just as many companies that are in favour of SOPA, and you can find them <a href="http://theoriesofconspiracy.com/2011/11/list-of-major-companies-supporting-sopa.htm">here</a>.</p>

<p>If you also don’t agree with SOPA you can join the protest <a href="http://sopastrike.com/strike/">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calling All Scottish Mountain Bikers]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/calling-all-scottish-mountain-bikers/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-17T11:59:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/calling-all-scottish-mountain-bikers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A friend of mine has started a new website dedicated to Mountain Biking in Scotland.  The site is called MTB Trails, and you can find it <a href="http://www.mtbtrails.info/">here</a>.  Full information about what the site is for, and it’s objectives can be found <a href="http://www.mtbtrails.info/About.aspx">here</a>.</p>

<p>If you are at all interested in Mountain Biking, I would highly recommend that you check it out!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.mtbtrails.info/Default.aspx"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image_thumb.png" alt="image" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
