<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Conferences | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/conferences/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-02T21:24:11+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slides and Code From Continuous Integration 101 Talk at DunDDD]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-code-continuous-integration-101-talk-dunddd/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-02T22:08:13+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-code-continuous-integration-101-talk-dunddd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Continuous Integration 101</h1>

<p>On Saturday 23rd November 2013, I presented a talk entitled &ldquo;Continuous Integration 101&rdquo; at the <a href="http://dun.dddscotland.com/">DunDDD Conference in Dundee</a>.  The abstract for the talk was as follows:</p>

<blockquote>It is well understood that &#8220;Continuous Integration&#8221; is a development best practice, however, it is also something that is not often implemented within development teams. Typical reasons include:

- It is difficult to set up
- It is difficult to maintain
- It takes too long

In this session we will look at how you can incrementally work your way to fully implementing Continuous Integration into your development process. This talk will focus on using TeamCity as the Continuous Integration Server and psake build engine.</blockquote>


<p>Overall, I was quite happy with how the talk went, and it seems to go down quite well.  There was a fair bit of interaction with the audience, with several questions, which I hope that I was able to answer.  If there are any follow-up questions, then please feel free to get in touch, and I will do my best to respond.</p>

<h1>slides and code</h1>

<p>If you are interested in seeing the slides from the talk, you can find them displayed below, and also available as a download link on this post.</p>

<p>[slideshare id=28819037&amp;doc=continuousintegration101-131202154042-phpapp02]</p>

<p>If you want to check out what little code was used during the presentation, you can find it <a href="http://gep13.me/CIDemos">here</a>.</p>

<p>[wpdm_file id=2]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Registration for DunDDD 2013 Is Now Open]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-dunddd-2013-now-open/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-14T20:18:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-dunddd-2013-now-open</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Grab your ticket for DunDDD quickly so you don&rsquo;t miss out!</h1>

<p>The call for speakers at the Scottish Community Event (organised by the <a href="http://scottishdevelopers.com/">Scottish Developers</a>) known as <a href="http://dun.dddscotland.co.uk/speaker">DunDDD </a>has now closed and the registration has opened.</p>

<h1>DunDDD is now in its third year</h1>

<p>This will be the 3rd DunDDD, built on the popular foundation of the Developer! Developer! Developer! conference series which has spread to all corners of the UK and the international arena.  DDD conferences are community-run days where passionate and enthusiastic people come together to learn, share ideas, and to network within the many hubs of the development community. Best of all DDD events are <strong>free</strong> to everyone!</p>

<p>This year DunDDD will be featuring an entire track dedicated to Data Science.</p>

<p>Go and grab your <a href="http://dun.dddscotland.co.uk/registration">ticket now</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Lights 2013 Conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/northern-lights-2013-conference/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-05T21:22:44+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/northern-lights-2013-conference</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Get your tickets now!</h1>

<p>I wanted to let you know about an upcoming event in Aberdeen that I have been helping to arrange. It is taking place on Friday 18th October 2013.  The event in question is the Northern Lights 2013 Conference.  The website for the conference can be found here:</p>

<p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/">http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/</a></p>

<p>The event is in its third year, and this year the theme is tools.  Both the tools that we use, and the tools we build.  There is a wide range of speakers available, including:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/hadi-hariri.html">Hadi Hariri</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/kendall-miller.html">Kendall Miller</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/24/sarah-drummond.html">Sarah Drummond</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/kate-stone.html">Kate Stone</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/10/02/maria-gutierrez.html">Maria Gutierrez</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/niall-merrigan.html">Niall Merrigan</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/glenn-henriksen.html">Glenn Hendrickson</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>Who are offering up an exciting line up of talks.</p>

<p>In addition, there will be two open spaces at the conference, where attendees will have an opportunity to suggest a topic for an interactive conversation with other attendees and speakers.  If you haven’t been to an open space before, they are fantastic.  It is a perfect opportunity to interact with other like mind people about a topic that you are interested in.  The best way to get something out of this is to suggest a topic that you are especially interested in, and hopefully other people will get involved as well.</p>

<p>Tickets are £15 for the day, which includes coffee and lunch for regular attendees, and Students tickets to the talks are free, plus you can buy a lunch ticket for £5.</p>

<p>We hope to see you there.  If you have any questions about the event, then please don’t hesitate to get in touch with me.</p>

<p>If you know anyone else who would be interested in attending this event, I would really appreciate it if you could forward on this email.</p>

<p>This event is lovingly sponsored by:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>University of Aberdeen -  <a href="http://www.abdn.ac.uk">http://www.abdn.ac.uk/</a></p></li>
<li><p>Neo - <a href="http://www.neo.com">http://www.neo.com</a></p></li>
<li><p>Fifth Ring - <a href="http://www.fifthring.com">http://www.fifthring.com</a></p></li>
<li><p>Codify - <a href="http://www.codify.ltd.uk">http://www.codify.ltd.uk</a></p></li>
<li><p>Arnold Clark - <a href="http://www.arnoldclark.com">http://www.arnoldclark.com</a></p></li>
<li><p>AAA - <a href="http://www.aaajobs.co.uk">http://aaajobs.co.uk</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review of DevOpsDays London 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/review-of-devopsdays-london-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-16T22:06:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/review-of-devopsdays-london-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>DevOpsDays has now finished, but had a great time&hellip;</h1>

<p>In a change to the normal Developer Conferences that I attend, I have just finished up at the <a href="http://devopsdays.org/">DevOpsDays </a>London Conference.  More and more I have hearing about how you can better improve the deployment of applications and software by closely combining both the Developer and Operations teams.  This is a relatively new idea to me, and I was very interested to hear, from people who have done this, what can be achieved!</p>

<p>This was a very &ldquo;different&rdquo; conference to what I have attended in the past, but in this case, &ldquo;different&rdquo; is a good thing!  The format was similar, in the sense that there were prepared session on each morning from various speakers, but each afternoon was given over to Open Spaces (more on this below).  I had never been to an Open Space session before, and I was very intrigued.  Turns out they are a GREAT way to learn!  In addition, just before lunch time, there were a series of Ingite talks (again, more on these below).</p>

<p>Overall, I got a lot from this conference.  After two days of hearing what can be done in terms of Configuration Management, Automated Deployments, Team Collaboration, my mind is buzzing with how some of these principles can be taken back to the office.  As to how many we will be able to implement, that is another question, but the fact that I now know that some of them exist, is half the battle!</p>

<p>What follows are some rough notes taken across the duration of the two days.</p>

<h1>Prepared Sessions</h1>

<p>In total, across the two days, there were seven prepared sessions.  Details on these can be seen below:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Niek Bartholomeus</p>

<ul>
<li><p><em>&ldquo;DevOps for Dinosaurs&rdquo;</em></p></li>
<li><p>This was a really great introduction to what DevOps is, and what it is trying to achieve.  The talk centered around the work that Niek had done in a company that he worked at to bring DevOps processed into being.  It was really great to hear the experiences from someone who had been through the process.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://speakerdeck.com/niekbartho/devops-for-dinosaurs">Slides</a></p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>John Clapham</p>

<ul>
<li><p><em>&ldquo;Checking DevOps Vital Signs&rdquo;</em></p></li>
<li><p>In this talk, John explained how in applying DevOps to his organisation, they attempted to garner some metrics so that they could accurately &ldquo;measure&rdquo; how it was helping.  This is a big stumbling block for DevOps.  i.e. how do you prove that the system is working, and actually providing value.  They chose to do this by measuring several vital signs (Cycle Time, Shared Purpose, Motivation, Collaboration, Effectiveness).  The first is reasonably simple to measure, but the others not so much.  They opted to collect this information in the form of a questionnaire.</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>David Mytton</p>

<ul>
<li><p><em>&ldquo;StartOps: Growing an Ops Team from 1 founder&rdquo;</em></p></li>
<li><p>Again, another interesting session, where David explained the decisions that he had taken in establishing his business.  He was in a position where he had to be pragmatic in adopting the tools and processes that he did.  As the company grew, he was able to adopt different tools and services, to ensure that the company was heading in the right direction.</p></li>
<li><p>Slides will appear <a href="http://blog.serverdensity.com/">here</a></p></li>
<li><p>Some interesting posts <a href="http://www.serverdensity.com/devopsdays/">here</a></p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Deri Jones</p>

<ul>
<li><em>&ldquo;Adding Business Metrics&rdquo;</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Thomas Falkenberg and Nils Probson</p>

<ul>
<li><p><em>&ldquo;DevOps and the traditional Enterprise IT&rdquo;</em></p></li>
<li><p>A very open, and honest, discussion of how the team at Payback had slowly, over the period of two years, implemented a culture of DevOps.  They found that they are now in a position where Dev and Ops teams have common goals.  However, this can only be achieved by:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Working together</p></li>
<li><p>One step at a time</p></li>
<li><p>Change takes time and patience</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>An important takeaway from this talk &ldquo;The term DevOps helped form a common language, a mantra.  i.e. if the business has a problem, then the company, both the Dev and Ops, need to work together to fix the issue</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Sam Eaton</p>

<ul>
<li><p><em>&ldquo;DevOps and the hell of a Thousand Different Platforms&rdquo;</em></p></li>
<li><p>This was an amazing talk!  Sam is clearly enthusiastic about this topic, and this flowed through in his talk.  I later found out that this was his first public talk, which certainly didn&rsquo;t show!  He had some very interesting ideas, the best of which was the &ldquo;FailCake&rdquo;.  Basically, in collaborating between Dev and Ops, it is &ldquo;ok&rdquo; to make mistakes, but these have to be discussed immediately within the team, without associating blame.  They best way they have found to do this is by bringing cake to the meetings!</p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Gene Kim</p>

<ul>
<li><p>&ldquo;How can we better sell DevOps&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>This was a VERY inspiring session.  Gene Kim, an author of the hugely popular &ldquo;The Phoenix Project&rdquo; book, explained how to best sell DevOps within the enterprise.  I would highly encourage you to take a look at the slides linked below as they explain, in detail, the barriers that exist Dev and Ops team, and how they are perceived from either side.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/realgenekim/how-can-we-better-sell-devops/">Slides</a></p></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h1>Open Spaces</h1>

<p>For me, this was the stand out part of the conference.  I had never been to an Open Space before this conference, but I will definitely be looking to attend others.  I am also going to suggest that this is something that we should be looking to include within DDD events.</p>

<p>The format is reasonably simple.  Anyone can suggest a topic to be discussed in an Open Space.  This can be asking for an answer to a question.  Providing a demonstration of a piece of software, or technology.  Pretty much anything.</p>

<p>With the sessions proposed, these are then organised &ldquo;roughly&rdquo; into order, and people &ldquo;vote&rdquo; with their feet, and go to the sessions that interest them.  This then takes the form of an open discussion, where anyone is free to talk, ask questions, and provide input.</p>

<p>We were told that Open Spaces follow three main principles:</p>

<pre><code>* Whenever it starts is the right time


* Whatever happens is the only thing that could have


* It's over when it's over
</code></pre>

<p>All I can say is&hellip;</p>

<p>Amazing!  I got so much out of these sessions.  So many snippets of information, and suggestions.</p>

<h1>Ignites</h1>

<p>Before attending DevOpsDays, I hadn&rsquo;t heard of Ignites.  Turns out this form of talks (which were held on both days just before lunch time) are similar to the 20 x 20 talks that I have seen at DDD events.  Basically, there are a set number of slides, each of which are timed to automatically transition to the next slide.  The speaker has to keep up with each transition, as they can&rsquo;t go back to a previous slide.  Topics here ranged from a custom-built tool for automatic deployments to being conscious of the server farms that you are using and their carbon footprint.</p>

<p>Well done to everyone who was brave enough to do one of these Ignites, I still think the format is very difficult, and I wouldn&rsquo;t like to do one myself.</p>

<p>Some of the slides that I am aware of from these Ignites can be found here:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/jedi4ever/what-ifconfigmgtwasdesignedbygamers">What If Config Management - Patrick Debois</a></li>
</ul>


<h1>Recommendations</h1>

<p>During the various sessions, and Open Spaces, there were a number of recommendations made.  These included blogs, podcasts, books, etc.  I have captured the ones that I could below.  If I have missed anything, or if there are any that you would like to add, please feel free to get in touch.</p>

<h1>Newsletters</h1>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://devopsweekly.com/">DevOps Weekly</a></li>
</ul>


<h1>IRC Channels and Application Recommendations</h1>

<ul>
<li><p>&ldquo;<a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23infra&amp;src=hash">##<strong>infra</strong></a>-talk&rdquo; - DevOps IRC Channel</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.irssi.org/">irssi</a> - Windows IRC Client</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.irccloud.com/">IRCCloud</a> - Web Based IRC Client</p></li>
</ul>


<h1>Book Recommendations</h1>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/The-Phoenix-Project-Business-ebook/dp/B00AZRBLHO/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363461035&amp;sr=1-1">The Phoenix Project</a></p>

<ul>
<li>You can get a free 170 page excerpt <a href="http://www.instantcustomer.com/go/83330">here</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/DevOps-Developers-Michael-xfc-ttermann/dp/1430245697/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363460874&amp;sr=1-1">DevOps for Developers</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Getting-Real-Smarter-Successful-Application/dp/0578012812/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363460890&amp;sr=1-1">Getting Real</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/ReWork-Change-Work-Forever-ebook/dp/B003ELY7PG/ref=dp_kinw_strp_1">ReWork</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Toyota-Way-Management-Principles-Manufacturer/dp/0071392319/ref=sr_1_4?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363460947&amp;sr=1-4">The Toyota Way</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.realgenekim.me/devops-cookbook/">DevOps Cookbook</a> (Not released yet)</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Goal-Eliyahu-M-Goldratt/dp/0884270610/ref=sr_1_2?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363461279&amp;sr=1-2">The Goal</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Agile-Coaching-Rachel-Davies/dp/1934356433/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363461310&amp;sr=1-1">Agile Coaching</a></p></li>
</ul>


<h1>Podcast Recommendations</h1>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://devopscafe.org/">DevOps Cafe</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://foodfightshow.org/">Food Fight</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://theshipshow.com/">The Ship Show</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review of Day 5 of DevWeek 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/review-of-day-5-of-devweek-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-08T20:09:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/review-of-day-5-of-devweek-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Today was the last day of DevWeek</h1>

<p>Well, it has been a long, but enjoyable, week at DevWeek, and today was the last day.  Today was another full day workshop, and I decided to attend the Continuous Delivery Workshop with Neal Ford.</p>

<p>People who have been following this series of posts will know that I have been rather lucky, winning both a Surface RT and a Telerik DevCraft Complete License.  There were no prizes won today, but you will all be happy to know that I have purchased a Euro Millions lottery ticket.  I will keep you posted on whether I win anything :-)</p>

<p>Review of the other days of DevWeek can be seen here:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://gep13.me/W0AJEP">Day 1 - Pre-Conference Workshop</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://gep13.me/YuOPy2">Day 2 - Conference Sessions</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://gep13.me/ZqTHU1">Day 3 - Conference Sessions</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://gep13.me/13I4BKv">Day 4 - Conference Sessions</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://gep13.me/Y0Gj7A">Day 5 - Post-Conference Workshop</a> (this post)</p></li>
</ul>


<h1>Post-Conference Workshop at DevWeek</h1>

<p><strong>Presenter: </strong>Neal Ford (you can find his blog <a href="http://nealford.com/">here</a>, and his twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/neal4d">here</a>)</p>

<p><strong>Topic: </strong>Continuous Delivery Workshop</p>

<blockquote>Getting software released to users is often a painful, risky, and time-consuming process. This workshop sets out the principles and technical practices that enable rapid, incremental delivery of high quality, valuable new functionality to users.
Through automation of the build, deployment, and testing process, and improved collaboration between developers, testers and operations, delivery teams can get changes released in a matter of hours – sometimes even minutes – no matter what the size of a project or the complexity of its code base.
The workshop materials are derived from the best-selling book ‘Continuous Delivery’, and were created in collaboration with the authors and other of my ThoughtWorks colleagues.</blockquote>


<h1>Thoughts</h1>

<p>Overall, I have to say that this was a very well structured and executed presentation.  Neal obviously understands this area very well, and was able to field a number of questions from the audience.  There was loads of active conversation from the audience, which made it even more interesting.  Lots of conversation regarding real-life situations, and experiences.</p>

<p>The one thing that I thought was missing from the Workshop was some demos.  There was lots of description of the deployment pipeline, and using puppet to automate the configuration of a server, but I think what really would have cemented these ideas was an example.  Even if this was a simple website application being packaged, and deployed onto even a single server, at the click of a button.  This would have made for a very cool end demonstration to summarize the whole discussion.</p>

<h1>Takeaways</h1>

<p>There really was loads to think about in this talk.  Some of the stand out questions, takeaways were as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>How often do you release to users?</p>

<ul>
<li>Correct answer of course is that you should be ready to release to users whenever they require it.  Software should always be in a deployable state.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>How long would it take your organisation to deploy a change that involves just one line of code?</p></li>
<li><p>Thinking about the above, can you do this in a repeatable fashion, that doesn&rsquo;t involve crazy amounts of over time?</p></li>
<li><p>Make sure there is a clear delineation between Unit Tests and Functional Tests, and run these as separate parts of your delivery pipeline</p></li>
<li><p>Features Toggles gives you an alternative to creating many Feature Branches, avoiding the problem of merging</p></li>
<li><p>Going Live should be just another deployment that you are already practiced at internally</p></li>
<li><p>You should strive of Continuous Integration of your Databases as well as code</p></li>
<li><p>Look to make use of Puppet and Chef to configure development and staging environments, and store the configuration within your source control</p></li>
<li><p>When implementing Continuous Delivery, first gather metrics of current state of deployment, i.e. lead times and cycle times, and then compare after implementing Continuous Delivery</p></li>
</ul>


<h1>Quotes</h1>

<ul>
<li><p>&ldquo;Melt down silly architectural barriers between different areas of the organisation&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;If it hurts&hellip; Do it more often!&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;Bring the pain forward&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;Rational ClearCase i the most hostile pice of software towards Agile Development&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;Git is one of my favourite tools&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;Avoid life in the knitted Castle&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>&ldquo;The biggest PITA around software updates is data migration and schema changes&rdquo;</p></li>
</ul>


<h1>Book Recommendations</h1>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Continuous-Integration-Improving-Software-Signature/dp/0321336380/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1362768478&amp;sr=8-1">Continuous Integration: Improving Software Quality and Reducing Risk</a> - Paul M. Duvall, Steve Matyas and Andrew Glover</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/0321601912/ref=s9_simh_gw_p14_d0_i3?pf_rd_m=A3P5ROKL5A1OLE&amp;pf_rd_s=center-2&amp;pf_rd_r=00E47JENTWKEBCSS5F0X&amp;pf_rd_t=101&amp;pf_rd_p=358549767&amp;pf_rd_i=468294">Continuous Delivery: Reliable Software Releases Through Build, Test, and Deployment Automation</a> - Jaz Humble, David Farley</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Succeeding-Agile-Development-Addison-Wesley-Signature/dp/0321579364/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1362768511&amp;sr=8-1">Succeeding with Agile: Software Development Using Scrum</a> - Mike Cohn</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Specification-Example-Successful-Deliver-Software/dp/1617290084/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1362768530&amp;sr=8-1">Specification by Example: How Successful Teams Deliver the Right Software</a> - Gojko Adzic</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Growing-Object-Oriented-Software-Guided-Tests/dp/B006V349VQ/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1362768546&amp;sr=8-1">Growing Object-Oriented Software, Guided by Tests</a> - Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Refactoring-Databases-Evolutionary-Addison-Wesley-Signature/dp/0321774515/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1362768559&amp;sr=8-1">Refactoring Databases: Evolutionary Database Design</a> - Scott J. Ambler and Pramod J. Sadalage</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Release-It-Production-Ready-Pragmatic-Programmers/dp/0978739213/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1362768566&amp;sr=8-1">Release It!: Design and Deploy Production-Ready Software</a> - Michael T. Nygard</p></li>
</ul>


<h1>Overall Thoughts</h1>

<p>As I have said in my other posts, I have had a really good time at DevWeek, and I am happy to say that I have learnt a lot this week.  Hoping to be able to take back a lot of what I have learnt and start applying them at work.</p>

<p>Huge congratulations to the organisers of DevWeek, they did a great job, and a huge thanks to all the staff of the Barbican and the helpers at DevWeek!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
