<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Conferences | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/conferences/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-29T13:44:11+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slides From Talk at ScotSoft2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-from-talk-at-scotsoft2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-24T13:20:13+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-from-talk-at-scotsoft2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Semantic Versioning with GitVersion</h2>

<p>On Thursday 17th September 2015, I presented a talk entitled &ldquo;Semantic Versioning with GitVersion&rdquo; at the first Developer Forum as part of the <a href="http://www.scotlandis.com/scotsoft2015/">ScotlandIS ScotSoft2015</a> event.  The abstract for the talk was as follows:</p>

<blockquote>
Have you ever needed to control the version number of your application?  If so, you will know that this isn&#8217;t something that you &#8220;get for free&#8221;.  It&#8217;s hard!

You may have tried to use some form of auto incrementing number from your Continuous Integration Server, or store a text file in source control and update it each time the build happens.  Both of these approaches will work, but they don&#8217;t account for more complicated scenarios where you are working on multiple releases at the same time, or you want to use multiple Continuous Integration Servers.

In this session, we will look at how we can improve the versioning of your application using a combination of branching strategies (either Gitflow or Githubflow) and an open source tool called GitVersion.  

GitVersion is a tool which allows you to easy generate the Semantic Version number for your application, based on the current state of your code base in it&#8217;s Git Repository.
</blockquote>




<!--more-->


<p>I thoroughly enjoyed doing this presentation, and there were quite a few questions after the talk was finished, so I feel that people were able to get something from it.  If there are any follow-up questions, then please feel free to get in touch, and I will do my best to respond.</p>

<h2>Slides</h2>

<p>If you are interested in seeing teh slide from the talk, you can find them displayed below, or you can find the full version on SlideShare <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/gep13/semantic-versioning-with-gitversion">here</a>.</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/53150160 " width="595" height="446" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC;border-width:1px 1px 0;margin-bottom:5px" allowfullscreen></iframe> </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Registration for DunDDD 2014 Is Now Open]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-for-dunddd-2014-is-now-open/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-for-dunddd-2014-is-now-open</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Grab your ticket for DunDDD quickly so you don&rsquo;t miss out!</h1>

<p>The call for speakers at the Scottish Community Event (organised by the <a href="http://scottishdevelopers.com/">Scottish Developers</a>) known as <a href="http://dun.dddscotland.co.uk/speaker">DunDDD </a>has now closed and the registration has opened.</p>

<!--more-->


<h1>DunDDD is now in its fourth year</h1>

<p>This will be the 4th DunDDD, built on the popular foundation of the Developer! Developer! Developer! conference series which has spread to all corners of the UK and the international arena.  DDD conferences are community-run days where passionate and enthusiastic people come together to learn, share ideas, and to network within the many hubs of the development community. Best of all DDD events are <strong>free</strong> to everyone!</p>

<p>This year DunDDD will be featuring an entire track dedicated to the <strong>Not Only SQL</strong> movement and <strong>Big Data</strong>.</p>

<p>Go and grab your <a href="http://dun.dddscotland.co.uk/registration">ticket now</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slides and Code From Continuous Integration 101 Talk at DunDDD]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-code-continuous-integration-101-talk-dunddd/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-02T22:08:13+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/slides-code-continuous-integration-101-talk-dunddd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Continuous Integration 101</h1>

<p>On Saturday 23rd November 2013, I presented a talk entitled &ldquo;Continuous Integration 101&rdquo; at the <a href="http://dun.dddscotland.com/">DunDDD Conference in Dundee</a>.  The abstract for the talk was as follows:</p>

<blockquote>It is well understood that &#8220;Continuous Integration&#8221; is a development best practice, however, it is also something that is not often implemented within development teams. Typical reasons include:

- It is difficult to set up
- It is difficult to maintain
- It takes too long

In this session we will look at how you can incrementally work your way to fully implementing Continuous Integration into your development process. This talk will focus on using TeamCity as the Continuous Integration Server and psake build engine.</blockquote>




<!--more-->


<p>Overall, I was quite happy with how the talk went, and it seems to go down quite well.  There was a fair bit of interaction with the audience, with several questions, which I hope that I was able to answer.  If there are any follow-up questions, then please feel free to get in touch, and I will do my best to respond.</p>

<h1>slides and code</h1>

<p>If you are interested in seeing the slides from the talk, you can find them displayed below, and also available for download <a href="/assets/posts/2013-12-02-slides-code-continuous-integration-101-talk-dunddd/Continuous%20Integration%20101.pdf">here</a>.</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/28819037 " width="595" height="446" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC;border-width:1px 1px 0;margin-bottom:5px" allowfullscreen></iframe> </p>

<p>If you want to check out what little code was used during the presentation, you can find it <a href="http://gep13.me/CIDemos">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Registration for DunDDD 2013 Is Now Open]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-dunddd-2013-now-open/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-14T19:18:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/registration-dunddd-2013-now-open</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Grab your ticket for DunDDD quickly so you don&rsquo;t miss out!</h1>

<p>The call for speakers at the Scottish Community Event (organised by the <a href="http://scottishdevelopers.com/">Scottish Developers</a>) known as <a href="http://dun.dddscotland.co.uk/speaker">DunDDD </a>has now closed and the registration has opened.</p>

<!--more-->


<h1>DunDDD is now in its third year</h1>

<p>This will be the 3rd DunDDD, built on the popular foundation of the Developer! Developer! Developer! conference series which has spread to all corners of the UK and the international arena.  DDD conferences are community-run days where passionate and enthusiastic people come together to learn, share ideas, and to network within the many hubs of the development community. Best of all DDD events are <strong>free</strong> to everyone!</p>

<p>This year DunDDD will be featuring an entire track dedicated to Data Science.</p>

<p>Go and grab your <a href="http://dun.dddscotland.co.uk/registration">ticket now</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Lights 2013 Conference]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/northern-lights-2013-conference/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-05T20:22:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/northern-lights-2013-conference</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Get your tickets now!</h1>

<p>I wanted to let you know about an upcoming event in Aberdeen that I have been helping to arrange. It is taking place on Friday 18th October 2013.  The event in question is the Northern Lights 2013 Conference.  The website for the conference can be found here:</p>

<p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/">http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/</a></p>

<!--more-->


<p>The event is in its third year, and this year the theme is tools.  Both the tools that we use, and the tools we build.  There is a wide range of speakers available, including:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/hadi-hariri.html">Hadi Hariri</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/kendall-miller.html">Kendall Miller</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/24/sarah-drummond.html">Sarah Drummond</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/kate-stone.html">Kate Stone</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/10/02/maria-gutierrez.html">Maria Gutierrez</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/niall-merrigan.html">Niall Merrigan</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://northernlightsconf.co.uk/speakers/2013/09/23/glenn-henriksen.html">Glenn Hendrickson</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>Who are offering up an exciting line up of talks.</p>

<p>In addition, there will be two open spaces at the conference, where attendees will have an opportunity to suggest a topic for an interactive conversation with other attendees and speakers.  If you haven’t been to an open space before, they are fantastic.  It is a perfect opportunity to interact with other like mind people about a topic that you are interested in.  The best way to get something out of this is to suggest a topic that you are especially interested in, and hopefully other people will get involved as well.</p>

<p>Tickets are £15 for the day, which includes coffee and lunch for regular attendees, and Students tickets to the talks are free, plus you can buy a lunch ticket for £5.</p>

<p>We hope to see you there.  If you have any questions about the event, then please don’t hesitate to get in touch with me.</p>

<p>If you know anyone else who would be interested in attending this event, I would really appreciate it if you could forward on this email.</p>

<p>This event is lovingly sponsored by:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>University of Aberdeen -  <a href="http://www.abdn.ac.uk">http://www.abdn.ac.uk/</a></p></li>
<li><p>Neo - <a href="http://www.neo.com">http://www.neo.com</a></p></li>
<li><p>Fifth Ring - <a href="http://www.fifthring.com">http://www.fifthring.com</a></p></li>
<li><p>Codify - <a href="http://www.codify.ltd.uk">http://www.codify.ltd.uk</a></p></li>
<li><p>Arnold Clark - <a href="http://www.arnoldclark.com">http://www.arnoldclark.com</a></p></li>
<li><p>AAA - <a href="http://www.aaajobs.co.uk">http://aaajobs.co.uk</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
