<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Day to Day | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/day-to-day/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-03T09:06:46+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Great Day Out at Phoenix Falconry]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/a-great-day-out-at-phoenix-falconry/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-11T11:00:43+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/a-great-day-out-at-phoenix-falconry</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Sunday, I finally used a birthday present that I received last year; a day out at a Falconry Centre.  I had the choice of a number of Falconry centres in Scotland, but I ended up choosing Phoenix Falconry.  You can find their website <a href="http://falconry-in-scotland.co.uk/">here</a>, and you can find them on TripAdvisor <a href="http://www.tripadvisor.co.uk/Attraction_Review-g1146700-d2108482-Reviews-Phoenix_Falconry-Blackford_Perth_and_Kinross_Scotland.html">here,</a> as you will see, they come highly recommended!</p>

<h1>The Experience</h1>

<p>Phoenix Falconry offer a number of different <a href="http://www.scottishfalconry.co.uk/shopdisplayproducts.asp?id=1&amp;cat=Falcon+Experiences">experiences</a>.  I opted for “<a href="http://www.scottishfalconry.co.uk/shopexd.asp?id=3">The Phoenix Experience</a>”, which consisted of:</p>

<blockquote>This half day action packed experience is designed to get you closer and more interactive than you ever imagined possible as you join us a our new luxury facility in scenic South Perthshire to handle and fly stunning birds of prey from around the world!

You&#8217;ll learn about their ecology, biology and psychology and personally fly and handle up to 12 species of hawk, buzzard, owl, falcon and eagles including species as varied as the huge American Bald eagle to the 200mph Peregrine falcon!</blockquote>


<p>I am happy to report that I had a great day, so much so that I have actually booked into another event, “<a href="http://www.scottishfalconry.co.uk/shopexd.asp?id=4">A Walk in the Wilderness</a>”.  If you are at all interested in attending an event at this facility make sure and book soon.  Speaking to the Falconer on the say, it turns out that Phoenix Falconry will no longer be doing public events, this will be their last season of doing them.  Turns out that it is not economic for them to continue doing them.  Instead, the centre will be concentrating on their breeding programme, which it reported to be going from strength to strength.</p>

<h1>The birds</h1>

<p>In total, there were 7 different birds of prey shown to us.  It really was a fascinating day, starting with a small Harris Hawk, and finishing with a Bald Eagle.  Some of the photos that I took on the day can be seen below (there were far more actually taken, and if you are interested, I would be happy to let you see them, but be warned there are lots!)</p>

<p>[gallery]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Round of Golf on Trump International Scotland]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/my-round-of-golf-on-trump-international-scotland/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T06:59:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/my-round-of-golf-on-trump-international-scotland</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Christmas, I got an amazing present from my family…</p>

<p>A round of golf on Donald Trump’s new Golf Course, “Trump International Scotland”.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/my-round-of-golf-on-trump-international-scotland/wp_000300.jpg/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/WP_000300-300x225.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><strong><em>NOTE:</em></strong> Below you will see a gallery of some of the photos that I took on the day.</p>

<p>Well, the 27th July 2012 finally came round, and my dad, my sisters boyfriend, his dad and myself, headed for Trump International.</p>

<p>You have to give Donald Trump credit, he certainly knows what he is doing.  The drive up to the Golf Course is spectacular!  Once we were all signed in, we took advantage of the driving range, and pitching/putting area, which not to put to fine a point on it, are in better condition than some actual Golf Courses that I have played!</p>

<p>It was then time to head out on the course.  We were greeted at the first tee by the starter, who pointed us in the right direction, and explained which tee we should be playing off.  For us, it was the Green tees, since the white tees were closed, and the Blue tees were only recommended for single handicappers, which we aren’t, not by a long shot.  He did recommend that we take a look at the views from some of the Black tees, which we did, and all I can say is, they are amazing!  You can see some of these below.</p>

<p>Granted, we did get an amazing day for playing the course.  The sun was out, and there was very little wind.  This definitely helped the scores, and the number of lost balls count.  On any other day, the narrow fairways, elevated tees, sandy fairways, deep bunkers, and fast greens, would not have been so forgiving!</p>

<p>All in all, we had a fantastic time, and I would highly recommend playing this course.  There are still some areas where the course needs work, and time to bed in, but that will come with time.  Congratulations to Donald Trump for bringing a great Golf Course to the North East!</p>

<p>[gallery]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scottish Developers Have a New Committee Member… Me!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/scottish-developers-have-a-new-committee-member-me/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T06:50:53+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/scottish-developers-have-a-new-committee-member-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am happy to announce that I am now a fully signed up member of the <a href="http://scottishdevelopers.com/">Scottish Developers User Group</a>.  Over the last year, I have been working more and more with the guys at Scottish Developers (Andy Gibson – <a href="http://twitter.com/argibson">@ARGibson</a>, Craig Murphy – <a href="http://twitter.com/camurphy">@CAMURPHY</a>, and Colin Mackay – <a href="http://twitter.com/camurphy">@ColinMackay</a>) in order to bring speakers to Scottish User Groups, and I was thrilled when I was invited to become a committee member!</p>

<p>Working directly with Scottish Developers has meant that we have been able to bring people like Scott Hanselman – <a href="http://twitter.com/shanselman">@shanselman</a>, Matt Lacey – <a href="http://twitter.com/mrlacey">@mrlacey</a>, Sebastien Lambla – <a href="http://twitter.com/serialseb">@serialseb</a>, Gill Cleeren – <a href="http://twitter.com/gillcleeren">@gillcleeren</a>, and Mark Rendle – <a href="http://twitter.com/markrendle">@markrendle</a> to Scotland, to do User Group presentations.  This typically means doing a tour of Glasgow, Edinburgh, Aberdeen and Dundee.  These events seem to have gone down really well, and this is definitely something that we are looking to continue.  It is much easier to get speakers to commit to a series of events in Scotland, rather than a single event, as it makes the trip more worthwhile.  If there is anyone in particular that you are interested in seeing in Scotland, feel free to get in touch, and we will see what we can do.</p>

<p>In addition to the regular monthly events, I will also be getting involved in helping with the setup and running of the Annual Events, such as DDD Scotland, and DunDDD, as well as the general day-to-day running of the User Group.  This doesn’t mean that I will be neglecting the <a href="http://aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/">Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group</a>.  This will continue to exist in it’s own right, and host regular monthly events.</p>

<p>I attended my first Scottish Developers Annual General Meeting on the 7th July 2012, where I was formally introduced as a committee members.  You can see photos from the day below.</p>

<p>[gallery orderby=&ldquo;title&rdquo;]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum of Solace]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/quantum-of-solace/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-08T10:33:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/quantum-of-solace</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Went to see the new Bond Film, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0830515/">Quantum of Solace</a>, this morning. I was down in Glasgow with Lynn, and after not being able to go on the Tour that I wanted to, decided to go to the cinema instead. And I am glad that I did!! I really enjoyed the film!!</p>

<p>The action sequences, and the fight scenes were amazing. I did think that the film jumped around a little bit, but apart from that, a very good film.</p>

<p>I am having to rethink the order of my “Best James Bond of All Time”. Daniel Craig has still got a lot to prove, but he is working his way up the list.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glasgow City Chambers]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/glasgow-city-chambers/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-08T09:45:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/glasgow-city-chambers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whilst waiting to try to get into the tour of the Glasgow City Chambers (which ended up not happening, only runs on week days) I took some photos with my new phone. I was quite surprised by the quality of some of the photos. I have added them below,so feel free to have a look.</p>

<p>[nggallery id=24]</p>

<p>While I was there, there was a marching band that led a procession for placing a poppy wreath at the base of the statue. That was interesting to watch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
