<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Night's Out | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/nights-out/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-01T18:02:19+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matrikon Christmas Party]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/matrikon-christmas-party/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-06T11:34:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/matrikon-christmas-party</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night was the Matrikon Christmas Party, and it was at the Ardoe House Hotel. We had 7 tables, and there were a number of other companies there as well, so it was a good atmosphere.</p>

<p>I thought the meal was very good, but I heard some people that they didn&rsquo;t like it very much, “turkey was too dry”, “dessert was disgusting”, etc., but I really liked it.</p>

<p>Wes took the role of Paparazzi for the evening, so I am hoping that he has got some good shots. I will try and get the photos from him and put them up on the website.</p>

<p>The night ended with the obligatory rendition was Runrig&rsquo;s Loch Lomond, which was a lot of fun, and then it was home to bed.</p>

<p>The photos from the night can be seen here:</p>

<p>[nggallery id=30]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Birthday Weekend - Glasgow]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/birthday-weekend-glasgow/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-01T19:42:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/birthday-weekend-glasgow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This weekend was my birthday, and Lynn and myself spent the weekend together with a number of different activities.</p>

<p>The first was Clubland on Friday night at the Aberdeen Exhibition and Conference Centre. To say I felt a little bit old at the event would be a little bit of an understatement. The event was full of lot of young people wearing very little clothes!!! I think there is going to be a major flu epidemic hitting Aberdeen in the next few days. Have to say though, I had quite a good time, didn&rsquo;t know many of the songs, or the artists, but it was good. You can see the pictures below:</p>

<p>[nggallery id=28]</p>

<p>We then went down to Glasgow to spend the weekend. We took the Mega Bus down rather than the train this time, but that was fine. We stayed in the same Holiday Inn by Express that we stayed in last time. Once we arrived we went for a meal at Di Maggio&rsquo;s, it was really nice!!! Then we took a taxi to The Saw Doctors concert at The Barrow Lands. I had a really good time, they put on a really good show!! I picked up a new t-shirt and the new CD, which I am looking forward to listening too. You can see the photos from the concert below:</p>

<p>[nggallery id=29]</p>

<p>Sunday was spent doing some shopping, and then we went to see the new Angelina Jolie film, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0824747/">Changeling</a>. It was quite a sad story, but it was a really good watch.</p>

<p>In the evening we went to the <a href="http://www.jongleurs.com/">Jongleurs</a> comedy club. We got a table for two right at the front of the stage, we were a little concerned that we were going to get picked on, but we didn&rsquo;t. The three comics that were there were very funny, and I would fully recommend going along. There was one annoying girl in the crowd who thought she was funny, and was continually trying to heckle the comics, but she ended up coming across very annoying!! Towards the end I think she got the idea, and stopped heckling.</p>

<p>We came back up the road on the Mega Bus again on Monday afternoon, after having a great weekend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meal at Mill of Mundurno]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/meal-at-mill-of-mundurno/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-23T14:23:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/meal-at-mill-of-mundurno</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lynn and I met up with folks and my sister and her boyfriend and his son for a meal this afternoon at the Mill of Mundurno and it was really nice!!!</p>

<p>The food was really nice, and the place looks like it has just been done up, so I would definitely recommend it!!</p>

<p>Couldn&rsquo;t decide what I was going to have, but ended up choosing the Steak Pie (substituting the Mash and Peas for Chips and Beans) and it was lovely. For dessert you were able to choose a small portion of three different desserts, so thought I would go for that. Made two very good choices, the Belgian Waffles and the Cheesecake, but the bitter chocolate pudding definitely wasn&rsquo;t to my taste.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Birthday Night Out]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/birthday-night-out/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-22T20:18:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/birthday-night-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Had my birthday night out tonight, and I have to say, I had a great time.</p>

<p>I was actually debating about not going out because of the weather, it had been snowing since Friday, and a couple of my mates had decided that they were not going to make the trip out from Peterhead in case they got stuck. Decided we should just go, and very glad we did&hellip;.</p>

<p>Finally met up with everyone at Slain&rsquo;s Castle (major problem with the taxi that we had booked, just got the bus instead) where we had an area reserved. Was able to catch up with a lot of people that I hadn&rsquo;t seen since I got back, so that was really good. I think everyone had a good time, at least I hope so.</p>

<p>I had also booked us on the guest list at Tiger Tiger, but we decided that it would be easier to get home at 1 rather than trying to get home once the club&rsquo;s kicked out. So it was in past the pie shop for a steak pie and then into the taxi queue. Again, not much luck with the taxi&rsquo;s, ended up getting the number 17X bus home.</p>

<p>Great night!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
