<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gep13 Blog | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/gep13-blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-18T09:46:52+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Daughter Is 1 Year Old Today!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/our-daughter-is-1-year-old-today/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/our-daughter-is-1-year-old-today</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Is it really 1 year?</h2>

<p>As amazing as it sounds, our daughter is 1 year old today!</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I was always told that time would start passing quickly as soon as you had your first child, but I honestly didn&rsquo;t expect that it would be this fast!</p>

<p>Today is Alivia&rsquo;s 1st Birthday!  I can remember being in the hospital holding for the first time as if it were yesterday!</p>

<p>So much as happened since Alivia came into our lives, but I wouldn&rsquo;t change anything, I love being a dad!</p>

<p>She has:</p>

<ul>
<li>learned to walk (well almost)</li>
<li>learned to swim</li>
<li>learned to say &ldquo;dad&rdquo;</li>
<li>learned to sign &ldquo;mum&rdquo;</li>
<li>learned to clap</li>
<li>learned to sleep through the night</li>
<li>learned to blow raspberries</li>
<li>and so much more!</li>
</ul>


<p>Looking forward to teaching her so many new things in the next year!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stats for My Blog in 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/stats-for-my-blog-in-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-31T10:05:15+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/stats-for-my-blog-in-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>What were the stats?</h1>

<p>Last year around this time, I wrote a blog post about the stats for my blog in 2011, you can see this blog post <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/stats-for-my-blog-in-2011/">here</a>.</p>

<p>It is now time to see what the stats were for 2012 and compare these to the previous years stats.</p>

<p>First up, what does Google Analytics have to say about it:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/stats-for-my-blog-in-2012/google_analytics_results/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Google_Analytics_Results-1024x408.png" alt="Google_Analytics_Results" /></a></p>

<p>Highlights being:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>7,616 Visits (an increase of 3,134 on last year)</p></li>
<li><p>6,252 Unique Visitors (an increase of 3,23 on last year)</p></li>
<li><p>10,485 Pageviews (an increase of 3,284 on last year)</p></li>
<li><p>1.38 Pages/Visit (a decrease of 0.23 on last year)</p></li>
<li><p>00:01:42 Avg. Time on Site (a decrease of 00:00:07 on last year)</p></li>
<li><p>72.87% Bounce Rate (a decrease of 2.59% on last year)</p></li>
<li><p>80.53% % of New Visits (an increase of 13.66% on last year)</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Overall, I am really happy with these results.  I spent a lot more time working on the blog this year, and I am pleased to see an increase in traffic to the blog.</p>

<p>Thanks again to the amazing <a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/jetpack/">Jetpack plugin for WordPress</a>, I am able to share some more stats:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/stats-for-my-blog-in-2012/crunchy_numbers_from_jetpack/"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Crunchy_Numbers_from_Jetpack.png" alt="Crunchy_Numbers_from_Jetpack" /></a></p>

<p>My top 5 blog posts were:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/scott-hanselman-doing-user-group-tour-of-scotland/">Scott Hanselman doing user group tour of Scotland</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/sebastien-lambla-on-tour/">Sebastien Lambla on tour</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/uk-developer-events-for-2012/">UK Developer Events for 2012</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/use-the-cloud9-online-ide-to-hack-on-wordpress/">Use the Cloud9 Online IDE to hack on WordPress</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/ddd-attendance-leaderboard-where-do-you-rank/">DDD attendance leaderboard, where do you rank?</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>In 2012, there were actually 28 posts fewer than in 2011.  However, the busy day increased to 410 views, compared to 279 views in 2011.</p>

<p>The keen-eyed amongst you will notice that 93 (the total number of posts at the end of 2011) plus, the total number of posts of 2012 which was 53, does not equal the total number of posts at the end of 2012 which was 229.  The reason for this is that during 2012, I copied some blog posts from an older incarnation of the gep13 blog, and added them here.</p>

<p>If you are interested in seeing the full report from Jetpack, you can find it <a href="http://jetpack.me/annual-report/23095201/2012/">here</a>.</p>

<h1>Happy New Year</h1>

<p>Finally, just wanted to wish everyone a Happy New Year, and all the best for 2013!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blog Is Now Hosted on a New Server]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/blog-is-now-hosted-on-a-new-server/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-28T14:01:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/blog-is-now-hosted-on-a-new-server</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I hope that everyone has had a great Christmas, and are looking forward to celebrating at New Year.</p>

<p>In the downtime since finishing up work before Christmas, I have been working my way through my to do list, and one of them was to update the WordPress system that hosts this blog.  In doing so, it became clear that there were some &ldquo;issues&rdquo; with the WordPress installation which was hosted with my Web Host.  I tried for some while to get this resolved, and wasn&rsquo;t able to.  In the end, I decided to move the hosting of this WordPress blog to my own Virtual Private Server, that I have through <a href="http://tagadab.com/">Tagadab</a> (thanks again to <a href="http://twitter.com/agileguy">@agileguy</a> for the recommendation!).</p>

<p>This transfer has now been completed, and from what I can see, the blog seems to working correctly.  If you find any issues, then please feel free to get in touch, and I will get them corrected.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continue Using WordPress, or Not?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/continue-using-wordpress-or-not/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-15T17:32:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/continue-using-wordpress-or-not</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In one way or another, I have had a blog since the start of 2008. This started out as a custom blog with I created in ASP.Net. This was hosted on my own server in the house, using Red Hat Linux, MySQL and Mono (using the mod_mono Apache Module). This was set up as more of an experiment than anything, just to prove that you could happily run an ASP.Net application on top of Linux, and by the start of 2009 I wasn’t really using the blog anymore. Back in May 2011, I decided that I wanted to start blogging “properly” again. This decision was taken for a number of reasons, but mainly due to the fact that I had started getting more involved in the UK .Net Development Community and I wanted somewhere to record what was going on, and so this WordPress blog was born.</p>

<p>Being a .Net Developer, my intention was always to start using one of the .Net Blogging systems such as <a href="http://www.dotnetblogengine.net/">BlogEngine</a>, <a href="http://dasblog.info/">dasBlog</a>, or <a href="http://subtextproject.com/default.aspx?AspxAutoDetectCookieSupport=1">Subtext</a>, however, due to time constraints at the time, I set up this WordPress blog. This was ridiculously simple to do, and I was very quickly able to set up the blog as I wanted it, with pages, contact form, and blog entries. There was very little that I could fault with WordPress. The sheer volume of plugins that it has means that if you want to add something to your blog, such as Galleries, Comment Management, Syntax Highlighting, you can simply add it. And, best of all, normally, this doesn’t cost you anything.</p>

<p>For the next year or so, I was quite happy using the WordPress system, and it wasn’t until I set up the Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group site with <a href="http://www.dotnetblogengine.net/">BlogEngine</a>, that I started to wonder whether I wanted to move this blog onto another system. I started doing some investigation, and there are a number of tutorials out there that show you the steps that you need to take in order to migrate a WordPress blog onto another system. The more I thought about it, the more I thought that I was going to go ahead and move it. At least that way, if there was “something” that I wanted to add to the blog system, be it another module, or function, then in theory (given that I am a .Net Developer and that a new system would be based on .Net) I should quite easily be able to add it.</p>

<p>However, recently, a number of things have happened that are making me to rethink this decision.</p>

<ol>
<li><p> I attended <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=569">GiveCamp UK</a> and worked on a WordPress site and I got to see more into the innards of WordPress and saw that it isn’t that “bad” to tinker with, as I had previously thought</p></li>
<li><p> I found an amazing Metro WordPress Theme thanks to <a href="http://www.pedrolamas.com/2011/12/21/metro-cimbalino-wordpress-theme/">Pedro Lamas</a></p></li>
<li><p> <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=416">WordPress 3.3.1</a> was released and it is quite simply, amazing!</p></li>
<li><p> I installed a few new WordPress Plugins that contained the last remaining functionality that I was looking for on my blog, namely <a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/backupwordpress/">BackUpWordPress</a>, <a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/disqus-comment-system/">Disqus Comment System</a>, <a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/feedburner-setting/">FeedBurner FeedSmith Extend</a>, <a href="http://alexrabe.de/wordpress-plugins/nextgen-gallery/">NextGen Gallery</a>, and <a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/now-reading-reloaded/">Now Reading Reloaded</a>, (If you are interested in seeing all the WordPress plugins that I currently use, take a look at this <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=174">blog post</a>).</p></li>
</ol>


<p>The Now Reading plugin doesn’t “quite” do exactly what I want, but I think I am now prepared to invest the time to get it working the way I want it.</p>

<p>So what does all this mean?</p>

<p>Unless someone can convince me to the contrary, I am going to continue using WordPress.</p>

<p>It is VERY good at what it does, and I don’t see any killer feature in any of the other systems that would make me want to switch. Granted, it is created in PHP, and this is not something that I am overly familiar with, but using it also forces me to get my toes wet with PHP, which when it comes to becoming a “well-rounded” developer is far from a bad thing. To this end, over the last week or so I have added a few more things to the blog. This includes, as mentioned, the Now Reading plugin which you can see in action <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?now_reading_library=true">here</a> (expect to see some changes to this in the near future), and I have added some photo albums, which you can see <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?page_id=581">here</a>. The majority of these photos come from my old blog back in 2008 (I have also imported the old blog posts from that blog into this one). If anyone is looking for an explanation of what the hell “<strong>Gary The Coconut</strong>” is all about, check out this blog post <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=698">here</a> and <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=694">here</a>.</p>

<p>As always, I would be interested to hear your thoughts on this, so feel free to comment.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Now Using Feedburner for Blog Site]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/now-using-feedburner-for-blog-site/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-14T13:26:54+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/now-using-feedburner-for-blog-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have decided to start using <a href="http://feedburner.google.com/">FeedBurner</a> for managing the Feeds for my blog (If you are not familiar with what FeedBurner is, you can find some more information <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FeedBurner">here</a>). Basically, it will allow me, on top of the Google Analytics that I already have running, to monitor how many people (if any) are actually looking at my blog.</p>

<p>The installation and setup of FeedBurner actually turned out to be quite simple. The one thing that I was worried about was previously subscribed RSS readers not working after the switch. However, with the help of the <a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/feedburner-setting/">FeedBurner FeedSmith Extend</a> plugin for WordPress, this is all taken care of (and it is actually recommended by FeedBurner during the setup phase. With that in place, and the feeds configured in my FeedBurner account, it all seemed to be working. On top of this, I then chose to create a custom CNAME entry in my domains DNS Records so that I could use:</p>

<blockquote>  
> 
> feeds.gep13.co.uk
> 
> </blockquote>


<p>rather then</p>

<blockquote>  
> 
> feeds.feedburner.com
> 
> </blockquote>


<p>This is very small change, but it helps to keep everything “tidy”, and again, it was very simple to setup and configure.</p>

<p>If you actually subscribe to my blog, there should be nothing for you to do, everything should continue to work as it did before. The redirect to the FeedBurner proxy happens with the help of the WordPress plugin I am using. If you have any problems, and for some reason the RSS Feed is no longer working, then I would be interested to hear from you so that I can figure out what is going on. Thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
