<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Trips Abroad | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/trips-abroad/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-07T18:51:14+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back to Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/back-to-work/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-23T08:41:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/back-to-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, that is me back to work, couldn&rsquo;t escape it for long.</p>

<p>I am back into a normal sleeping pattern, so it&rsquo;s all good, just have to try and get my desk back now at work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gaz Is Home]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/gaz-is-home/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-19T16:40:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/gaz-is-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Flew into Aberdeen today, so good to be home!!</p>

<p>Had a bit of a panic at London as I thought I wasn&rsquo;t going to make the transfer, literally had to run from Terminal 4 to Terminal 5. I made it though, which was the main thing!!</p>

<p>There was a woman throwing up in the seat behind me coming into London, needless to say I was glad to get off the plane.</p>

<p>Was met at the airport by Lynn, and to my surprise, Steve and Louie. Was great to see everyone!</p>

<p>Oh, and when I got to Aberdeen, guess what&hellip;.</p>

<p>&hellip;it was raining.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confirmed Leaving Date]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/confirmed-leaving-date/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-23T15:24:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/confirmed-leaving-date</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Woot Woot!! I have now got a confirmed date for when I leaving Calgary!! Getting on the plane on the night of the 18th October. Can&rsquo;t wait to get home!! The whole trip has been a great experience, but it is time for this Scottish loon to make his way home to familiar shores. Would definitely come back to Canada if I get a chance though, it&rsquo;s a really nice place!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Archery in Calgary]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/archery-in-calgary/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-21T23:45:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/archery-in-calgary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, me and three of the guys from the office went along to the Calgary Archery Centre in the SE. The place is jam packed full of everything to do with archery, and to be honest, hunting in general. The three guys that I went with hadn&rsquo;t done archery before, and I think they came away thinking that it was quite good fun. We were there for about 2 hours, and it total it cost us $15, which we didn&rsquo;t think was all the expensive, as you were allowed to be there for as long as you wanted. The only extra money that would be needed would have been if you completely trashed any arrows, which we didn&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>We all started of with recurve bows, however, the one I got wasn&rsquo;t all that good, and it wasn&rsquo;t a patch on my old bow, so I traded it in for a compound bow. That was a little bit more fun although, it wasn&rsquo;t very powerful, but at least it had a sight on it which the recurves didn&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>There is word of going to the shooting range next, that should be really good fun!!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lakeview Terrace]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/lakeview-terrace/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-21T17:18:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/lakeview-terrace</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Went to see the new Samuel L Jackson film, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0947802/">Lakeview Terrace</a>, last night. Have to say that it was very good.</p>

<p>I thought Jackson did a very good job of portraying the psycho cop next door. Ending was maybe a little bit too “happy”, but all in all, worth a watch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
