<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gary the Coconut | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/gary-the-coconut/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-15T19:20:48+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Story of Gary the Coconut]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/the-story-of-gary-the-coconut/"/>
    <updated>2008-07-12T18:38:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/the-story-of-gary-the-coconut</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Due to the fact that our business Headquarters are in Canada, there are a fair number of Canadians in our Scottish Office. One Friday evening, the Canadians decided that they were going to have a night of Nintendo Wii fun round at the company flat, and I was invited to come along. Initially, I thought that this would be a great idea, so I said that I would come along. However, later that night, my plans changed, and I wasn&rsquo;t able to come along, so I text them to let them know that I wouldn&rsquo;t be attending.</p>

<p>The following Monday, I was told that I had missed a really good night, and as the stories of the evening were recited, I realised that I probably should have attended. Days passed, and I thought that was the end of it, however, I was wrong&hellip;..</p>

<p>[singlepic id=1204 w=320 h=240 float=]</p>

<p>Turns out, that rather than be without a Gary at the party, the Canadians thought it would be a good idea to replace a Scottish Gary with someone else, and so <strong>Gary The Coconut</strong> was born.</p>

<p>Since that night, Gary The Coconut has ventured out into the world, in lots of different ways:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>He has got his own <a href="http://www.facebook.com/people/Gary_Park/1155266863">Facebook account</a></p></li>
<li><p>He has been Skiing</p></li>
<li><p>He has been White Water Rafting</p></li>
<li><p>He has been to a BBQ</p></li>
<li><p>He has been to lots of parties</p></li>
</ul>


<p>He has made lots of friends along the way, however, his best friend in the whole wide world has to be Wes:</p>

<p>[singlepic id=1211 w=320 h=240 float=]</p>

<p>Where will Gary The Coconut go next? No one knows&hellip;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
