<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Visual Studio 2010 | gep13's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/categories/visual-studio-2010/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-05T12:21:06+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@gep13.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All-In-One Code Framework]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/all-in-one-code-framework/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-16T20:30:23+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/all-in-one-code-framework</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This afternoon, while trying to find a sample that would help me create a Shell Extension for Windows Explorer, I stumbled across the All-In-One Code Framework on CodePlex:</p>

<p><a href="http://1code.codeplex.com/">http://1code.codeplex.com/</a></p>

<p>This is not something that I had heard of before, and the initial description of the project warranted some more investigation:</p>

<blockquote>  
> 
>    
> 
>     
>   * Are you frustrated by the lack of code samples for a certain programming task? 
>      
>   * Have you ever struggled to quickly get started with a technique? 
>      
>   * Have you expected someone to write code samples for you based on your requests for free? 
>      
>   * Is a one-stop code sample library for all Microsoft development technologies attractive to you?
>       
> 
> If your answer is YES to any of these questions, the Microsoft All-In-One Code Framework is for you!
> 
>    
> 
> </blockquote>


<p>After watching the introduction video <a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/Shows/Visual-Studio-Toolbox/Visual-Studio-Toolbox-All-In-One-Code-Framework">here</a>, I decided to get it installed.</p>

<p>There are two ways that you can use it, either as a <a href="http://1code.codeplex.com/releases/view/64539">standalone application</a> or as a <a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/4934b087-e6cc-44dd-b992-a71f00a2a6df">Visual Studio 2010 Extension</a>. Due to the fact that the sample application is intended for use with the Express Editions of Visual Studio and because I am a hoarder of <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=3">Visual Studio Extensions</a>, I opted to install the Extension.</p>

<p>With this installed, you have two ways to access the available sample applications. The first is from the Tools Menu:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/All-In-Code-Framework_12560/All-In-One-Code-1.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/All-In-Code-Framework_12560/All-In-One-Code-1_thumb.png" alt="All In One Code 1" /></a></p>

<p>Clicking on this brings up this:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/All-In-Code-Framework_12560/All-In-One-Code-3.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/All-In-Code-Framework_12560/All-In-One-Code-3_thumb.png" alt="All In One Code 3" /></a></p>

<p>Where you have the option to filter on keyword, language and technology.</p>

<p>The second method is to highlight a keyword within your code file and filter on that:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/All-In-Code-Framework_12560/All-In-One-Code-2.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/All-In-Code-Framework_12560/All-In-One-Code-2_thumb.png" alt="All In One Code 2" /></a></p>

<p>There are currently 678 sample applications that span a very wide area. The people behind this strive to create each sample using C#, VB.Net and C++, as well as for Visual Studio 2008 and Visual Studio 2010, so you should always be able to find sample in the language that you require. If you can’t, there is also the option to request a particular <a href="http://1code.codeplex.com/wikipage?title=Request%20Code%20Sample%20from%20Microsoft%20All-In-One%20Code%20Framework&amp;referringTitle=Documentation">code sample</a>.</p>

<p>Once you have specified the location that you want to store the downloaded sample applications:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/All-In-Code-Framework_12560/image.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/All-In-Code-Framework_12560/image_thumb.png" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p>You have the option to either download the sample applications as and when you require them, or you can download them all at once. Also, if an update to an application is published to the CodePlex site, the application notifies you of this, and gives you the option to upgrade.</p>

<p>All in all, I think that this is going to be a useful resource, and I would encourage you to take a look. Part of becoming a better programmer involves reading other peoples code, and this application gives you access to lots of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Modification to My Use of #ExtensionSync]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/a-modification-to-my-use-of-extensionsync/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-15T06:42:31+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/a-modification-to-my-use-of-extensionsync</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In an earlier <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=189">blog post</a> I mentioned how I am now using a very clever Visual Studio 2010 extension called <a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/dbaf0ac9-fb7b-4fb3-b34d-ea2269276d3c">ExtensionSync</a> (a complete list of all the Visual Studio 2010 extensions that I am currently using can be found <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=3">here</a>).</p>

<p>In that blog post I explained that I am using a mapped drive in order in “share” the ExtensionSync settings file between different developers in the team. Initially, this worked well, but there were a few problems with this, and this was actually noted by the author of the tool in a Twitter conversation.</p>

<p>Basically, when you make a change, i.e. you add another extension, it saves the changes to the shared settings file it will work great until another developer who perhaps already had Visual Studio 2010 open, closes his Visual Studio. When this happens, his current extensions will be persisted to the shared ExtensionSync settings file, removing the extension that you just added. Not good!</p>

<p>After giving it some thought, it occurred to me that this file was actually living in the wrong place. This file should really be treated as an <em>artefact</em> of the project, and as such, should live in our source control repository.</p>

<p>The way our source control is configured, we have a folder called SharedSource. In here we keep things like, code analysis dictionaries, shared strong key files, shared code snippets, etc, so this seemed like a perfect place to put the ExtensionSync settings file.</p>

<p>With that checked in, it was a quick change to the ExtensionSync settings to point it at the new settings file location and everything was set up.</p>

<p>The benefit of using this approach is that unless “checked out” the settings file is read only, so that even if it wanted to, ExtensionSync can’t make changes to the file (I was worried that this would cause ExtensionSync to complain, but so far I haven’t seen this).</p>

<p>It also has the benefit of applying some process to making changes to the extensions that are used. A developer now have to go through the process of checking out the settings file, installing the extension, and then checking back in. This formality means that a little more thought is given to the addition of an extension, and should prevent ad-hoc extensions appearing that are of little or no use.</p>

<p>It strikes me as well that there is a logical extension (no pun intended) to this approach. For instance, depending on the project that you are working on, you may want/need different extensions installed. If you are working on a SharePoint development project then you would want all the SharePoint helper extensions installed. However, there is absolutely no need have these installed if you are working on an ASP.Net MVC project. As a result, you might have an ExtensionSync settings file per project, which you could switch to as and when required. If this could be made to do this automatically based on the currently loaded project this would be great, but I don’t know what sort of overhead this would involve in terms of installing/uninstalling extensions. Perhaps a feature request though…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visual Studio 2010 Crashes When I Open Build Details Page]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/visual-studio-2010-crashes-when-i-open-build-details-page/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-09T06:17:55+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/visual-studio-2010-crashes-when-i-open-build-details-page</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For that last few weeks I have noticed that every time I try to open a build details screen from my Team Foundation Server within Visual Studio 2010 I was greeted with this:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/image.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/image_thumb.png" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p><em>NOTE: By build details screen I mean the TFS build details screen which you can get to via Team Explorer | Builds | View Builds and then double click on an available completed build</em></p>

<p>The details of the event didn’t really provide much insight into what might be going on:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/image1.png"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/image_thumb1.png" alt="image" /></a></p>

<pre><code>[![image](http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/image_thumb2.png)](http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/image2.png)  
</code></pre>

<p>But due to the fact that I am in the process of transitioning the code base from Visual Studio 2008 to Visual Studio 2010 there really wasn’t much of a push to get this working, as I could simply jump back to my 2008 VM and check what I needed.</p>

<p>The other day though I found myself with a couple minutes, so I thought that I would look into getting the problem fixed. A quick Bing turned up the following:</p>

<p><a href="http://connect.microsoft.com/VisualStudio/Downloads/DownloadDetails.aspx?DownloadID=34824">http://connect.microsoft.com/VisualStudio/Downloads/DownloadDetails.aspx?DownloadID=34824</a></p>

<p>The description of the error:</p>

<blockquote>  
> 
> Visual Studio 2010 SP1 crashes or shows the following error when attempting to view a build report on a TFS 2008 server:
> 
>    
> 
> &#8220;TF50316: The following name is not valid. Verify that the name does not exceed the maximum character limit, only contains valid characters, and is not a reserved name&#8221;
> 
> </blockquote>


<p>Seemed to fit my problem exactly. I had installed Service Pack 1 for Visual Studio 2010 recently, and I don’t recall the build details screen working since then, and we are still using TFS 2008, so I thought I would give it a try, nothing to lose.</p>

<p>Thankfully, once this fix was installed, the build details page started working again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visual Studio 2010 Extensions]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/visual-studio-2010-extensions/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-15T16:20:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/visual-studio-2010-extensions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having completed a new install of Visual Studio 2010 I thought I would keep a note of the Extensions that I have added to the default installation, that way I won’t have to try and remember them all if I have to do another install. My memory is bad enough as it is without having to remember anything else!!</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/4934b087-e6cc-44dd-b992-a71f00a2a6df">All-In-One Code Framework Sample Browser</a> (more info can be found <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=309">here</a>)</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/175787af-a563-4306-957b-686b4ee9b497">Amazon Web Services Toolkit for Visual Studio</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/a346880f-2d29-47a6-84a2-f2d568dd6997">CKS - Development Tools Edition (Foundation)</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/00ec88c2-1553-47d2-8170-3c5baa0c6e44/">Color Printing</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/a921b98e-9430-4be2-bf53-1169e12bdb50">CSSCop</a> <a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/a921b98e-9430-4be2-bf53-1169e12bdb50"><img src="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/new-icon_thumb1.gif" alt="new-icon" /></a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/dbaf0ac9-fb7b-4fb3-b34d-ea2269276d3c">ExtensionSync</a> (more info can be found <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=189">here</a>)</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/46A20578-F0D5-4B1E-B55D-F001A6345748/">GhostDoc</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/425f09d8-d070-4ab1-84c1-68fa326190f4?SRC=Home">GoOffline</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/bdbcffca-32a6-4034-8e89-c31b86ad4813">Hide Main Menu</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/872d27ee-38c7-4a97-98dc-0d8a431cc2ed/">JScript Editor</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/1269c9a1-fcfe-4b47-91e7-22c7027f3c41">KillCassini</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/27077b70-9dad-4c64-adcf-c7cf6bc9970c/">NuGet Package Manager</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/e5f41ad9-4edc-4912-bca3-91147db95b99/">PowerCommands for Visual Studio 2010</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/6a7a0b57-7059-470d-bcfa-60ceb78dc752/">Presentation Zoom</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/d0d33361-18e2-46c0-8ff2-4adea1e34fef/">Productivity Power Tools</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/9811e528-cfa8-4fe7-9dd1-4021978b5097">Remove Unused References</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/e8360a85-58ca-42d1-8de0-e48a1ab071c7">Silverlight SharePoint Web Parts</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/69023d00-a4f9-4a34-a6cd-7e854ba318b5">SlowCheetah - XML Transforms</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/B08B0375-139E-41D7-AF9B-FAEE50F68392/">Snippet Designer</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/06C6AE96-FB05-4379-8800-F08DAEABB7BE">StyleCop</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/c255a1e4-04ba-4f68-8f4e-cd473d6b971f/">Team Foundation Server Power Tools</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/8e602a8c-6714-4549-9e95-f3700344b0d9">Visual Studio 2010 SharePoint Power Tools</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/20cd93a2-c435-4d00-a797-499f16402378/">Visual Studio Color Theme Editor</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/6819514d-4bd6-4f31-a231-48c6530ed03b">Windows Phone Test Project</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/bb424812-f742-41ef-974a-cdac607df921">World of VS Default Browser Switcher</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/dc06b54c-b6c4-4cf5-8203-a09c6979e881">World of VS Quick Add Reference</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>Are there any others that I should get?</p>

<p>Note: I will be updating this blog post as and when I add any other extensions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
